[
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 58 years hence at 13 % per annum is rs . 141 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((141 * 100) / (58 * 13))) / (58 * 13)) = 2.480141280104694"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 126 years hence at 115 % per annum is rs . 72 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((72 * 100) / (126 * 115))) / (126 * 115)) = 0.0034292229809378067"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 53 years hence at 280 % per annum is rs . 45 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((45 * 100) / (53 * 280))) / (53 * 280)) = 0.0020433591735020814"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 217 years hence at 17 % per annum is rs . 16 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((16 * 100) / (217 * 17))) / (217 * 17)) = 0.011757166599271158"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 48 years hence at 112 % per annum is rs . 120 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((120 * 100) / (48 * 112))) / (48 * 112)) = 0.041520514455782316"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 259 years hence at 14 % per annum is rs . 288 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((288 * 100) / (259 * 14))) / (259 * 14)) = 0.21904678748111103"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 102 years hence at 280 % per annum is rs . 215 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((215 * 100) / (102 * 280))) / (102 * 280)) = 0.002635858264874577"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 113 years hence at 230 % per annum is rs . 143 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((143 * 100) / (113 * 230))) / (113 * 230)) = 0.002117012773581339"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 4 years hence at 82 % per annum is rs . 217 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((217 * 100) / (4 * 82))) / (4 * 82)) = 20.17028554431886"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the banker ' s gain of a certain sum due 175 years hence at 143 % per annum is rs . 80 . what is the present worth ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * ((80 * 100) / (175 * 143))) / (175 * 143)) = 0.0012774438348863923"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 58 years . 13 new students whose average age is 141 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 126 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((141 + 126) * 13) - (13 * 141)) / (58 - (141 + 126))) * 126) = -987.5023923444976"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 115 years . 72 new students whose average age is 53 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 280 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((53 + 280) * 72) - (72 * 53)) / (115 - (53 + 280))) * 280) = -25893.57798165138"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 45 years . 217 new students whose average age is 17 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 16 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((17 + 16) * 217) - (217 * 17)) / (45 - (17 + 16))) * 16) = 4629.333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 48 years . 112 new students whose average age is 120 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 259 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((120 + 259) * 112) - (112 * 120)) / (48 - (120 + 259))) * 259) = -22698.102719033235"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 14 years . 288 new students whose average age is 102 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 280 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((102 + 280) * 288) - (288 * 102)) / (14 - (102 + 280))) * 280) = -61356.52173913043"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 215 years . 113 new students whose average age is 230 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 143 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((230 + 143) * 113) - (113 * 230)) / (215 - (230 + 143))) * 143) = -14624.917721518988"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 4 years . 82 new students whose average age is 217 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 175 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((217 + 175) * 82) - (82 * 217)) / (4 - (217 + 175))) * 175) = -6472.29381443299"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 143 years . 80 new students whose average age is 111 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 173 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((111 + 173) * 80) - (80 * 111)) / (143 - (111 + 173))) * 173) = -16980.992907801417"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 53 years . 48 new students whose average age is 195 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 50 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((195 + 50) * 48) - (48 * 195)) / (53 - (195 + 50))) * 50) = -625.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average age of students of an adult school is 184 years . 177 new students whose average age is 136 years joined the school . as a result the average age is decreased by 23 years . find the number of students of the school after joining of the new students .",
        "Solution": "(((((136 + 23) * 177) - (177 * 136)) / (184 - (136 + 23))) * 23) = 3745.32"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 58 / 13 of a book . she calculated that she finished 141 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(141 / (1 - (58 / 13))) = -40.733333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 126 / 115 of a book . she calculated that she finished 72 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(72 / (1 - (126 / 115))) = -752.7272727272735"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 53 / 280 of a book . she calculated that she finished 45 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(45 / (1 - (53 / 280))) = 55.50660792951542"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 217 / 17 of a book . she calculated that she finished 16 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(16 / (1 - (217 / 17))) = -1.3599999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 48 / 112 of a book . she calculated that she finished 120 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / (1 - (48 / 112))) = 210.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 259 / 14 of a book . she calculated that she finished 288 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(288 / (1 - (259 / 14))) = -16.457142857142856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 102 / 280 of a book . she calculated that she finished 215 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(215 / (1 - (102 / 280))) = 338.2022471910113"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 113 / 230 of a book . she calculated that she finished 143 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(143 / (1 - (113 / 230))) = 281.11111111111114"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 4 / 82 of a book . she calculated that she finished 217 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / (1 - (4 / 82))) = 228.12820512820514"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sophia finished 175 / 143 of a book . she calculated that she finished 80 more pages than she has yet to read . how long is her book ?",
        "Solution": "(80 / (1 - (175 / 143))) = -357.50000000000006"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 is what percent of 13 ?",
        "Solution": "((58 / 13) * 100) = 446.1538461538462"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "141 is what percent of 126 ?",
        "Solution": "((141 / 126) * 100) = 111.90476190476191"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 is what percent of 72 ?",
        "Solution": "((115 / 72) * 100) = 159.72222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 is what percent of 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((53 / 280) * 100) = 18.928571428571427"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 is what percent of 217 ?",
        "Solution": "((45 / 217) * 100) = 20.737327188940093"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "17 is what percent of 16 ?",
        "Solution": "((17 / 16) * 100) = 106.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 is what percent of 112 ?",
        "Solution": "((48 / 112) * 100) = 42.857142857142854"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "120 is what percent of 259 ?",
        "Solution": "((120 / 259) * 100) = 46.33204633204633"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "14 is what percent of 288 ?",
        "Solution": "((14 / 288) * 100) = 4.861111111111112"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "102 is what percent of 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((102 / 280) * 100) = 36.42857142857142"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 58 girls and 13 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(58 / 13) = 4.461538461538462"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 141 girls and 126 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(141 / 126) = 1.119047619047619"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 115 girls and 72 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(115 / 72) = 1.5972222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 53 girls and 280 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(53 / 280) = 0.18928571428571428"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 45 girls and 217 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(45 / 217) = 0.2073732718894009"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 17 girls and 16 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(17 / 16) = 1.0625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 48 girls and 112 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(48 / 112) = 0.42857142857142855"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 120 girls and 259 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / 259) = 0.46332046332046334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 14 girls and 288 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(14 / 288) = 0.04861111111111111"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 102 girls and 280 boys in a classroom . what is the ratio of girls to boys ?",
        "Solution": "(102 / 280) = 0.36428571428571427"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 58 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 13 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 141 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 126 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * (141 / 100)) - 126) / ((141 / 100) - (13 / 100))) = -34.54687500000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 115 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 72 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 53 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 280 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 * (53 / 100)) - 280) / ((53 / 100) - (72 / 100))) = 1152.8947368421057"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 45 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 217 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 17 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 16 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 * (17 / 100)) - 16) / ((17 / 100) - (217 / 100))) = 4.175"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 48 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 112 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 120 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 259 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * (120 / 100)) - 259) / ((120 / 100) - (112 / 100))) = -2517.500000000005"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 14 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 288 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 102 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 280 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 * (102 / 100)) - 280) / ((102 / 100) - (288 / 100))) = 142.86021505376345"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 215 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 113 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 230 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 143 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((215 * (230 / 100)) - 143) / ((230 / 100) - (113 / 100))) = 300.4273504273504"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 4 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 82 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 217 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 175 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * (217 / 100)) - 175) / ((217 / 100) - (82 / 100))) = -123.19999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 143 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 80 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 111 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 173 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 * (111 / 100)) - 173) / ((111 / 100) - (80 / 100))) = -46.032258064516064"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 53 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 48 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 195 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 50 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * (195 / 100)) - 50) / ((195 / 100) - (48 / 100))) = 36.29251700680272"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an empty fuel tank with a capacity of 184 gallons was filled partially with fuel a and then to capacity with fuel b . fuel a contains 177 % ethanol by volume and fuel b contains 136 % ethanol by volume . if the full fuel tank contains 23 gallons of ethanol , how many gallons of fuel a were added ?",
        "Solution": "(((184 * (136 / 100)) - 23) / ((136 / 100) - (177 / 100))) = -554.2439024390245"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 58 and sold for rs . 13 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((13 * 100) / 58)) = 77.58620689655172"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 141 and sold for rs . 126 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((126 * 100) / 141)) = 10.63829787234043"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 115 and sold for rs . 72 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((72 * 100) / 115)) = 37.391304347826086"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 53 and sold for rs . 280 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((280 * 100) / 53)) = -428.3018867924528"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 45 and sold for rs . 217 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((217 * 100) / 45)) = -382.22222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 17 and sold for rs . 16 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((16 * 100) / 17)) = 5.882352941176464"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 48 and sold for rs . 112 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((112 * 100) / 48)) = -133.33333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 120 and sold for rs . 259 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((259 * 100) / 120)) = -115.83333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 14 and sold for rs . 288 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((288 * 100) / 14)) = -1957.1428571428573"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an article is bought for rs . 102 and sold for rs . 280 , find the gain percent ?",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((280 * 100) / 102)) = -174.50980392156862"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 workers should finish a job in 13 days . after 141 days came 126 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 13) - (141 * 58)) / (58 + 126)) = -40.34782608695652"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 workers should finish a job in 72 days . after 53 days came 280 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 * 72) - (53 * 115)) / (115 + 280)) = 5.531645569620253"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 workers should finish a job in 217 days . after 17 days came 16 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 217) - (17 * 45)) / (45 + 16)) = 147.54098360655738"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 workers should finish a job in 112 days . after 120 days came 259 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 112) - (120 * 48)) / (48 + 259)) = -1.250814332247557"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "14 workers should finish a job in 288 days . after 102 days came 280 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 * 288) - (102 * 14)) / (14 + 280)) = 8.857142857142858"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "215 workers should finish a job in 113 days . after 230 days came 143 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((215 * 113) - (230 * 215)) / (215 + 143)) = -70.26536312849161"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "4 workers should finish a job in 82 days . after 217 days came 175 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 82) - (217 * 4)) / (4 + 175)) = -3.016759776536313"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "143 workers should finish a job in 80 days . after 111 days came 173 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 80) - (111 * 143)) / (143 + 173)) = -14.028481012658228"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 workers should finish a job in 48 days . after 195 days came 50 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 48) - (195 * 53)) / (53 + 50)) = -75.64077669902913"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "184 workers should finish a job in 177 days . after 136 days came 23 workers join them . how many days m do they need to finish the same job ?",
        "Solution": "(((184 * 177) - (136 * 184)) / (184 + 23)) = 36.44444444444444"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 58 % less than p and 13 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 58) / 100) = 33.64"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 141 % less than p and 126 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * 141) / 100) = 198.81"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 115 % less than p and 72 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * 115) / 100) = 132.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 53 % less than p and 280 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 53) / 100) = 28.09"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 45 % less than p and 217 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * 45) / 100) = 20.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 17 % less than p and 16 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 17) / 100) = 2.89"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 48 % less than p and 112 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 48) / 100) = 23.04"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 120 % less than p and 259 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * 120) / 100) = 144.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 14 % less than p and 288 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * 14) / 100) = 1.96"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "j is 102 % less than p and 280 % less than t . t is q % less than p . what is the value of q ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 102) / 100) = 104.04"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 58 / 13 of a number . but the student divided the number by 58 / 13 , thus the student got 141 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((141 * (58 / 13)) * (58 / 13)) / (1 - ((58 / 13) * (58 / 13)))) / (58 / 13)) = -33.27511737089202"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 126 / 115 of a number . but the student divided the number by 126 / 115 , thus the student got 72 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((72 * (126 / 115)) * (126 / 115)) / (1 - ((126 / 115) * (126 / 115)))) / (126 / 115)) = -393.54205960015133"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 53 / 280 of a number . but the student divided the number by 53 / 280 , thus the student got 45 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((45 * (53 / 280)) * (53 / 280)) / (1 - ((53 / 280) * (53 / 280)))) / (53 / 280)) = 8.834385045838792"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 217 / 17 of a number . but the student divided the number by 217 / 17 , thus the student got 16 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((16 * (217 / 17)) * (217 / 17)) / (1 - ((217 / 17) * (217 / 17)))) / (217 / 17)) = -1.261196581196581"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 48 / 112 of a number . but the student divided the number by 48 / 112 , thus the student got 120 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((120 * (48 / 112)) * (48 / 112)) / (1 - ((48 / 112) * (48 / 112)))) / (48 / 112)) = 62.99999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 259 / 14 of a number . but the student divided the number by 259 / 14 , thus the student got 288 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((288 * (259 / 14)) * (259 / 14)) / (1 - ((259 / 14) * (259 / 14)))) / (259 / 14)) = -15.613186813186813"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 102 / 280 of a number . but the student divided the number by 102 / 280 , thus the student got 215 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((215 * (102 / 280)) * (102 / 280)) / (1 - ((102 / 280) * (102 / 280)))) / (102 / 280)) = 90.305312077181"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 113 / 230 of a number . but the student divided the number by 113 / 230 , thus the student got 143 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((143 * (113 / 230)) * (113 / 230)) / (1 - ((113 / 230) * (113 / 230)))) / (113 / 230)) = 92.61094914156138"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 4 / 82 of a number . but the student divided the number by 4 / 82 , thus the student got 217 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((217 * (4 / 82)) * (4 / 82)) / (1 - ((4 / 82) * (4 / 82)))) / (4 / 82)) = 10.61061419200954"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a student was asked to find 175 / 143 of a number . but the student divided the number by 175 / 143 , thus the student got 80 more than the correct answer . find the number .",
        "Solution": "((((80 * (175 / 143)) * (175 / 143)) / (1 - ((175 / 143) * (175 / 143)))) / (175 / 143)) = -196.73742138364778"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 58 person ' s increases by 13 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 141 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 13) + 141) = 895"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 126 person ' s increases by 115 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 72 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * 115) + 72) = 14562"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 53 person ' s increases by 280 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 45 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 280) + 45) = 14885"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 217 person ' s increases by 17 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 16 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 17) + 16) = 3705"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 48 person ' s increases by 112 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 120 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 112) + 120) = 5496"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 259 person ' s increases by 14 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 288 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 14) + 288) = 3914"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 102 person ' s increases by 280 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 215 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 280) + 215) = 28775"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 113 person ' s increases by 230 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 143 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((113 * 230) + 143) = 26133"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 4 person ' s increases by 82 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 217 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((4 * 82) + 217) = 545"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average weight of 175 person ' s increases by 143 kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing 80 kg . what might be the weight of the new person ?",
        "Solution": "((175 * 143) + 80) = 25105"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 58 result is 13 . average of the first 141 of them is 141 and that of the last 141 is 126 . find the 115 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((141 * 141) + (141 * 126)) - (58 * 13)) = 36893"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 72 result is 53 . average of the first 280 of them is 280 and that of the last 280 is 45 . find the 217 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 * 280) + (280 * 45)) - (72 * 53)) = 87184"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 17 result is 16 . average of the first 48 of them is 48 and that of the last 48 is 112 . find the 120 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 48) + (48 * 112)) - (17 * 16)) = 7408"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 259 result is 14 . average of the first 288 of them is 288 and that of the last 288 is 102 . find the 280 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((288 * 288) + (288 * 102)) - (259 * 14)) = 108694"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 215 result is 113 . average of the first 230 of them is 230 and that of the last 230 is 143 . find the 4 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((230 * 230) + (230 * 143)) - (215 * 113)) = 61495"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 82 result is 217 . average of the first 175 of them is 175 and that of the last 175 is 143 . find the 80 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((175 * 175) + (175 * 143)) - (82 * 217)) = 37856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 111 result is 173 . average of the first 53 of them is 53 and that of the last 53 is 48 . find the 195 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 53) + (53 * 48)) - (111 * 173)) = -13850"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 50 result is 184 . average of the first 177 of them is 177 and that of the last 177 is 136 . find the 23 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((177 * 177) + (177 * 136)) - (50 * 184)) = 46201"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 236 result is 275 . average of the first 64 of them is 64 and that of the last 64 is 194 . find the 41 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((64 * 64) + (64 * 194)) - (236 * 275)) = -48388"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average of 283 result is 151 . average of the first 186 of them is 186 and that of the last 186 is 296 . find the 99 th result ?",
        "Solution": "(((186 * 186) + (186 * 296)) - (283 * 151)) = 46919"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 58 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 13 plus 2.58 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 141,126 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 115 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 4) - 12) = 220"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 72 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 53 plus 2.72 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 280,45 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 217 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((72 * 4) - 12) = 276"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 17 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 16 plus 2.17 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 48,112 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 120 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 4) - 12) = 56"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 259 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 14 plus 2.259 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 288,102 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 280 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 4) - 12) = 1024"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 215 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 113 plus 2.215 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 230,143 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 4 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((215 * 4) - 12) = 848"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 82 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 217 plus 2.82 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 175,143 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 80 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((82 * 4) - 12) = 316"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 111 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 173 plus 2.111 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 53,48 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 195 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((111 * 4) - 12) = 432"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 50 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 184 plus 2.50 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 177,136 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 23 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((50 * 4) - 12) = 188"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 236 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 275 plus 2.236 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 64,194 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 41 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((236 * 4) - 12) = 932"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 283 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 151 plus 2.283 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 186,296 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 99 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((283 * 4) - 12) = 1120"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 58 meters by 13 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 141 meters by 141 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 126 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(58 * 58) = 3364"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 115 meters by 72 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 53 meters by 53 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 280 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(115 * 115) = 13225"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 45 meters by 217 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 17 meters by 17 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 16 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(45 * 45) = 2025"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 48 meters by 112 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 120 meters by 120 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 259 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(48 * 48) = 2304"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 14 meters by 288 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 102 meters by 102 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 280 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(14 * 14) = 196"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 215 meters by 113 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 230 meters by 230 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 143 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(215 * 215) = 46225"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 4 meters by 82 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 217 meters by 217 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 175 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(4 * 4) = 16"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 143 meters by 80 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 111 meters by 111 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 173 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(143 * 143) = 20449"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 53 meters by 48 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 195 meters by 195 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 50 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(53 * 53) = 2809"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 184 meters by 177 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 136 meters by 136 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 23 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(184 * 184) = 33856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 58 litre has 13 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 141 litre had 126 % alcohol . the total liquid of 115 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 72 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((13 / 100) * 58) + ((126 / 100) * 141)) / 72) * 100) = 257.2222222222222"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 53 litre has 280 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 45 litre had 217 % alcohol . the total liquid of 17 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 16 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((280 / 100) * 53) + ((217 / 100) * 45)) / 16) * 100) = 1537.8124999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 48 litre has 112 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 120 litre had 259 % alcohol . the total liquid of 14 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 288 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((112 / 100) * 48) + ((259 / 100) * 120)) / 288) * 100) = 126.58333333333331"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 102 litre has 280 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 215 litre had 113 % alcohol . the total liquid of 230 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 143 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((280 / 100) * 102) + ((113 / 100) * 215)) / 143) * 100) = 369.6153846153846"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 4 litre has 82 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 217 litre had 175 % alcohol . the total liquid of 143 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 80 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((82 / 100) * 4) + ((175 / 100) * 217)) / 80) * 100) = 478.78749999999997"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 111 litre has 173 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 53 litre had 48 % alcohol . the total liquid of 195 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 50 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((173 / 100) * 111) + ((48 / 100) * 53)) / 50) * 100) = 434.94"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 184 litre has 177 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 136 litre had 23 % alcohol . the total liquid of 236 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 275 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((177 / 100) * 184) + ((23 / 100) * 136)) / 275) * 100) = 129.8036363636364"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 64 litre has 194 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 41 litre had 283 % alcohol . the total liquid of 151 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 186 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((194 / 100) * 64) + ((283 / 100) * 41)) / 186) * 100) = 129.13440860215053"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 296 litre has 99 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 36 litre had 24 % alcohol . the total liquid of 117 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 149 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((99 / 100) * 296) + ((24 / 100) * 36)) / 149) * 100) = 202.46979865771814"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a vessel of capacity 41 litre has 120 % of alcohol and another vessel of capacity 52 litre had 195 % alcohol . the total liquid of 143 litre was poured out in a vessel of capacity 233 litre and thus the rest part of the vessel was filled with the water . what is the new concentration of mixture ?",
        "Solution": "(((((120 / 100) * 41) + ((195 / 100) * 52)) / 233) * 100) = 64.63519313304721"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 58 of 13 paise and 141 paise make a sum of rs . 126 . the no of 13 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 141) - (126 * 100)) / (141 - 13)) = -34.546875"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 115 of 72 paise and 53 paise make a sum of rs . 280 . the no of 72 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((115 * 53) - (280 * 100)) / (53 - 72)) = 1152.8947368421052"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 45 of 217 paise and 17 paise make a sum of rs . 16 . the no of 217 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 17) - (16 * 100)) / (17 - 217)) = 4.175"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 48 of 112 paise and 120 paise make a sum of rs . 259 . the no of 112 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 120) - (259 * 100)) / (120 - 112)) = -2517.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 14 of 288 paise and 102 paise make a sum of rs . 280 . the no of 288 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((14 * 102) - (280 * 100)) / (102 - 288)) = 142.86021505376345"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 215 of 113 paise and 230 paise make a sum of rs . 143 . the no of 113 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((215 * 230) - (143 * 100)) / (230 - 113)) = 300.4273504273504"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 4 of 82 paise and 217 paise make a sum of rs . 175 . the no of 82 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 217) - (175 * 100)) / (217 - 82)) = -123.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 143 of 80 paise and 111 paise make a sum of rs . 173 . the no of 80 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 111) - (173 * 100)) / (111 - 80)) = -46.03225806451613"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 53 of 48 paise and 195 paise make a sum of rs . 50 . the no of 48 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 195) - (50 * 100)) / (195 - 48)) = 36.29251700680272"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total of 184 of 177 paise and 136 paise make a sum of rs . 23 . the no of 177 paise coins is",
        "Solution": "(((184 * 136) - (23 * 100)) / (136 - 177)) = -554.2439024390244"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 58 to 13 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 141 nor by 126 ?",
        "Solution": "(13 - (((13 / 141) + (13 / 126)) - (13 / (141 * 126)))) = 12.8053585500394"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 115 to 72 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 53 nor by 280 ?",
        "Solution": "(72 - (((72 / 53) + (72 / 280)) - (72 / (53 * 280)))) = 70.38921832884097"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 45 to 217 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 17 nor by 16 ?",
        "Solution": "(217 - (((217 / 17) + (217 / 16)) - (217 / (17 * 16)))) = 191.47058823529412"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 48 to 112 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 120 nor by 259 ?",
        "Solution": "(112 - (((112 / 120) + (112 / 259)) - (112 / (120 * 259)))) = 110.63783783783784"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 14 to 288 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 102 nor by 280 ?",
        "Solution": "(288 - (((288 / 102) + (288 / 280)) - (288 / (102 * 280)))) = 284.1579831932773"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 215 to 113 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 230 nor by 143 ?",
        "Solution": "(113 - (((113 / 230) + (113 / 143)) - (113 / (230 * 143)))) = 111.72192155670416"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 4 to 82 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 217 nor by 175 ?",
        "Solution": "(82 - (((82 / 217) + (82 / 175)) - (82 / (217 * 175)))) = 81.15570770243582"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 143 to 80 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 111 nor by 173 ?",
        "Solution": "(80 - (((80 / 111) + (80 / 173)) - (80 / (111 * 173)))) = 78.82101754934125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 53 to 48 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 195 nor by 50 ?",
        "Solution": "(48 - (((48 / 195) + (48 / 50)) - (48 / (195 * 50)))) = 46.79876923076923"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the number of integers from 184 to 177 ( inclusive ) that are divisible by neither 136 nor by 23 ?",
        "Solution": "(177 - (((177 / 136) + (177 / 23)) - (177 / (136 * 23)))) = 168.05946291560102"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 58 cm long , 13 cm wide and 141 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 126 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((58 * 13) * 141) / 141) + 3) = 757.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 115 cm long , 72 cm wide and 53 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 280 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((115 * 72) * 53) / 53) + 3) = 8283.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 45 cm long , 217 cm wide and 17 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 16 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((45 * 217) * 17) / 17) + 3) = 9768.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 48 cm long , 112 cm wide and 120 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 259 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((48 * 112) * 120) / 120) + 3) = 5379.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 14 cm long , 288 cm wide and 102 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 280 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((14 * 288) * 102) / 102) + 3) = 4035.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 215 cm long , 113 cm wide and 230 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 143 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((215 * 113) * 230) / 230) + 3) = 24298.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 4 cm long , 82 cm wide and 217 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 175 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((4 * 82) * 217) / 217) + 3) = 331.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 143 cm long , 80 cm wide and 111 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 173 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((143 * 80) * 111) / 111) + 3) = 11443.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 53 cm long , 48 cm wide and 195 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 50 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((53 * 48) * 195) / 195) + 3) = 2547.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arun makes a popular brand of ice cream in a rectangular shaped bar 184 cm long , 177 cm wide and 136 cm thick . to cut costs , the company had decided to reduce the volume of the bar by 23 % . the thickness will remain same , but the length and width will be decreased by some percentage . the new width will be ,",
        "Solution": "((((184 * 177) * 136) / 136) + 3) = 32571.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 58 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((58 / ((2 + 58) * 58)) + (2 / ((2 + 58) * 58))) + (1 / ((2 + 58) * 58)))) = 0.9824712643678161"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 13 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((13 / ((2 + 13) * 13)) + (2 / ((2 + 13) * 13))) + (1 / ((2 + 13) * 13)))) = 0.9179487179487179"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 141 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((141 / ((2 + 141) * 141)) + (2 / ((2 + 141) * 141))) + (1 / ((2 + 141) * 141)))) = 0.992858205624163"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 126 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((126 / ((2 + 126) * 126)) + (2 / ((2 + 126) * 126))) + (1 / ((2 + 126) * 126)))) = 0.9920014880952381"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 115 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((115 / ((2 + 115) * 115)) + (2 / ((2 + 115) * 115))) + (1 / ((2 + 115) * 115)))) = 0.9912300260126347"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 72 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((72 / ((2 + 72) * 72)) + (2 / ((2 + 72) * 72))) + (1 / ((2 + 72) * 72)))) = 0.9859234234234234"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 53 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((53 / ((2 + 53) * 53)) + (2 / ((2 + 53) * 53))) + (1 / ((2 + 53) * 53)))) = 0.9807890222984562"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 280 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((280 / ((2 + 280) * 280)) + (2 / ((2 + 280) * 280))) + (1 / ((2 + 280) * 280)))) = 0.9964159067882472"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 45 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((45 / ((2 + 45) * 45)) + (2 / ((2 + 45) * 45))) + (1 / ((2 + 45) * 45)))) = 0.9773049645390071"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kim finds a 217 - meter tree branch and marks it off in thirds and fifths . she then breaks the branch along all the markings and removes one piece of every distinct length . what fraction of the original branch remains ?",
        "Solution": "(1 - (((217 / ((2 + 217) * 217)) + (2 / ((2 + 217) * 217))) + (1 / ((2 + 217) * 217)))) = 0.9953706626265176"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 58 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 13 . each pot cost 141 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((13 - ((((58 - 1) * 58) / 2) * 141)) / 58) + ((58 - 1) * 141)) = 4018.7241379310344"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 126 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 115 . each pot cost 72 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 - ((((126 - 1) * 126) / 2) * 72)) / 126) + ((126 - 1) * 72)) = 4500.912698412699"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 53 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 280 . each pot cost 45 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 - ((((53 - 1) * 53) / 2) * 45)) / 53) + ((53 - 1) * 45)) = 1175.2830188679245"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 217 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 17 . each pot cost 16 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((17 - ((((217 - 1) * 217) / 2) * 16)) / 217) + ((217 - 1) * 16)) = 1728.078341013825"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 48 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 112 . each pot cost 120 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((112 - ((((48 - 1) * 48) / 2) * 120)) / 48) + ((48 - 1) * 120)) = 2822.3333333333335"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 259 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 14 . each pot cost 288 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 - ((((259 - 1) * 259) / 2) * 288)) / 259) + ((259 - 1) * 288)) = 37152.05405405405"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 102 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 280 . each pot cost 215 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 - ((((102 - 1) * 102) / 2) * 215)) / 102) + ((102 - 1) * 215)) = 10860.245098039215"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 113 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 230 . each pot cost 143 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((230 - ((((113 - 1) * 113) / 2) * 143)) / 113) + ((113 - 1) * 143)) = 8010.0353982300885"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 4 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 82 . each pot cost 217 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((82 - ((((4 - 1) * 4) / 2) * 217)) / 4) + ((4 - 1) * 217)) = 346.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "mark bought a set of 175 flower pots of different sizes at a total cost of $ 143 . each pot cost 80 more than the next one below it in size . what was the cost , in dollars , of the largest pot ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 - ((((175 - 1) * 175) / 2) * 80)) / 175) + ((175 - 1) * 80)) = 6960.817142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 58 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 13 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 141 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 126 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 115 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 72 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 53 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 280 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 45 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the above number , a and b represent the tens and units digits , respectively . if the above number is divisible by 217 , what is the greatest possible value of b x a ?",
        "Solution": "((3 + 4) * (2 + 3)) = 35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 58 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 13 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((58 + 13) / 2) = 35.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 141 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 126 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((141 + 126) / 2) = 133.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 115 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 72 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((115 + 72) / 2) = 93.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 53 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 280 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((53 + 280) / 2) = 166.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 45 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 217 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((45 + 217) / 2) = 131.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 17 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 16 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((17 + 16) / 2) = 16.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 48 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 112 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((48 + 112) / 2) = 80.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 120 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 259 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((120 + 259) / 2) = 189.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 14 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 288 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((14 + 288) / 2) = 151.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the profit obtained by selling an article for rs . 102 is the same as the loss obtained by selling it for rs . 280 . what is the cost price of the article ?",
        "Solution": "((102 + 280) / 2) = 191.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 58 , the profits of company n were 13 percent of revenues . in 141 , the revenues of company n fell by 126 percent , but profits were 115 percent of revenues . the profits in 141 were what percent of the profits in 58 ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 * (1 - (126 / 100))) / 13) * 100) = -230.00000000000003"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 72 , the profits of company n were 53 percent of revenues . in 280 , the revenues of company n fell by 45 percent , but profits were 217 percent of revenues . the profits in 280 were what percent of the profits in 72 ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * (1 - (45 / 100))) / 53) * 100) = 225.18867924528303"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 17 , the profits of company n were 16 percent of revenues . in 48 , the revenues of company n fell by 112 percent , but profits were 120 percent of revenues . the profits in 48 were what percent of the profits in 17 ?",
        "Solution": "(((120 * (1 - (112 / 100))) / 16) * 100) = -90.00000000000009"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 259 , the profits of company n were 14 percent of revenues . in 288 , the revenues of company n fell by 102 percent , but profits were 280 percent of revenues . the profits in 288 were what percent of the profits in 259 ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 * (1 - (102 / 100))) / 14) * 100) = -40.000000000000036"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 215 , the profits of company n were 113 percent of revenues . in 230 , the revenues of company n fell by 143 percent , but profits were 4 percent of revenues . the profits in 230 were what percent of the profits in 215 ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * (1 - (143 / 100))) / 113) * 100) = -1.5221238938053094"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 82 , the profits of company n were 217 percent of revenues . in 175 , the revenues of company n fell by 143 percent , but profits were 80 percent of revenues . the profits in 175 were what percent of the profits in 82 ?",
        "Solution": "(((80 * (1 - (143 / 100))) / 217) * 100) = -15.852534562211979"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 111 , the profits of company n were 173 percent of revenues . in 53 , the revenues of company n fell by 48 percent , but profits were 195 percent of revenues . the profits in 53 were what percent of the profits in 111 ?",
        "Solution": "(((195 * (1 - (48 / 100))) / 173) * 100) = 58.61271676300578"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 50 , the profits of company n were 184 percent of revenues . in 177 , the revenues of company n fell by 136 percent , but profits were 23 percent of revenues . the profits in 177 were what percent of the profits in 50 ?",
        "Solution": "(((23 * (1 - (136 / 100))) / 184) * 100) = -4.500000000000002"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 236 , the profits of company n were 275 percent of revenues . in 64 , the revenues of company n fell by 194 percent , but profits were 41 percent of revenues . the profits in 64 were what percent of the profits in 236 ?",
        "Solution": "(((41 * (1 - (194 / 100))) / 275) * 100) = -14.014545454545454"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in 283 , the profits of company n were 151 percent of revenues . in 186 , the revenues of company n fell by 296 percent , but profits were 99 percent of revenues . the profits in 186 were what percent of the profits in 283 ?",
        "Solution": "(((99 * (1 - (296 / 100))) / 151) * 100) = -128.50331125827813"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 58 men has provisions for 13 days . at the end of 141 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 126 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 * 13) - (58 * 141)) / 126) - 58) = -116.92063492063491"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 115 men has provisions for 72 days . at the end of 53 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 280 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((115 * 72) - (115 * 53)) / 280) - 115) = -107.19642857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 45 men has provisions for 217 days . at the end of 17 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 16 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((45 * 217) - (45 * 17)) / 16) - 45) = 517.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 48 men has provisions for 112 days . at the end of 120 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 259 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((48 * 112) - (48 * 120)) / 259) - 48) = -49.48262548262548"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 14 men has provisions for 288 days . at the end of 102 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 280 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((14 * 288) - (14 * 102)) / 280) - 14) = -4.699999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 215 men has provisions for 113 days . at the end of 230 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 143 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((215 * 113) - (215 * 230)) / 143) - 215) = -390.9090909090909"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 4 men has provisions for 82 days . at the end of 217 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 175 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((4 * 82) - (4 * 217)) / 175) - 4) = -7.085714285714285"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 143 men has provisions for 80 days . at the end of 111 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 173 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((143 * 80) - (143 * 111)) / 173) - 143) = -168.6242774566474"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 53 men has provisions for 48 days . at the end of 195 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 50 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 * 48) - (53 * 195)) / 50) - 53) = -208.82"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a garrison of 184 men has provisions for 177 days . at the end of 136 days , a reinforcement arrives , and it is now found that the provisions will last only for 23 days more . what is the reinforcement ?",
        "Solution": "((((184 * 177) - (184 * 136)) / 23) - 184) = 144.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 58 percent and then increases this speed by 13 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 58) + ((100 + 58) * (13 / 100))) - 100) = 78.53999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 141 percent and then increases this speed by 126 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 141) + ((100 + 141) * (126 / 100))) - 100) = 444.6600000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 115 percent and then increases this speed by 72 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 115) + ((100 + 115) * (72 / 100))) - 100) = 269.79999999999995"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 53 percent and then increases this speed by 280 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 53) + ((100 + 53) * (280 / 100))) - 100) = 481.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 45 percent and then increases this speed by 217 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 45) + ((100 + 45) * (217 / 100))) - 100) = 359.65"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 17 percent and then increases this speed by 16 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 17) + ((100 + 17) * (16 / 100))) - 100) = 35.72"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 48 percent and then increases this speed by 112 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 48) + ((100 + 48) * (112 / 100))) - 100) = 213.76"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 120 percent and then increases this speed by 259 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 120) + ((100 + 120) * (259 / 100))) - 100) = 689.8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 14 percent and then increases this speed by 288 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 14) + ((100 + 14) * (288 / 100))) - 100) = 342.32"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a bicyclist in motion increases his speed by 102 percent and then increases this speed by 280 percent , what percent of the original speed is the total increase in speed ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 102) + ((100 + 102) * (280 / 100))) - 100) = 667.5999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 58 , 13 and 141 leaving a remainder of 126 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((141 - 126) - (13 - 126)) - (58 - 126)) / 3) / 2) = 32.666666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 115 , 72 and 53 leaving a remainder of 280 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((53 - 280) - (72 - 280)) - (115 - 280)) / 3) / 2) = 24.333333333333332"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 45 , 217 and 17 leaving a remainder of 16 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((17 - 16) - (217 - 16)) - (45 - 16)) / 3) / 2) = -38.166666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 48 , 112 and 120 leaving a remainder of 259 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((120 - 259) - (112 - 259)) - (48 - 259)) / 3) / 2) = 36.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 14 , 288 and 102 leaving a remainder of 280 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((102 - 280) - (288 - 280)) - (14 - 280)) / 3) / 2) = 13.333333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 215 , 113 and 230 leaving a remainder of 143 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((230 - 143) - (113 - 143)) - (215 - 143)) / 3) / 2) = 7.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 4 , 82 and 217 leaving a remainder of 175 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((217 - 175) - (82 - 175)) - (4 - 175)) / 3) / 2) = 51.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 143 , 80 and 111 leaving a remainder of 173 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((111 - 173) - (80 - 173)) - (143 - 173)) / 3) / 2) = 10.166666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 53 , 48 and 195 leaving a remainder of 50 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((195 - 50) - (48 - 50)) - (53 - 50)) / 3) / 2) = 24.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the greatest number that divides 184 , 177 and 136 leaving a remainder of 23 in each case ?",
        "Solution": "(((((136 - 23) - (177 - 23)) - (184 - 23)) / 3) / 2) = -33.666666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 58 and 13 which are divisible by 141 .",
        "Solution": "(((58 + 4) + (13 - 4)) / 2) = 35.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 126 and 115 which are divisible by 72 .",
        "Solution": "(((126 + 4) + (115 - 4)) / 2) = 120.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 53 and 280 which are divisible by 45 .",
        "Solution": "(((53 + 4) + (280 - 4)) / 2) = 166.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 217 and 17 which are divisible by 16 .",
        "Solution": "(((217 + 4) + (17 - 4)) / 2) = 117.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 48 and 112 which are divisible by 120 .",
        "Solution": "(((48 + 4) + (112 - 4)) / 2) = 80.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 259 and 14 which are divisible by 288 .",
        "Solution": "(((259 + 4) + (14 - 4)) / 2) = 136.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 102 and 280 which are divisible by 215 .",
        "Solution": "(((102 + 4) + (280 - 4)) / 2) = 191.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 113 and 230 which are divisible by 143 .",
        "Solution": "(((113 + 4) + (230 - 4)) / 2) = 171.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 4 and 82 which are divisible by 217 .",
        "Solution": "(((4 + 4) + (82 - 4)) / 2) = 43.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "find the average of all the numbers between 175 and 143 which are divisible by 80 .",
        "Solution": "(((175 + 4) + (143 - 4)) / 2) = 159.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 58 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 58) / 58) * 100) = 72.41379310344827"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 13 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 13) / 13) * 100) = 669.2307692307693"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 141 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 141) / 141) * 100) = -29.078014184397162"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 126 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 126) / 126) * 100) = -20.634920634920633"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 115 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 115) / 115) * 100) = -13.043478260869565"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 72 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 72) / 72) * 100) = 38.88888888888889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 53 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 53) / 53) * 100) = 88.67924528301887"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 280 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 280) / 280) * 100) = -64.28571428571429"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 45 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 45) / 45) * 100) = 122.22222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the cost price is 217 % of sp then what is the profit %",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 217) / 217) * 100) = -53.91705069124424"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 58 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 13 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 141 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 / 13) * 100) * 141) - (58 * 141)) = 54729.69230769231"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 126 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 115 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 72 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((126 / 115) * 100) * 72) - (126 * 72)) = -1183.304347826087"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 53 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 280 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 45 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 / 280) * 100) * 45) - (53 * 45)) = -1533.2142857142858"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 217 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 17 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 16 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((217 / 17) * 100) * 16) - (217 * 16)) = 16951.529411764706"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 48 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 112 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 120 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((48 / 112) * 100) * 120) - (48 * 120)) = -617.1428571428578"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 259 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 14 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 288 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((259 / 14) * 100) * 288) - (259 * 288)) = 458208.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 102 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 280 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 215 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((102 / 280) * 100) * 215) - (102 * 215)) = -14097.857142857145"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 113 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 230 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 143 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((113 / 230) * 100) * 143) - (113 * 143)) = -9133.347826086956"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 4 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 82 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 217 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((4 / 82) * 100) * 217) - (4 * 217)) = 190.53658536585363"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car gets 175 miles to the gallon . if it is modified to use a solar panel , it will use only 143 percent as much fuel as it does now . if the fuel tank holds 80 gallons , how many more miles will the car be able to travel , per full tank of fuel , after it has been modified ?",
        "Solution": "((((175 / 143) * 100) * 80) - (175 * 80)) = -4209.79020979021"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 58 men for 13 days . after 141 days , 126 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((58 * (126 + 141)) / (58 - 126)) = -227.73529411764707"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 115 men for 72 days . after 53 days , 280 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((115 * (280 + 53)) / (115 - 280)) = -232.0909090909091"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 45 men for 217 days . after 17 days , 16 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((45 * (16 + 17)) / (45 - 16)) = 51.206896551724135"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 48 men for 112 days . after 120 days , 259 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((48 * (259 + 120)) / (48 - 259)) = -86.21800947867298"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 14 men for 288 days . after 102 days , 280 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((14 * (280 + 102)) / (14 - 280)) = -20.105263157894736"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 215 men for 113 days . after 230 days , 143 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((215 * (143 + 230)) / (215 - 143)) = 1113.8194444444443"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 4 men for 82 days . after 217 days , 175 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((4 * (175 + 217)) / (4 - 175)) = -9.169590643274853"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 143 men for 80 days . after 111 days , 173 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((143 * (173 + 111)) / (143 - 173)) = -1353.7333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 53 men for 48 days . after 195 days , 50 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((53 * (50 + 195)) / (53 - 50)) = 4328.333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fort had provision of food for 184 men for 177 days . after 136 days , 23 men left the fort . the number of days for which the remaining food will last , is :",
        "Solution": "((184 * (23 + 136)) / (184 - 23)) = 181.71428571428572"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 58 % per annum at simple interest and in 13 years the interest amounted to rs . 141 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(141 / (1 - ((58 * 13) / 100))) = -21.559633027522935"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 126 % per annum at simple interest and in 115 years the interest amounted to rs . 72 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(72 / (1 - ((126 * 115) / 100))) = -0.5003474635163307"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 53 % per annum at simple interest and in 280 years the interest amounted to rs . 45 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(45 / (1 - ((53 * 280) / 100))) = -0.30529172320217096"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 217 % per annum at simple interest and in 17 years the interest amounted to rs . 16 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(16 / (1 - ((217 * 17) / 100))) = -0.4458066313736417"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 48 % per annum at simple interest and in 112 years the interest amounted to rs . 120 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / (1 - ((48 * 112) / 100))) = -2.2744503411675514"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 259 % per annum at simple interest and in 14 years the interest amounted to rs . 288 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(288 / (1 - ((259 * 14) / 100))) = -8.167895632444697"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 102 % per annum at simple interest and in 280 years the interest amounted to rs . 215 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(215 / (1 - ((102 * 280) / 100))) = -0.7554462403373154"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 113 % per annum at simple interest and in 230 years the interest amounted to rs . 143 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(143 / (1 - ((113 * 230) / 100))) = -0.5523368095789881"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 4 % per annum at simple interest and in 82 years the interest amounted to rs . 217 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / (1 - ((4 * 82) / 100))) = -95.17543859649123"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person lent a certain sum of money at 175 % per annum at simple interest and in 143 years the interest amounted to rs . 80 less than the sum lent . what was the sum lent ?",
        "Solution": "(80 / (1 - ((175 * 143) / 100))) = -0.320962888665998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 58 and the number of feet equals 13 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 4) - 13) / 2) = 109.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 141 and the number of feet equals 126 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((141 * 4) - 126) / 2) = 219.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 115 and the number of feet equals 72 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((115 * 4) - 72) / 2) = 194.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 53 and the number of feet equals 280 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 4) - 280) / 2) = -34.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 45 and the number of feet equals 217 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 4) - 217) / 2) = -18.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 17 and the number of feet equals 16 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((17 * 4) - 16) / 2) = 26.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 48 and the number of feet equals 112 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 4) - 112) / 2) = 40.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 120 and the number of feet equals 259 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((120 * 4) - 259) / 2) = 110.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 14 and the number of feet equals 288 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((14 * 4) - 288) / 2) = -116.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man has some hens and cows . if the number of heads be 102 and the number of feet equals 280 , then the number of hens will be",
        "Solution": "(((102 * 4) - 280) / 2) = 64.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 58 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 13 % on hers . if mindy earned 141 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((58 / 100) + (141 * (13 / 100))) / (1 + 141))) = 13.316901408450704"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 126 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 115 % on hers . if mindy earned 72 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((126 / 100) + (72 * (115 / 100))) / (1 + 72))) = 115.15068493150685"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 53 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 280 % on hers . if mindy earned 45 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((53 / 100) + (45 * (280 / 100))) / (1 + 45))) = 275.0652173913043"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 217 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 17 % on hers . if mindy earned 16 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((217 / 100) + (16 * (17 / 100))) / (1 + 16))) = 28.764705882352942"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 48 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 112 % on hers . if mindy earned 120 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((48 / 100) + (120 * (112 / 100))) / (1 + 120))) = 111.47107438016528"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 259 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 14 % on hers . if mindy earned 288 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((259 / 100) + (288 * (14 / 100))) / (1 + 288))) = 14.847750865051907"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 102 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 280 % on hers . if mindy earned 215 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((102 / 100) + (215 * (280 / 100))) / (1 + 215))) = 279.1759259259259"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 113 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 230 % on hers . if mindy earned 143 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((113 / 100) + (143 * (230 / 100))) / (1 + 143))) = 229.18749999999997"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 4 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 82 % on hers . if mindy earned 217 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((4 / 100) + (217 * (82 / 100))) / (1 + 217))) = 81.64220183486238"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "because he \u2019 s taxed by his home planet , mork pays a tax rate of 175 % on his income , while mindy pays a rate of only 143 % on hers . if mindy earned 80 times as much as mork did , what was their combined tax rate ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * (((175 / 100) + (80 * (143 / 100))) / (1 + 80))) = 143.39506172839504"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 58 % . if it was sold for rs . 13 more , there would have been a gain of 58 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((13 * 100) / ((100 + 58) - (100 - 58))) = 11.206896551724139"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 141 % . if it was sold for rs . 126 more , there would have been a gain of 141 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * 100) / ((100 + 141) - (100 - 141))) = 44.680851063829785"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 115 % . if it was sold for rs . 72 more , there would have been a gain of 115 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((72 * 100) / ((100 + 115) - (100 - 115))) = 31.304347826086957"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 53 % . if it was sold for rs . 280 more , there would have been a gain of 53 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 100) / ((100 + 53) - (100 - 53))) = 264.1509433962264"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 45 % . if it was sold for rs . 217 more , there would have been a gain of 45 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 100) / ((100 + 45) - (100 - 45))) = 241.11111111111111"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 17 % . if it was sold for rs . 16 more , there would have been a gain of 17 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((16 * 100) / ((100 + 17) - (100 - 17))) = 47.05882352941177"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 48 % . if it was sold for rs . 112 more , there would have been a gain of 48 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((112 * 100) / ((100 + 48) - (100 - 48))) = 116.66666666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 120 % . if it was sold for rs . 259 more , there would have been a gain of 120 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 100) / ((100 + 120) - (100 - 120))) = 107.91666666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 14 % . if it was sold for rs . 288 more , there would have been a gain of 14 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((288 * 100) / ((100 + 14) - (100 - 14))) = 1028.5714285714287"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a watch was sold at a loss of 102 % . if it was sold for rs . 280 more , there would have been a gain of 102 % . what is the cost price ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 100) / ((100 + 102) - (100 - 102))) = 137.2549019607843"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 58 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 13 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(58 * 13) = 754"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 141 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 126 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(141 * 126) = 17766"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 115 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 72 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(115 * 72) = 8280"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 53 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 280 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(53 * 280) = 14840"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 45 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 217 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(45 * 217) = 9765"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 17 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 16 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(17 * 16) = 272"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 48 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 112 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(48 * 112) = 5376"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 120 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 259 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(120 * 259) = 31080"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 14 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 288 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(14 * 288) = 4032"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels at a speed of 102 miles per hour . how far will it travel in 280 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(102 * 280) = 28560"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 58 people eat only vegetarian , 13 people eat only non veg . , 141 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(58 + 141) = 199"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 126 people eat only vegetarian , 115 people eat only non veg . , 72 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(126 + 72) = 198"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 53 people eat only vegetarian , 280 people eat only non veg . , 45 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(53 + 45) = 98"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 217 people eat only vegetarian , 17 people eat only non veg . , 16 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(217 + 16) = 233"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 48 people eat only vegetarian , 112 people eat only non veg . , 120 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(48 + 120) = 168"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 259 people eat only vegetarian , 14 people eat only non veg . , 288 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(259 + 288) = 547"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 102 people eat only vegetarian , 280 people eat only non veg . , 215 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(102 + 215) = 317"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 113 people eat only vegetarian , 230 people eat only non veg . , 143 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(113 + 143) = 256"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 4 people eat only vegetarian , 82 people eat only non veg . , 217 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(4 + 217) = 221"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a family 175 people eat only vegetarian , 143 people eat only non veg . , 80 people eat both veg and non veg . . how many people eat veg in the family ?",
        "Solution": "(175 + 80) = 255"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 58 / 13 , then the value of 141 / 126 + { ( 115 q - p ) / ( 115 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((141 / 126) + ((115 - (58 / 13)) / (115 + (58 / 13)))) = 2.0443534786741484"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 72 / 53 , then the value of 280 / 45 + { ( 217 q - p ) / ( 217 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((280 / 45) + ((217 - (72 / 53)) / (217 + (72 / 53)))) = 7.209779467534587"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 17 / 16 , then the value of 48 / 112 + { ( 120 q - p ) / ( 120 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((48 / 112) + ((120 - (17 / 16)) / (120 + (17 / 16)))) = 1.4110185116896525"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 259 / 14 , then the value of 288 / 102 + { ( 280 q - p ) / ( 280 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((288 / 102) + ((280 - (259 / 14)) / (280 + (259 / 14)))) = 3.6995763129372357"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 215 / 113 , then the value of 230 / 143 + { ( 4 q - p ) / ( 4 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((230 / 143) + ((4 - (215 / 113)) / (4 + (215 / 113)))) = 1.963713947222193"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 82 / 217 , then the value of 175 / 143 + { ( 80 q - p ) / ( 80 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((175 / 143) + ((80 - (82 / 217)) / (80 + (82 / 217)))) = 2.2143736323302887"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 111 / 173 , then the value of 53 / 48 + { ( 195 q - p ) / ( 195 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((53 / 48) + ((195 - (111 / 173)) / (195 + (111 / 173)))) = 2.097607545943391"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 50 / 184 , then the value of 177 / 136 + { ( 23 q - p ) / ( 23 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((177 / 136) + ((23 - (50 / 184)) / (23 + (50 / 184)))) = 2.2781170151386103"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 236 / 275 , then the value of 64 / 194 + { ( 41 q - p ) / ( 41 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((64 / 194) + ((41 - (236 / 275)) / (41 + (236 / 275)))) = 1.2888926504186493"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if p / q = 283 / 151 , then the value of 186 / 296 + { ( 99 q - p ) / ( 99 q + p ) } is ?",
        "Solution": "((186 / 296) + ((99 - (283 / 151)) / (99 + (283 / 151)))) = 1.5912197649330002"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 58 + y ^ 58 = 13 and xy = 141 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 58 =",
        "Solution": "(141 ** 58) = 45155279418350889236060536203086896715575451489120306149991262159994871032263072549447808066189903223530074508546726830870921"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 126 + y ^ 126 = 115 and xy = 72 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 126 =",
        "Solution": "(72 ** 126) = 1056560937869495299765969560979233194270341129079086834889801848171487545135725550207553009170811492228226467200498186751192669219465303583205206083267368261011056267481288534014354363792116542714106198039906132751368570855611489583104"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 53 + y ^ 53 = 280 and xy = 45 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 53 =",
        "Solution": "(45 ** 53) = 4171221286304718892940847791974000677848581725578924750408305044402368366718292236328125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 217 + y ^ 217 = 17 and xy = 16 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 217 =",
        "Solution": "(16 ** 217) = 1968050491570179337085559162931578630651709906891441055118891257892079288351255876848165899096642389501163344805155428792843027262027135257611196407910211298273454174395669565233333102153340134967208776281070666030600772398529804270112502942856537090575466233856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 48 + y ^ 48 = 112 and xy = 120 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 48 =",
        "Solution": "(120 ** 48) = 6319748715279270675921934218987893281199411530039296000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 259 + y ^ 259 = 14 and xy = 288 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 259 =",
        "Solution": "(288 ** 259) = 9608472016308727975389670541431545864394887137205832127055601623955370824988771876809126361571418446340501564044953087732446720159523087247875931411987506907251052965149858549325645293898612507574354317015722575066896746563116423627868095248611676262512245203605308518586515398884907533886122554783460167172075511652186453698546168526082870923189594952219888054257162846022755713430688032591370701864353712474921092466825309099354809906097695323321649979501348043459037383720746701029123208876065993525079683131980321454996277844352586256887132412205814619032077732970032417747034322007841731946400719075973656376748581683075809544241152"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 102 + y ^ 102 = 280 and xy = 215 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 102 =",
        "Solution": "(215 ** 102) = 8104438134232959755370422636268041069569516619835429114071689923245781678039198089497266548177830731187179149118422381163414448136447204225521231825488001705420371645208116356120143810921039968981662016123124203659244813024997711181640625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 113 + y ^ 113 = 230 and xy = 143 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 113 =",
        "Solution": "(143 ** 113) = 3572499967827980065915069981416945448565927460102859048228361774391655927106409864335943817050655569893270414552158484439855000253596120801253563575734372633073816715603171367417495070827007728209731205874695424296321646968782074251104473286543"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 4 + y ^ 4 = 82 and xy = 217 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 4 =",
        "Solution": "(217 ** 4) = 2217373921"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if x ^ 175 + y ^ 175 = 143 and xy = 80 , then ( x \u2212 y ) ^ 175 =",
        "Solution": "(80 ** 175) = 1098367625620897554397104127853022914763109648022928865503114153469686909343624968339609542505832728796367409822636937285939518079954663010011844526578409144320000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 58 % full with water . if 13 liters of water is added , the container becomes 141 / 126 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(13 / ((141 / 126) - (58 / 100))) = 24.116607773851587"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 115 % full with water . if 72 liters of water is added , the container becomes 53 / 280 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(72 / ((53 / 280) - (115 / 100))) = -74.94423791821562"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 45 % full with water . if 217 liters of water is added , the container becomes 17 / 16 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / ((17 / 16) - (45 / 100))) = 354.2857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 48 % full with water . if 112 liters of water is added , the container becomes 120 / 259 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(112 / ((120 / 259) - (48 / 100))) = -6714.814814814829"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 14 % full with water . if 288 liters of water is added , the container becomes 102 / 280 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(288 / ((102 / 280) - (14 / 100))) = 1284.0764331210194"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 215 % full with water . if 113 liters of water is added , the container becomes 230 / 143 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(113 / ((230 / 143) - (215 / 100))) = -208.63783085861849"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 4 % full with water . if 82 liters of water is added , the container becomes 217 / 175 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(82 / ((217 / 175) - (4 / 100))) = 68.33333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 143 % full with water . if 80 liters of water is added , the container becomes 111 / 173 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(80 / ((111 / 173) - (143 / 100))) = -101.47371508175087"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 53 % full with water . if 48 liters of water is added , the container becomes 195 / 50 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(48 / ((195 / 50) - (53 / 100))) = 14.243323442136498"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a big container is 184 % full with water . if 177 liters of water is added , the container becomes 136 / 23 full . what is the capacity of the big container in liters ?",
        "Solution": "(177 / ((136 / 23) - (184 / 100))) = 43.456447480785656"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 58 : 13 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 / 13) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = 7.923076923076923"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 141 : 126 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((141 / 126) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = 1.2380952380952381"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 115 : 72 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 / 72) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = 2.1944444444444446"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 53 : 280 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 / 280) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = -0.6214285714285714"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 45 : 217 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 / 217) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = -0.5852534562211982"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 17 : 16 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((17 / 16) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = 1.125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 48 : 112 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 / 112) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = -0.1428571428571429"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 120 : 259 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((120 / 259) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = -0.07335907335907332"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 14 : 288 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 / 288) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = -0.9027777777777778"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of the arithmetic mean of two numbers to one of the numbers is 102 : 280 . what is the ratio of the smaller number to the larger number ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 / 280) - (1 / 2)) * 2) = -0.27142857142857146"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 58 : 13 : 141 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 126 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((141 * (126 / (13 + 141))) / (126 / (13 + 141))) - 1) * 100) = 14000.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 115 : 72 : 53 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 280 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 * (280 / (72 + 53))) / (280 / (72 + 53))) - 1) * 100) = 5200.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 45 : 217 : 17 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 16 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((17 * (16 / (217 + 17))) / (16 / (217 + 17))) - 1) * 100) = 1600.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 48 : 112 : 120 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 259 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((120 * (259 / (112 + 120))) / (259 / (112 + 120))) - 1) * 100) = 11899.999999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 14 : 288 : 102 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 280 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((102 * (280 / (288 + 102))) / (280 / (288 + 102))) - 1) * 100) = 10100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 215 : 113 : 230 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 143 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((230 * (143 / (113 + 230))) / (143 / (113 + 230))) - 1) * 100) = 22900.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 4 : 82 : 217 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 175 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((217 * (175 / (82 + 217))) / (175 / (82 + 217))) - 1) * 100) = 21600.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 143 : 80 : 111 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 173 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((111 * (173 / (80 + 111))) / (173 / (80 + 111))) - 1) * 100) = 11000.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 53 : 48 : 195 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 50 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((195 * (50 / (48 + 195))) / (50 / (48 + 195))) - 1) * 100) = 19400.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the salaries of a , b , and c are in the ratio of 184 : 177 : 136 . the salary of b and c together is rs . 23 . by what percent is the salary of c more than that of a ?",
        "Solution": "((((136 * (23 / (177 + 136))) / (23 / (177 + 136))) - 1) * 100) = 13500.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 58 km and upstream 13 km taking 141 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((13 / 141) + (58 / 141)) / 2) = 0.25177304964539005"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 126 km and upstream 115 km taking 72 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 / 72) + (126 / 72)) / 2) = 1.6736111111111112"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 53 km and upstream 280 km taking 45 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 / 45) + (53 / 45)) / 2) = 3.7"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 217 km and upstream 17 km taking 16 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((17 / 16) + (217 / 16)) / 2) = 7.3125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 48 km and upstream 112 km taking 120 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((112 / 120) + (48 / 120)) / 2) = 0.6666666666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 259 km and upstream 14 km taking 288 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 / 288) + (259 / 288)) / 2) = 0.47395833333333337"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 102 km and upstream 280 km taking 215 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 / 215) + (102 / 215)) / 2) = 0.8883720930232559"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 113 km and upstream 230 km taking 143 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((230 / 143) + (113 / 143)) / 2) = 1.1993006993006992"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 4 km and upstream 82 km taking 217 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((82 / 217) + (4 / 217)) / 2) = 0.19815668202764974"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a man swims downstream 175 km and upstream 143 km taking 80 hours each time ; what is the speed of the current ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 / 80) + (175 / 80)) / 2) = 1.9875"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 58 days . prakash can do the same work in 13 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 141 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (141 * (1 / 13))) / (1 / 58)) = -571.0769230769231"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 126 days . prakash can do the same work in 115 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 72 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (72 * (1 / 115))) / (1 / 126)) = 47.11304347826086"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 53 days . prakash can do the same work in 280 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 45 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (45 * (1 / 280))) / (1 / 53)) = 44.48214285714286"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 217 days . prakash can do the same work in 17 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 16 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (16 * (1 / 17))) / (1 / 217)) = 12.764705882352944"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 48 days . prakash can do the same work in 112 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 120 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (120 * (1 / 112))) / (1 / 48)) = -3.428571428571427"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 259 days . prakash can do the same work in 14 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 288 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (288 * (1 / 14))) / (1 / 259)) = -5068.999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 102 days . prakash can do the same work in 280 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 215 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (215 * (1 / 280))) / (1 / 102)) = 23.678571428571434"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 113 days . prakash can do the same work in 230 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 143 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (143 * (1 / 230))) / (1 / 113)) = 42.74347826086957"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 4 days . prakash can do the same work in 82 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 217 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (217 * (1 / 82))) / (1 / 4)) = -6.585365853658537"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "vinoth can complete a painting work in 175 days . prakash can do the same work in 143 days . they start the work together but vinoth quit after 80 days of work . how many days are required to complete the remaining painting work by prakash .",
        "Solution": "((1 - (80 * (1 / 143))) / (1 / 175)) = 77.0979020979021"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 58 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 13 people , the cost per person would have been $ 141 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((13 * 58) * (141 / (13 - 58))) = -2362.5333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 126 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 115 people , the cost per person would have been $ 72 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * 126) * (72 / (115 - 126))) = -94843.63636363637"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 53 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 280 people , the cost per person would have been $ 45 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 53) * (45 / (280 - 53))) = 2941.850220264317"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 217 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 17 people , the cost per person would have been $ 16 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 217) * (16 / (17 - 217))) = -295.12"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 48 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 112 people , the cost per person would have been $ 120 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((112 * 48) * (120 / (112 - 48))) = 10080.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 259 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 14 people , the cost per person would have been $ 288 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * 259) * (288 / (14 - 259))) = -4262.400000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 102 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 280 people , the cost per person would have been $ 215 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 102) * (215 / (280 - 102))) = 34496.629213483146"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 113 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 230 people , the cost per person would have been $ 143 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((230 * 113) * (143 / (230 - 113))) = 31765.55555555556"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 4 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 82 people , the cost per person would have been $ 217 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((82 * 4) * (217 / (82 - 4))) = 912.5128205128204"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total cost of a vacation was divided among 175 people . if the total cost of the vacation had been divided equally among 143 people , the cost per person would have been $ 80 less . what was the total cost cost of the vacation ?",
        "Solution": "((143 * 175) * (80 / (143 - 175))) = -62562.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 58 % salt solution must be added to 13 ounces of a 141 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 126 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((126 / 100) * 13) - ((141 / 100) * 13)) / ((126 / 100) - (141 / 100))) = 13.000000000000004"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 115 % salt solution must be added to 72 ounces of a 53 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 280 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((280 / 100) * 72) - ((53 / 100) * 72)) / ((280 / 100) - (53 / 100))) = 72.00000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 45 % salt solution must be added to 217 ounces of a 17 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 16 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((16 / 100) * 217) - ((17 / 100) * 217)) / ((16 / 100) - (17 / 100))) = 216.99999999999997"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 48 % salt solution must be added to 112 ounces of a 120 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 259 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((259 / 100) * 112) - ((120 / 100) * 112)) / ((259 / 100) - (120 / 100))) = 111.99999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 14 % salt solution must be added to 288 ounces of a 102 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 280 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((280 / 100) * 288) - ((102 / 100) * 288)) / ((280 / 100) - (102 / 100))) = 288.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 215 % salt solution must be added to 113 ounces of a 230 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 143 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((143 / 100) * 113) - ((230 / 100) * 113)) / ((143 / 100) - (230 / 100))) = 112.99999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 4 % salt solution must be added to 82 ounces of a 217 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 175 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((175 / 100) * 82) - ((217 / 100) * 82)) / ((175 / 100) - (217 / 100))) = 82.00000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 143 % salt solution must be added to 80 ounces of a 111 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 173 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((173 / 100) * 80) - ((111 / 100) * 80)) / ((173 / 100) - (111 / 100))) = 80.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 53 % salt solution must be added to 48 ounces of a 195 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 50 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((50 / 100) * 48) - ((195 / 100) * 48)) / ((50 / 100) - (195 / 100))) = 48.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many ounces of a 184 % salt solution must be added to 177 ounces of a 136 percent salt solution so that the resulting mixture is 23 % salt ?",
        "Solution": "((((23 / 100) * 177) - ((136 / 100) * 177)) / ((23 / 100) - (136 / 100))) = 177.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 58 % of a is the same as 13 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((13 / 100) / (58 / 100)) = 0.2241379310344828"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 141 % of a is the same as 126 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((126 / 100) / (141 / 100)) = 0.8936170212765958"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 115 % of a is the same as 72 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((72 / 100) / (115 / 100)) = 0.6260869565217392"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 53 % of a is the same as 280 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((280 / 100) / (53 / 100)) = 5.283018867924528"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 45 % of a is the same as 217 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((217 / 100) / (45 / 100)) = 4.822222222222222"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 17 % of a is the same as 16 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((16 / 100) / (17 / 100)) = 0.9411764705882353"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 48 % of a is the same as 112 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((112 / 100) / (48 / 100)) = 2.3333333333333335"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 120 % of a is the same as 259 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((259 / 100) / (120 / 100)) = 2.158333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 14 % of a is the same as 288 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((288 / 100) / (14 / 100)) = 20.57142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 102 % of a is the same as 280 % of b , then a : b is :",
        "Solution": "((280 / 100) / (102 / 100)) = 2.745098039215686"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 58 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 13 x boxes in 141 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 58 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 58) / ((58 / 58) + ((13 * 58) / 141))) = 529.9709497206703"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 126 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 115 x boxes in 72 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 126 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * 126) / ((126 / 126) + ((115 * 126) / 72))) = 78.49690976514215"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 53 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 280 x boxes in 45 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 53 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 53) / ((53 / 53) + ((280 * 53) / 45))) = 8.49210614712798"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 217 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 17 x boxes in 16 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 217 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 217) / ((217 / 217) + ((17 * 217) / 16))) = 203.35330634278003"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 48 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 112 x boxes in 120 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 48 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 48) / ((48 / 48) + ((112 * 48) / 120))) = 50.3056768558952"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 259 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 14 x boxes in 288 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 259 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 259) / ((259 / 259) + ((14 * 259) / 288))) = 4935.9550332141025"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 102 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 280 x boxes in 215 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 102 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 102) / ((102 / 102) + ((280 * 102) / 215))) = 77.73622936576889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 113 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 230 x boxes in 143 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 113 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((113 * 113) / ((113 / 113) + ((230 * 113) / 143))) = 69.87207744996746"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 4 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 82 x boxes in 217 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 4 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((4 * 4) / ((4 / 4) + ((82 * 4) / 217))) = 6.370642201834864"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "working alone at its constant rate , machine a produces x boxes in 175 minutes and working alone at its constant rate , machine b produces 143 x boxes in 80 minutes . how many minutes does it take machines a and b , working simultaneously at their respective constant rates , to produce 175 x boxes ?",
        "Solution": "((175 * 175) / ((175 / 175) + ((143 * 175) / 80))) = 97.59012148974308"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 58 , ( 13 y ) / 141 + ( 126 y ) / 115 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((13 / 141) + (126 / 115))) = 118.78507554733271"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 72 , ( 53 y ) / 280 + ( 45 y ) / 217 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((53 / 280) + (45 / 217))) = 39.665898617511516"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 17 , ( 16 y ) / 48 + ( 112 y ) / 120 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((16 / 48) + (112 / 120))) = 126.66666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 259 , ( 14 y ) / 288 + ( 102 y ) / 280 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((14 / 288) + (102 / 280))) = 41.28968253968254"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 215 , ( 113 y ) / 230 + ( 143 y ) / 4 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((113 / 230) + (143 / 4))) = 3624.130434782609"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 82 , ( 217 y ) / 175 + ( 143 y ) / 80 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((217 / 175) + (143 / 80))) = 302.75"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 111 , ( 173 y ) / 53 + ( 48 y ) / 195 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((173 / 53) + (48 / 195))) = 351.03047895500725"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 50 , ( 184 y ) / 177 + ( 136 y ) / 23 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((184 / 177) + (136 / 23))) = 695.2591500859739"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 236 , ( 275 y ) / 64 + ( 194 y ) / 41 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((275 / 64) + (194 / 41))) = 902.8582317073169"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if y > 283 , ( 151 y ) / 186 + ( 296 y ) / 99 is what percent of y ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((151 / 186) + (296 / 99))) = 380.17269468882375"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 58 , 13 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(13 / 58) = 0.22413793103448276"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 141 , 126 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(126 / 141) = 0.8936170212765957"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 115 , 72 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(72 / 115) = 0.6260869565217392"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 53 , 280 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / 53) = 5.283018867924528"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 45 , 217 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / 45) = 4.822222222222222"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 17 , 16 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(16 / 17) = 0.9411764705882353"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 48 , 112 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(112 / 48) = 2.3333333333333335"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 120 , 259 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(259 / 120) = 2.158333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 14 , 288 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(288 / 14) = 20.571428571428573"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many of the positive factors of 102 , 280 and how many common factors are there in numbers ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / 102) = 2.7450980392156863"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 58 was 13 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 141 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 126 was 115 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 58 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 126 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 141 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 13) * ((100 + 115) / 100)) - 100) = 142.95"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 72 was 53 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 280 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 45 was 217 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 72 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 45 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 280 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 53) * ((100 + 217) / 100)) - 100) = 385.01"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 17 was 16 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 48 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 112 was 120 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 17 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 112 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 48 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 16) * ((100 + 120) / 100)) - 100) = 155.20000000000002"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 259 was 14 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 288 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 102 was 280 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 259 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 102 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 288 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 14) * ((100 + 280) / 100)) - 100) = 333.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 215 was 113 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 230 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 143 was 4 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 215 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 143 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 230 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 113) * ((100 + 4) / 100)) - 100) = 121.52000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 82 was 217 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 175 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 143 was 80 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 82 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 143 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 175 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 217) * ((100 + 80) / 100)) - 100) = 470.6"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 111 was 173 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 53 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 48 was 195 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 111 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 48 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 53 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 173) * ((100 + 195) / 100)) - 100) = 705.35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 50 was 184 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 177 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 136 was 23 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 50 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 136 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 177 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 184) * ((100 + 23) / 100)) - 100) = 249.32"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 236 was 275 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 64 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 194 was 41 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 236 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 194 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 64 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 275) * ((100 + 41) / 100)) - 100) = 428.75"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 283 was 151 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 186 , and its enrollment at the beginning of 296 was 99 percent greater than it was at the beginning of 283 . the college ' s enrollment at the beginning of 296 was what percent greater than its enrollment at the beginning of 186 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 + 151) * ((100 + 99) / 100)) - 100) = 399.49"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the 58,13 employees of the anvil factory , 141 / 126 are journeymen . if half of the journeymen were laid off , what percentage of the total remaining employees would be journeymen ?",
        "Solution": "(((((141 / 126) / 141) / (((141 / 126) / 141) + (1 - (141 / 126)))) * 100) * 3) = -21.428571428571423"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the 115,72 employees of the anvil factory , 53 / 280 are journeymen . if half of the journeymen were laid off , what percentage of the total remaining employees would be journeymen ?",
        "Solution": "(((((53 / 280) / 53) / (((53 / 280) / 53) + (1 - (53 / 280)))) * 100) * 3) = 1.3157894736842104"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 58 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 13 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(13 / 1) = 13.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 141 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 126 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(126 / 1) = 126.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 115 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 72 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(72 / 1) = 72.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 53 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 280 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / 1) = 280.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 45 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 217 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / 1) = 217.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 17 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 16 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(16 / 1) = 16.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 48 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 112 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(112 / 1) = 112.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 120 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 259 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(259 / 1) = 259.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 14 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 288 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(288 / 1) = 288.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "an electric pump can fill a tank in 102 hours . because of a leak in the tank , it took 280 hours to fill the tank . if the tank is full , how much time will the leak take to empty it ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / 1) = 280.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 58 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 13 ) = 58 x 141 x 126 x 115 x 72 x 13 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 53 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((53 / 58) - 1) = -0.08620689655172409"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 280 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 45 ) = 280 x 217 x 17 x 16 x 48 x 45 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 112 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((112 / 280) - 1) = -0.6"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 120 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 259 ) = 120 x 14 x 288 x 102 x 280 x 259 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 215 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((215 / 120) - 1) = 0.7916666666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 113 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 230 ) = 113 x 143 x 4 x 82 x 217 x 230 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 175 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((175 / 113) - 1) = 0.5486725663716814"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 143 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 80 ) = 143 x 111 x 173 x 53 x 48 x 80 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 195 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((195 / 143) - 1) = 0.36363636363636354"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 50 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 184 ) = 50 x 177 x 136 x 23 x 236 x 184 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 275 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((275 / 50) - 1) = 4.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 64 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 194 ) = 64 x 41 x 283 x 151 x 186 x 194 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 296 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((296 / 64) - 1) = 3.625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 99 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 36 ) = 99 x 24 x 117 x 149 x 41 x 36 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 120 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((120 / 99) - 1) = 0.21212121212121215"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 52 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 195 ) = 52 x 143 x 233 x 187 x 84 x 195 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 190 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((190 / 52) - 1) = 2.6538461538461537"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for every even positive integer m , f ( m ) represents the product of all even integers from 182 to m , inclusive . for example , f ( 108 ) = 182 x 137 x 37 x 88 x 274 x 108 . what is the greatest prime factor of f ( 126 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((126 / 182) - 1) = -0.3076923076923077"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 58 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 13 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((13 * 58) / (13 - 58)) = -16.755555555555556"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 141 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 126 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * 141) / (126 - 141)) = -1184.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 115 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 72 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((72 * 115) / (72 - 115)) = -192.5581395348837"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 53 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 280 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 53) / (280 - 53)) = 65.37444933920705"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 45 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 217 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 45) / (217 - 45)) = 56.77325581395349"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 17 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 16 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((16 * 17) / (16 - 17)) = -272.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 48 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 112 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((112 * 48) / (112 - 48)) = 84.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 120 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 259 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 120) / (259 - 120)) = 223.59712230215828"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 14 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 288 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((288 * 14) / (288 - 14)) = 14.715328467153284"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "pipe a can fill a tank in 102 hours . due to a leak at the bottom , it takes 280 hours for the pipe a to fill the tank . in what time can the leak alone empty the full tank ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 102) / (280 - 102)) = 160.4494382022472"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 women can do a work in two days . 13 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (58 * 13)) / (1 / (13 * 10))) = 0.17241379310344826"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "141 women can do a work in two days . 126 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (141 * 126)) / (1 / (126 * 10))) = 0.07092198581560283"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 women can do a work in two days . 72 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (115 * 72)) / (1 / (72 * 10))) = 0.08695652173913043"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 women can do a work in two days . 280 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (53 * 280)) / (1 / (280 * 10))) = 0.18867924528301888"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 women can do a work in two days . 217 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (45 * 217)) / (1 / (217 * 10))) = 0.2222222222222222"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "17 women can do a work in two days . 16 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (17 * 16)) / (1 / (16 * 10))) = 0.588235294117647"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 women can do a work in two days . 112 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (48 * 112)) / (1 / (112 * 10))) = 0.20833333333333331"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "120 women can do a work in two days . 259 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (120 * 259)) / (1 / (259 * 10))) = 0.08333333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "14 women can do a work in two days . 288 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (14 * 288)) / (1 / (288 * 10))) = 0.7142857142857142"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "102 women can do a work in two days . 280 men can complete the same work in five days . what is the ratio between the capacity of a man and a woman ?",
        "Solution": "((1 / (102 * 280)) / (1 / (280 * 10))) = 0.09803921568627451"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 58 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (58 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 58) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 58)))) = 3274"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 13 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (13 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 13) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 13)))) = 169"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 141 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (141 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 141) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 141)))) = 19625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 126 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (126 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 126) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 126)))) = 15650"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 115 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (115 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 115) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 115)))) = 13021"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 72 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (72 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 72) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 72)))) = 5066"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 53 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (53 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 53) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 53)))) = 2729"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 280 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (280 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 280) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 280)))) = 77866"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 45 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (45 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 45) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 45)))) = 1961"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the positive difference between the sum of the squares of the first 217 positive integers and the sum of the prime numbers between the first square and fourth square ?",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + (2 ** 2)) + (3 ** 2)) + (4 ** 2)) + ((4 + 1) ** 2)) + (217 ** 2)) - (((4 + 3) + 217) + ((((2 + 3) + (4 + 1)) + (4 + 3)) + ((2 + 3) + 217)))) = 46681"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 58 persons in a office is 13 years . out of these , the average age of 141 of them is 126 years and that of the other 115 persons is 72 years . the age of the 13 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 13) - (141 * 126)) - (115 * 72)) = -25292"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 53 persons in a office is 280 years . out of these , the average age of 45 of them is 217 years and that of the other 17 persons is 16 years . the age of the 280 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 280) - (45 * 217)) - (17 * 16)) = 4803"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 48 persons in a office is 112 years . out of these , the average age of 120 of them is 259 years and that of the other 14 persons is 288 years . the age of the 112 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 112) - (120 * 259)) - (14 * 288)) = -29736"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 102 persons in a office is 280 years . out of these , the average age of 215 of them is 113 years and that of the other 230 persons is 143 years . the age of the 280 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 * 280) - (215 * 113)) - (230 * 143)) = -28625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 4 persons in a office is 82 years . out of these , the average age of 217 of them is 175 years and that of the other 143 persons is 80 years . the age of the 82 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 82) - (217 * 175)) - (143 * 80)) = -49087"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 111 persons in a office is 173 years . out of these , the average age of 53 of them is 48 years and that of the other 195 persons is 50 years . the age of the 173 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((111 * 173) - (53 * 48)) - (195 * 50)) = 6909"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 184 persons in a office is 177 years . out of these , the average age of 136 of them is 23 years and that of the other 236 persons is 275 years . the age of the 177 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((184 * 177) - (136 * 23)) - (236 * 275)) = -35460"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 64 persons in a office is 194 years . out of these , the average age of 41 of them is 283 years and that of the other 151 persons is 186 years . the age of the 194 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((64 * 194) - (41 * 283)) - (151 * 186)) = -27273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 296 persons in a office is 99 years . out of these , the average age of 36 of them is 24 years and that of the other 117 persons is 149 years . the age of the 99 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((296 * 99) - (36 * 24)) - (117 * 149)) = 11007"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average age of 41 persons in a office is 120 years . out of these , the average age of 52 of them is 195 years and that of the other 143 persons is 233 years . the age of the 120 th person is ?",
        "Solution": "(((41 * 120) - (52 * 195)) - (143 * 233)) = -38539"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 58 percent to 13 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 141 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 126 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 141) / 100) * (((100 - 13) / 100) * 126)) = -44.9442"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 115 percent to 72 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 53 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 280 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 53) / 100) * (((100 - 72) / 100) * 280)) = 36.848"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 45 percent to 217 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 17 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 16 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 17) / 100) * (((100 - 217) / 100) * 16)) = -15.537599999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 48 percent to 112 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 120 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 259 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 120) / 100) * (((100 - 112) / 100) * 259)) = 6.216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 14 percent to 288 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 102 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 280 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 102) / 100) * (((100 - 288) / 100) * 280)) = 10.528"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 215 percent to 113 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 230 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 143 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 230) / 100) * (((100 - 113) / 100) * 143)) = 24.167"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 4 percent to 82 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 217 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 175 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 217) / 100) * (((100 - 82) / 100) * 175)) = -36.855"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 143 percent to 80 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 111 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 173 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 111) / 100) * (((100 - 80) / 100) * 173)) = -3.806"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 53 percent to 48 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 195 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 50 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 195) / 100) * (((100 - 48) / 100) * 50)) = -24.7"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a pet store regularly sells pet food at a discount of 184 percent to 177 percent from the manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price . if during a sale , the store discounts an additional 136 percent from the discount price , what would be the lowest possible price of a container of pet food that had a manufacturer \u2019 s suggested retail price o f $ 23 ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - 136) / 100) * (((100 - 177) / 100) * 23)) = 6.3756"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 58 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 13 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((13 - (58 / 3)) - (58 / 3)) = -25.666666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 141 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 126 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((126 - (141 / 3)) - (141 / 3)) = 32.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 115 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 72 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((72 - (115 / 3)) - (115 / 3)) = -4.666666666666671"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 53 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 280 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((280 - (53 / 3)) - (53 / 3)) = 244.66666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 45 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 217 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((217 - (45 / 3)) - (45 / 3)) = 187.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 17 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 16 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((16 - (17 / 3)) - (17 / 3)) = 4.666666666666665"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 48 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 112 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((112 - (48 / 3)) - (48 / 3)) = 80.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 120 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 259 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((259 - (120 / 3)) - (120 / 3)) = 179.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 14 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 288 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((288 - (14 / 3)) - (14 / 3)) = 278.66666666666663"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the perimeter of an equilateral triangle is 102 . if one of the sides of the equilateral triangle is the side of an isosceles triangle of perimeter 280 , then how long is the base of isosceles triangle ?",
        "Solution": "((280 - (102 / 3)) - (102 / 3)) = 212.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 58 % of x equal to 13 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(58 / 13) = 4.461538461538462"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 141 % of x equal to 126 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(141 / 126) = 1.119047619047619"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 115 % of x equal to 72 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(115 / 72) = 1.5972222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 53 % of x equal to 280 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(53 / 280) = 0.18928571428571428"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 45 % of x equal to 217 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(45 / 217) = 0.2073732718894009"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 17 % of x equal to 16 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(17 / 16) = 1.0625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 48 % of x equal to 112 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(48 / 112) = 0.42857142857142855"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 120 % of x equal to 259 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / 259) = 0.46332046332046334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 14 % of x equal to 288 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(14 / 288) = 0.04861111111111111"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "calculate the ratio between x and y if 102 % of x equal to 280 % of y ?",
        "Solution": "(102 / 280) = 0.36428571428571427"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 58 / ? = . 13",
        "Solution": "((58 / 1000) / (13 / 100)) = 0.4461538461538462"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 141 / ? = . 126",
        "Solution": "((141 / 1000) / (126 / 100)) = 0.1119047619047619"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 115 / ? = . 72",
        "Solution": "((115 / 1000) / (72 / 100)) = 0.15972222222222224"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 53 / ? = . 280",
        "Solution": "((53 / 1000) / (280 / 100)) = 0.01892857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 45 / ? = . 217",
        "Solution": "((45 / 1000) / (217 / 100)) = 0.020737327188940093"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 17 / ? = . 16",
        "Solution": "((17 / 1000) / (16 / 100)) = 0.10625000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 48 / ? = . 112",
        "Solution": "((48 / 1000) / (112 / 100)) = 0.04285714285714285"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 120 / ? = . 259",
        "Solution": "((120 / 1000) / (259 / 100)) = 0.04633204633204633"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 14 / ? = . 288",
        "Solution": "((14 / 1000) / (288 / 100)) = 0.004861111111111111"
    },
    {
        "Problem": ". 102 / ? = . 280",
        "Solution": "((102 / 1000) / (280 / 100)) = 0.03642857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 58 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 13 per metre is rs . 141 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((141 / 13) / 2) - (2 * 58)) = -110.57692307692308"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 126 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 115 per metre is rs . 72 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((72 / 115) / 2) - (2 * 126)) = -251.68695652173912"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 53 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 280 per metre is rs . 45 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 / 280) / 2) - (2 * 53)) = -105.91964285714286"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 217 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 17 per metre is rs . 16 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((16 / 17) / 2) - (2 * 217)) = -433.52941176470586"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 48 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 112 per metre is rs . 120 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((120 / 112) / 2) - (2 * 48)) = -95.46428571428571"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 259 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 14 per metre is rs . 288 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((288 / 14) / 2) - (2 * 259)) = -507.7142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 102 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 280 per metre is rs . 215 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((215 / 280) / 2) - (2 * 102)) = -203.61607142857142"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 113 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 230 per metre is rs . 143 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 / 230) / 2) - (2 * 113)) = -225.6891304347826"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 4 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 82 per metre is rs . 217 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 / 82) / 2) - (2 * 4)) = -6.676829268292683"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangular plot is 175 metres more than its breadth . if the cost of fencing the plot @ rs . 143 per metre is rs . 80 , what is the length of the plot in metres ?",
        "Solution": "(((80 / 143) / 2) - (2 * 175)) = -349.72027972027973"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 men can do a work in 13 days . when should 141 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 13 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 13) - (13 * 141)) / 13) = -83.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "126 men can do a work in 115 days . when should 72 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 115 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 * 115) - (115 * 72)) / 115) = 54.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 men can do a work in 280 days . when should 45 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 280 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 280) - (280 * 45)) / 280) = 8.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "217 men can do a work in 17 days . when should 16 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 17 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 17) - (17 * 16)) / 17) = 201.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 men can do a work in 112 days . when should 120 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 112 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 112) - (112 * 120)) / 112) = -72.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "259 men can do a work in 14 days . when should 288 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 14 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((259 * 14) - (14 * 288)) / 14) = -29.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "102 men can do a work in 280 days . when should 215 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 280 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 * 280) - (280 * 215)) / 280) = -113.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "113 men can do a work in 230 days . when should 143 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 230 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((113 * 230) - (230 * 143)) / 230) = -30.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "4 men can do a work in 82 days . when should 217 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 82 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 82) - (82 * 217)) / 82) = -213.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "175 men can do a work in 143 days . when should 80 men leave the work so that the entire work is completed in 143 days after they leave the work ?",
        "Solution": "(((175 * 143) - (143 * 80)) / 143) = 95.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 58 in buying raw materials , $ 13 in buying machinery and 141 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((58 + 13) / (1 - (141 / 100))) = -173.17073170731712"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 126 in buying raw materials , $ 115 in buying machinery and 72 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((126 + 115) / (1 - (72 / 100))) = 860.7142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 53 in buying raw materials , $ 280 in buying machinery and 45 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((53 + 280) / (1 - (45 / 100))) = 605.4545454545454"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 217 in buying raw materials , $ 17 in buying machinery and 16 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((217 + 17) / (1 - (16 / 100))) = 278.57142857142856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 48 in buying raw materials , $ 112 in buying machinery and 120 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((48 + 112) / (1 - (120 / 100))) = -800.0000000000002"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 259 in buying raw materials , $ 14 in buying machinery and 288 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((259 + 14) / (1 - (288 / 100))) = -145.2127659574468"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 102 in buying raw materials , $ 280 in buying machinery and 215 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((102 + 280) / (1 - (215 / 100))) = -332.1739130434783"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 113 in buying raw materials , $ 230 in buying machinery and 143 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((113 + 230) / (1 - (143 / 100))) = -797.6744186046512"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 4 in buying raw materials , $ 82 in buying machinery and 217 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((4 + 82) / (1 - (217 / 100))) = -73.50427350427351"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "kanul spent $ 175 in buying raw materials , $ 143 in buying machinery and 80 % of the total amount he had as cash with him . what was the total amount ?",
        "Solution": "((175 + 143) / (1 - (80 / 100))) = 1590.0000000000005"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 58 frisbees in one week , some for $ 13 and the rest for $ 141 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 126 , what is the fewest number of $ 13 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(126 - (58 * 13)) = -628"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 115 frisbees in one week , some for $ 72 and the rest for $ 53 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 280 , what is the fewest number of $ 72 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(280 - (115 * 72)) = -8000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 45 frisbees in one week , some for $ 217 and the rest for $ 17 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 16 , what is the fewest number of $ 217 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(16 - (45 * 217)) = -9749"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 48 frisbees in one week , some for $ 112 and the rest for $ 120 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 259 , what is the fewest number of $ 112 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(259 - (48 * 112)) = -5117"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 14 frisbees in one week , some for $ 288 and the rest for $ 102 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 280 , what is the fewest number of $ 288 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(280 - (14 * 288)) = -3752"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 215 frisbees in one week , some for $ 113 and the rest for $ 230 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 143 , what is the fewest number of $ 113 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(143 - (215 * 113)) = -24152"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 4 frisbees in one week , some for $ 82 and the rest for $ 217 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 175 , what is the fewest number of $ 82 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(175 - (4 * 82)) = -153"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 143 frisbees in one week , some for $ 80 and the rest for $ 111 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 173 , what is the fewest number of $ 80 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(173 - (143 * 80)) = -11267"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 53 frisbees in one week , some for $ 48 and the rest for $ 195 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 50 , what is the fewest number of $ 48 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(50 - (53 * 48)) = -2494"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sporting goods store sold 184 frisbees in one week , some for $ 177 and the rest for $ 136 each . if receipts from frisbee sales for the week totaled $ 23 , what is the fewest number of $ 177 frisbees that could have been sold ?",
        "Solution": "(23 - (184 * 177)) = -32545"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 58 / 13 s are there in 141 58 / 126 ?",
        "Solution": "((141 + (58 / 126)) / (58 / 13)) = 31.706622879036672"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 115 / 72 s are there in 53 115 / 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((53 + (115 / 280)) / (115 / 72)) = 33.43975155279503"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 45 / 217 s are there in 17 45 / 16 ?",
        "Solution": "((17 + (45 / 16)) / (45 / 217)) = 95.54027777777779"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 48 / 112 s are there in 120 48 / 259 ?",
        "Solution": "((120 + (48 / 259)) / (48 / 112)) = 280.43243243243245"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 14 / 288 s are there in 102 14 / 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((102 + (14 / 280)) / (14 / 288)) = 2099.3142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 215 / 113 s are there in 230 215 / 143 ?",
        "Solution": "((230 + (215 / 143)) / (215 / 113)) = 121.67393072044234"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 4 / 82 s are there in 217 4 / 175 ?",
        "Solution": "((217 + (4 / 175)) / (4 / 82)) = 4448.9685714285715"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 143 / 80 s are there in 111 143 / 173 ?",
        "Solution": "((111 + (143 / 173)) / (143 / 80)) = 62.560329843566834"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 53 / 48 s are there in 195 53 / 50 ?",
        "Solution": "((195 + (53 / 50)) / (53 / 48)) = 177.56377358490565"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many 184 / 177 s are there in 136 184 / 23 ?",
        "Solution": "((136 + (184 / 23)) / (184 / 177)) = 138.52173913043478"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 58 % microphotonics ; 13 % home electronics ; 141 % food additives ; 126 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 115 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((58 + 13) + 141) + 126) + 115)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -1270.8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 72 % microphotonics ; 53 % home electronics ; 280 % food additives ; 45 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 217 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((72 + 53) + 280) + 45) + 217)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -2041.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 17 % microphotonics ; 16 % home electronics ; 48 % food additives ; 112 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 120 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((17 + 16) + 48) + 112) + 120)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -766.8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 259 % microphotonics ; 14 % home electronics ; 288 % food additives ; 102 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 280 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((259 + 14) + 288) + 102) + 280)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -3034.8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 215 % microphotonics ; 113 % home electronics ; 230 % food additives ; 143 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 4 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((215 + 113) + 230) + 143) + 4)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -2178.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 82 % microphotonics ; 217 % home electronics ; 175 % food additives ; 143 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 80 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((82 + 217) + 175) + 143) + 80)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -2149.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 111 % microphotonics ; 173 % home electronics ; 53 % food additives ; 48 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 195 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((111 + 173) + 53) + 48) + 195)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -1728.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 50 % microphotonics ; 184 % home electronics ; 177 % food additives ; 136 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 23 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((50 + 184) + 177) + 136) + 23)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -1692.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 236 % microphotonics ; 275 % home electronics ; 64 % food additives ; 194 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 41 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((236 + 275) + 64) + 194) + 41)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -2556.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a circle graph shows how the megatech corporation allocates its research and development budget : 283 % microphotonics ; 151 % home electronics ; 186 % food additives ; 296 % genetically modified microorganisms ; 99 % industrial lubricants ; and the remainder for basic astrophysics . if the arc of each sector of the graph is proportional to the percentage of the budget it represents , how many degrees of the circle are used to represent basic astrophysics research ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 - ((((283 + 151) + 186) + 296) + 99)) * (3600 / 10)) / 100) = -3294.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 58,13 earn in 141 months at an annual rate of 126 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (126 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 9450.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 115,72 earn in 53 months at an annual rate of 280 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (280 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 21000.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 45,217 earn in 17 months at an annual rate of 16 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (16 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 1200.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 48,112 earn in 120 months at an annual rate of 259 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (259 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 19425.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 14,288 earn in 102 months at an annual rate of 280 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (280 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 21000.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 215,113 earn in 230 months at an annual rate of 143 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (143 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 10725.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 4,82 earn in 217 months at an annual rate of 175 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (175 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 13125.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 143,80 earn in 111 months at an annual rate of 173 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (173 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 12975.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 53,48 earn in 195 months at an annual rate of 50 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (50 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 3750.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how much interest will $ 184,177 earn in 136 months at an annual rate of 23 % ?",
        "Solution": "(((100 ** 2) * (23 / 100)) * (3 / 4)) = 1725.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 58 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(58 + 58) = 116"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 13 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(13 + 13) = 26"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 141 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(141 + 141) = 282"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 126 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(126 + 126) = 252"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 115 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(115 + 115) = 230"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 72 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(72 + 72) = 144"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 53 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(53 + 53) = 106"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 280 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(280 + 280) = 560"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 45 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(45 + 45) = 90"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many different values of positive integer x , for which | x + 217 | < x , are there ?",
        "Solution": "(217 + 217) = 434"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 58 consecutive integers is 13 then the 58 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((58 * 2) + ((13 - (58 * 2)) * 58)) = -5858"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 141 consecutive integers is 126 then the 141 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((141 * 2) + ((126 - (141 * 2)) * 141)) = -21714"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 115 consecutive integers is 72 then the 115 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((115 * 2) + ((72 - (115 * 2)) * 115)) = -17940"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 53 consecutive integers is 280 then the 53 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((53 * 2) + ((280 - (53 * 2)) * 53)) = 9328"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 45 consecutive integers is 217 then the 45 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((45 * 2) + ((217 - (45 * 2)) * 45)) = 5805"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 17 consecutive integers is 16 then the 17 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((17 * 2) + ((16 - (17 * 2)) * 17)) = -272"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 48 consecutive integers is 112 then the 48 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((48 * 2) + ((112 - (48 * 2)) * 48)) = 864"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 120 consecutive integers is 259 then the 120 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((120 * 2) + ((259 - (120 * 2)) * 120)) = 2520"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 14 consecutive integers is 288 then the 14 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((14 * 2) + ((288 - (14 * 2)) * 14)) = 3668"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average of 102 consecutive integers is 280 then the 102 th integer is : -",
        "Solution": "((102 * 2) + ((280 - (102 * 2)) * 102)) = 7956"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 58 pens , a total of 13 are defective . if a customer buys 141 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 - 13) / 58) * (((58 - 13) - 1) / (58 - 1))) = 0.5989110707803993"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 126 pens , a total of 115 are defective . if a customer buys 72 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 - 115) / 126) * (((126 - 115) - 1) / (126 - 1))) = 0.006984126984126984"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 53 pens , a total of 280 are defective . if a customer buys 45 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 - 280) / 53) * (((53 - 280) - 1) / (53 - 1))) = 18.779390420899855"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 217 pens , a total of 17 are defective . if a customer buys 16 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 - 17) / 217) * (((217 - 17) - 1) / (217 - 1))) = 0.849121010411333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 48 pens , a total of 112 are defective . if a customer buys 120 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 - 112) / 48) * (((48 - 112) - 1) / (48 - 1))) = 1.8439716312056738"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 259 pens , a total of 14 are defective . if a customer buys 288 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((259 - 14) / 259) * (((259 - 14) - 1) / (259 - 1))) = 0.8946155457783365"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 102 pens , a total of 280 are defective . if a customer buys 215 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 - 280) / 102) * (((102 - 280) - 1) / (102 - 1))) = 3.092797515045622"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 113 pens , a total of 230 are defective . if a customer buys 143 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((113 - 230) / 113) * (((113 - 230) - 1) / (113 - 1))) = 1.090865992414665"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 4 pens , a total of 82 are defective . if a customer buys 217 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 - 82) / 4) * (((4 - 82) - 1) / (4 - 1))) = 513.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a box of 175 pens , a total of 143 are defective . if a customer buys 80 pens selected at random from the box , what is the probability that neither pen will be defective ?",
        "Solution": "(((175 - 143) / 175) * (((175 - 143) - 1) / (175 - 1))) = 0.03257799671592775"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 58 percent of 13 ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 7166.48"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 141 percent of 126 ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 17421.96"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 115 percent of 72 ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 14209.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 53 percent of 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 6548.68"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 45 percent of 217 ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 5560.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 17 percent of 16 ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 2100.52"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 48 percent of 112 ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 5930.88"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 120 percent of 259 ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 14827.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 14 percent of 288 ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 1729.84"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is 102 percent of 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * (((((3 + 2) * 2) * ((3 * 4) * 100)) + (((3 + 4) * (3 + 2)) * ((3 + 2) * 2))) + (3 + 3))) / 100) = 12603.12"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 58 - ounce cans or 13 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 141 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(13 + 141) = 154"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 126 - ounce cans or 115 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 72 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(115 + 72) = 187"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 53 - ounce cans or 280 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 45 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(280 + 45) = 325"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 217 - ounce cans or 17 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 16 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(17 + 16) = 33"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 48 - ounce cans or 112 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 120 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(112 + 120) = 232"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 259 - ounce cans or 14 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 288 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(14 + 288) = 302"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 102 - ounce cans or 280 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 215 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(280 + 215) = 495"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 113 - ounce cans or 230 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 143 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(230 + 143) = 373"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 4 - ounce cans or 82 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 217 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(82 + 217) = 299"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "each week a restaurant serving mexican food uses the same volume of chili paste , which comes in either 175 - ounce cans or 143 - ounce cans of chili paste . if the restaurant must order 80 more of the smaller cans than the larger cans to fulfill its weekly needs , then how many larger cans are required to fulfill its weekly needs ?",
        "Solution": "(143 + 80) = 223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 58 ) / 13 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 141 and 126 ?",
        "Solution": "((((126 - 58) - (141 + 58)) / 13) + 58) = 47.92307692307692"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 115 ) / 72 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 53 and 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((((280 - 115) - (53 + 115)) / 72) + 115) = 114.95833333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 45 ) / 217 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 17 and 16 ?",
        "Solution": "((((16 - 45) - (17 + 45)) / 217) + 45) = 44.58064516129032"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 48 ) / 112 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 120 and 259 ?",
        "Solution": "((((259 - 48) - (120 + 48)) / 112) + 48) = 48.38392857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 14 ) / 288 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 102 and 280 ?",
        "Solution": "((((280 - 14) - (102 + 14)) / 288) + 14) = 14.520833333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 215 ) / 113 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 230 and 143 ?",
        "Solution": "((((143 - 215) - (230 + 215)) / 113) + 215) = 210.42477876106196"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 4 ) / 82 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 217 and 175 ?",
        "Solution": "((((175 - 4) - (217 + 4)) / 82) + 4) = 3.3902439024390243"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 143 ) / 80 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 111 and 173 ?",
        "Solution": "((((173 - 143) - (111 + 143)) / 80) + 143) = 140.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 53 ) / 48 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 195 and 50 ?",
        "Solution": "((((50 - 53) - (195 + 53)) / 48) + 53) = 47.770833333333336"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for any positive integer n , the sum of the first n positive integers equals n ( n + 184 ) / 177 . what is the sum of all the even integers between 136 and 23 ?",
        "Solution": "((((23 - 184) - (136 + 184)) / 177) + 184) = 181.28248587570621"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 58 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 13 plus 2.58 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 141,126 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 115 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 4) - 12) = 220"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 72 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 53 plus 2.72 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 280,45 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 217 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((72 * 4) - 12) = 276"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 17 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 16 plus 2.17 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 48,112 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 120 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 4) - 12) = 56"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 259 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 14 plus 2.259 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 288,102 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 280 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 4) - 12) = 1024"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 215 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 113 plus 2.215 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 230,143 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 4 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((215 * 4) - 12) = 848"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 82 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 217 plus 2.82 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 175,143 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 80 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((82 * 4) - 12) = 316"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 111 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 173 plus 2.111 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 53,48 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 195 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((111 * 4) - 12) = 432"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 50 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 184 plus 2.50 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 177,136 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 23 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((50 * 4) - 12) = 188"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 236 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 275 plus 2.236 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 64,194 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 41 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((236 * 4) - 12) = 932"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u00e2 \u20ac \u2122 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 283 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 151 plus 2.283 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 186,296 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 99 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "((283 * 4) - 12) = 1120"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 58 ^ a ) ^ b = 58 ^ 58 , what is the value of 58 ^ a * 58 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((58 ** 58) * 58) = 110217770094612479826305268801844904428138460567098846359509964014848097461681304933015363454019223683072"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 13 ^ a ) ^ b = 13 ^ 13 , what is the value of 13 ^ a * 13 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((13 ** 13) * 13) = 3937376385699289"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 141 ^ a ) ^ b = 141 ^ 141 , what is the value of 141 ^ a * 141 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((141 ** 141) * 141) = 154566010343176967146204482259372119468752833029758730788933216615396868451163391984498479749352754060854724900805719745039708918975544974426030667188987743046450326722551365557238458088077625073024155458332849561115000969870186546315982719585484395720715090492546011854131592053161034909930870097086155481"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 126 ^ a ) ^ b = 126 ^ 126 , what is the value of 126 ^ a * 126 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((126 ** 126) * 126) = 558546365187818550798854439603421267087331756479176090810615420441419483155403107893523188196665799014370735876545473933315267782997493302295051101340797974842077963491344964635983580950647511815245487938253068242462864266014918031046858310519339340728057047732453376"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 115 ^ a ) ^ b = 115 ^ 115 , what is the value of 115 ^ a * 115 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((115 ** 115) * 115) = 109887800583479063591213318704998979357164177578136433908336639242037075548929378538972053451981659172470298881717818495782718278188670086976005141030419749129076117216121115052691174196846161148000999008278455448817112483084201812744140625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 72 ^ a ) ^ b = 72 ^ 72 , what is the value of 72 ^ a * 72 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((72 ** 72) * 72) = 3848329407410063966449821610084142775235723300303676033059406926388218957230170383178174198012821574964995892819168434088598247206551552"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 53 ^ a ) ^ b = 53 ^ 53 , what is the value of 53 ^ a * 53 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((53 ** 53) * 53) = 1290912952746203743021313145565550452482273015820338964758771936617566192284961834966575969769"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 280 ^ a ) ^ b = 280 ^ 280 , what is the value of 280 ^ a * 280 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((280 ** 280) * 280) = 4481328773377350747722577496058768361291028529294740494567783427152055393551606122206399348650792650858081763505784178416549166245573584287638895223571200612777247821033293756495169644739939043458465074456420246864152819862092724577869986943641705882984003582774269996312903912352654801931491187352093588211777124598702787106017605742126401644354962926445830313810575295686887522880810150120777006105545932800000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 45 ^ a ) ^ b = 45 ^ 45 , what is the value of 45 ^ a * 45 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((45 ** 45) * 45) = 11162864000310351547259213207793571038503876167169437394477427005767822265625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a and b are positive integers and ( 217 ^ a ) ^ b = 217 ^ 217 , what is the value of 217 ^ a * 217 ^ b ?",
        "Solution": "((217 ** 217) * 217) = 222957445041380523572804770602886341231139487245970363639999805955172549222443381877582663863713964776724626704297100927555921696309630753393604803789452897106192218030595935131440084285705301525889058142126034722614053331605236631854279773770330574921165679699535351976530415167266037136932844352895155280820471028492967302272543999995622778562851485909980793324946125589818192647329289447244308932516000245641117250874850055854940023112729817112862636059437292733191808583659679519883780472669807724214972209"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 58 of 13 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 141 of 126 candidates eligible to fill 141 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 115 candidates are there to fill the 115 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * 115) * 13) = 188370"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 72 of 53 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 280 of 45 candidates eligible to fill 280 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 217 candidates are there to fill the 217 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * 217) * 53) = 517545"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 17 of 16 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 48 of 112 candidates eligible to fill 48 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 120 candidates are there to fill the 120 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((112 * 120) * 16) = 215040"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 259 of 14 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 288 of 102 candidates eligible to fill 288 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 280 candidates are there to fill the 280 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 280) * 14) = 399840"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 215 of 113 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 230 of 143 candidates eligible to fill 230 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 4 candidates are there to fill the 4 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((143 * 4) * 113) = 64636"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 82 of 217 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 175 of 143 candidates eligible to fill 175 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 80 candidates are there to fill the 80 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((143 * 80) * 217) = 2482480"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 111 of 173 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 53 of 48 candidates eligible to fill 53 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 195 candidates are there to fill the 195 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 195) * 173) = 1619280"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 50 of 184 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 177 of 136 candidates eligible to fill 177 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 23 candidates are there to fill the 23 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((136 * 23) * 184) = 575552"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 236 of 275 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 64 of 194 candidates eligible to fill 64 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 41 candidates are there to fill the 41 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((194 * 41) * 275) = 2187350"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain university will select 283 of 151 candidates eligible to fill a position in the mathematics department and 186 of 296 candidates eligible to fill 186 identical positions in the computer science department . if none of the candidates is eligible for a position in both departments , how many different sets of 99 candidates are there to fill the 99 positions ?",
        "Solution": "((296 * 99) * 151) = 4424904"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 58 , 13 , 141 and 126",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 115 , 72 , 53 and 280",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 45 , 217 , 17 and 16",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 48 , 112 , 120 and 259",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 14 , 288 , 102 and 280",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 215 , 113 , 230 and 143",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 4 , 82 , 217 and 175",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 143 , 80 , 111 and 173",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 53 , 48 , 195 and 50",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what will be the lcm of 184 , 177 , 136 and 23",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 2) * 2) * 3) * 3) * 3) = 216"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 58 from its 13 / 141 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 141) / (141 - 13)) = 63.890625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 126 from its 115 / 72 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * 72) / (72 - 115)) = -210.97674418604652"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 53 from its 280 / 45 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 45) / (45 - 280)) = -10.148936170212766"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 217 from its 17 / 16 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 16) / (16 - 17)) = -3472.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 48 from its 112 / 120 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 120) / (120 - 112)) = 720.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 259 from its 14 / 288 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 288) / (288 - 14)) = 272.2335766423358"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 102 from its 280 / 215 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 215) / (215 - 280)) = -337.38461538461536"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 113 from its 230 / 143 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((113 * 143) / (143 - 230)) = -185.73563218390805"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 4 from its 82 / 217 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((4 * 217) / (217 - 82)) = 6.42962962962963"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a number exceeds by 175 from its 143 / 80 part . then the number is ?",
        "Solution": "((175 * 80) / (80 - 143)) = -222.22222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 58 : x : : 13 : 141 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((58 * 141) / 13) = 629.0769230769231"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 126 : x : : 115 : 72 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((126 * 72) / 115) = 78.88695652173914"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 53 : x : : 280 : 45 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((53 * 45) / 280) = 8.517857142857142"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 217 : x : : 17 : 16 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((217 * 16) / 17) = 204.23529411764707"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 48 : x : : 112 : 120 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((48 * 120) / 112) = 51.42857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 259 : x : : 14 : 288 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((259 * 288) / 14) = 5328.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 102 : x : : 280 : 215 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((102 * 215) / 280) = 78.32142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 113 : x : : 230 : 143 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((113 * 143) / 230) = 70.25652173913043"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 4 : x : : 82 : 217 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((4 * 217) / 82) = 10.585365853658537"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 175 : x : : 143 : 80 , then x is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((175 * 80) / 143) = 97.9020979020979"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 58 sec and 13 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 141 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * 2) / ((141 / 13) + (141 / 58))) = 21.239436619718308"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 126 sec and 115 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 72 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((72 * 2) / ((72 / 115) + (72 / 126))) = 120.24896265560164"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 53 sec and 280 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 45 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * 2) / ((45 / 280) + (45 / 53))) = 89.12912912912911"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 217 sec and 17 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 16 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((16 * 2) / ((16 / 17) + (16 / 217))) = 31.52991452991453"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 48 sec and 112 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 120 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * 2) / ((120 / 112) + (120 / 48))) = 67.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 259 sec and 14 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 288 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((288 * 2) / ((288 / 14) + (288 / 259))) = 26.564102564102562"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 102 sec and 280 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 215 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((215 * 2) / ((215 / 280) + (215 / 102))) = 149.52879581151834"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 113 sec and 230 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 143 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((143 * 2) / ((143 / 230) + (143 / 113))) = 151.54518950437318"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 4 sec and 82 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 217 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 2) / ((217 / 82) + (217 / 4))) = 7.627906976744185"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains of equal lengths take 175 sec and 143 sec respectively to cross a telegraph post . if the length of each train be 80 m , in what time will they cross other travelling in opposite direction ?",
        "Solution": "((80 * 2) / ((80 / 143) + (80 / 175))) = 157.38993710691824"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 58 and an x - intercept of 58 . line b has a slope of 13 and a y - intercept of - 13 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((13 - 13) - 58) / 58) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 141 and an x - intercept of 141 . line b has a slope of 126 and a y - intercept of - 126 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 - 126) - 141) / 141) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 115 and an x - intercept of 115 . line b has a slope of 72 and a y - intercept of - 72 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((72 - 72) - 115) / 115) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 53 and an x - intercept of 53 . line b has a slope of 280 and a y - intercept of - 280 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 - 280) - 53) / 53) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 45 and an x - intercept of 45 . line b has a slope of 217 and a y - intercept of - 217 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 - 217) - 45) / 45) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 17 and an x - intercept of 17 . line b has a slope of 16 and a y - intercept of - 16 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((16 - 16) - 17) / 17) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 48 and an x - intercept of 48 . line b has a slope of 112 and a y - intercept of - 112 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((112 - 112) - 48) / 48) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 120 and an x - intercept of 120 . line b has a slope of 259 and a y - intercept of - 259 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((259 - 259) - 120) / 120) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 14 and an x - intercept of 14 . line b has a slope of 288 and a y - intercept of - 288 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((288 - 288) - 14) / 14) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in the coordinate plane , line a has a slope of - 102 and an x - intercept of 102 . line b has a slope of 280 and a y - intercept of - 280 . if the two lines intersect at the point ( a , b ) , what is the sum a + b ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 - 280) - 102) / 102) = -1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 58 % and the present number of people is 13 , what will the population be in 141 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 + 100) / 100) * 13) * ((58 + 100) / 100)) = 32.4532"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 126 % and the present number of people is 115 , what will the population be in 72 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((126 + 100) / 100) * 115) * ((126 + 100) / 100)) = 587.3739999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 53 % and the present number of people is 280 , what will the population be in 45 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 + 100) / 100) * 280) * ((53 + 100) / 100)) = 655.4520000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 217 % and the present number of people is 17 , what will the population be in 16 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((217 + 100) / 100) * 17) * ((217 + 100) / 100)) = 170.8313"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 48 % and the present number of people is 112 , what will the population be in 120 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((48 + 100) / 100) * 112) * ((48 + 100) / 100)) = 245.32479999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 259 % and the present number of people is 14 , what will the population be in 288 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((259 + 100) / 100) * 14) * ((259 + 100) / 100)) = 180.43339999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 102 % and the present number of people is 280 , what will the population be in 215 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((102 + 100) / 100) * 280) * ((102 + 100) / 100)) = 1142.512"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 113 % and the present number of people is 230 , what will the population be in 143 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((113 + 100) / 100) * 230) * ((113 + 100) / 100)) = 1043.4869999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 4 % and the present number of people is 82 , what will the population be in 217 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((4 + 100) / 100) * 82) * ((4 + 100) / 100)) = 88.69120000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the annual increase in the population of a town is 175 % and the present number of people is 143 , what will the population be in 80 years ?",
        "Solution": "((((175 + 100) / 100) * 143) * ((175 + 100) / 100)) = 1081.4375"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 58 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((58 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((58 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((58 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((58 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 861.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 13 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((13 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((13 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((13 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((13 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 62.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 141 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((141 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((141 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((141 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((141 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 4990.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 126 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((126 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((126 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((126 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((126 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 3989.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 115 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((115 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((115 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((115 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((115 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 3326.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 72 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((72 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((72 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((72 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((72 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 1316.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 53 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((53 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((53 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((53 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((53 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 722.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 280 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((280 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((280 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((280 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((280 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 19620.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 45 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((45 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((45 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((45 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((45 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 526.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of two consecutive integers is 217 . find the numbers .",
        "Solution": "((((((((217 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) ** 2) + (((((((217 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) + 2) + 2) ** 2)) + (((((217 - 10) - 2) / 4) ** 2) + (((((217 - 10) - 2) / 4) + 2) ** 2))) = 11792.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 58 was 13 percent greater than its profit in 141 , and its profit in 126 was 115 percent greater than its profit in 58 . the company \u2019 s profit in 126 was what percent greater than its profit in 141 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((115 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (13 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 142.94999999999996"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 72 was 53 percent greater than its profit in 280 , and its profit in 45 was 217 percent greater than its profit in 72 . the company \u2019 s profit in 45 was what percent greater than its profit in 280 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((217 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (53 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 385.01000000000005"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 17 was 16 percent greater than its profit in 48 , and its profit in 112 was 120 percent greater than its profit in 17 . the company \u2019 s profit in 112 was what percent greater than its profit in 48 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((120 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (16 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 155.20000000000002"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 259 was 14 percent greater than its profit in 288 , and its profit in 102 was 280 percent greater than its profit in 259 . the company \u2019 s profit in 102 was what percent greater than its profit in 288 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((280 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (14 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 333.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 215 was 113 percent greater than its profit in 230 , and its profit in 143 was 4 percent greater than its profit in 215 . the company \u2019 s profit in 143 was what percent greater than its profit in 230 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (113 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 121.51999999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 82 was 217 percent greater than its profit in 175 , and its profit in 143 was 80 percent greater than its profit in 82 . the company \u2019 s profit in 143 was what percent greater than its profit in 175 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((80 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (217 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 470.6"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 111 was 173 percent greater than its profit in 53 , and its profit in 48 was 195 percent greater than its profit in 111 . the company \u2019 s profit in 48 was what percent greater than its profit in 53 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((195 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (173 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 705.3499999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 50 was 184 percent greater than its profit in 177 , and its profit in 136 was 23 percent greater than its profit in 50 . the company \u2019 s profit in 136 was what percent greater than its profit in 177 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((23 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (184 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 249.32"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 236 was 275 percent greater than its profit in 64 , and its profit in 194 was 41 percent greater than its profit in 236 . the company \u2019 s profit in 194 was what percent greater than its profit in 64 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((41 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (275 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 428.74999999999994"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain company \u2019 s profit in 283 was 151 percent greater than its profit in 186 , and its profit in 296 was 99 percent greater than its profit in 283 . the company \u2019 s profit in 296 was what percent greater than its profit in 186 ?",
        "Solution": "(((((99 / 100) + 1) * (1 + (151 / 100))) - 1) * 100) = 399.48999999999995"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 58 , rs . 13 , rs . 141 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 126 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 / 141) * 126) + ((13 / 141) * 126)) + 126) = 189.44680851063828"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 115 , rs . 72 , rs . 53 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 280 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((115 / 53) * 280) + ((72 / 53) * 280)) + 280) = 1267.9245283018868"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 45 , rs . 217 , rs . 17 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 16 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((45 / 17) * 16) + ((217 / 17) * 16)) + 16) = 262.5882352941177"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 48 , rs . 112 , rs . 120 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 259 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((48 / 120) * 259) + ((112 / 120) * 259)) + 259) = 604.3333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 14 , rs . 288 , rs . 102 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 280 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((14 / 102) * 280) + ((288 / 102) * 280)) + 280) = 1109.0196078431372"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 215 , rs . 113 , rs . 230 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 143 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((215 / 230) * 143) + ((113 / 230) * 143)) + 143) = 346.9304347826087"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 4 , rs . 82 , rs . 217 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 175 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((4 / 217) * 175) + ((82 / 217) * 175)) + 175) = 244.3548387096774"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 143 , rs . 80 , rs . 111 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 173 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((143 / 111) * 173) + ((80 / 111) * 173)) + 173) = 520.5585585585586"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 53 , rs . 48 , rs . 195 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 50 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 / 195) * 50) + ((48 / 195) * 50)) + 50) = 75.8974358974359"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b and c started a partnership business by investing rs . 184 , rs . 177 , rs . 136 respectively . at the end of the year , the profit were distributed among them . if c ' s share of profit is 23 , what is the total profit ?",
        "Solution": "((((184 / 136) * 23) + ((177 / 136) * 23)) + 23) = 84.0514705882353"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 58 seconds and 13 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 141 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((58 - 141) / (141 - 13)) = -0.6484375"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 126 seconds and 115 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 72 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((126 - 72) / (72 - 115)) = -1.255813953488372"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 53 seconds and 280 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 45 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((53 - 45) / (45 - 280)) = -0.03404255319148936"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 217 seconds and 17 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 16 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((217 - 16) / (16 - 17)) = -201.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 48 seconds and 112 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 120 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((48 - 120) / (120 - 112)) = -9.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 259 seconds and 14 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 288 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((259 - 288) / (288 - 14)) = -0.10583941605839416"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 102 seconds and 280 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 215 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((102 - 215) / (215 - 280)) = 1.7384615384615385"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 113 seconds and 230 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 143 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((113 - 143) / (143 - 230)) = 0.3448275862068966"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 4 seconds and 82 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 217 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((4 - 217) / (217 - 82)) = -1.5777777777777777"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two trains running in opposite directions cross a man standing on the platform in 175 seconds and 143 seconds respectively . if they cross each other in 80 seconds , what is the ratio of their speeds ?",
        "Solution": "((175 - 80) / (80 - 143)) = -1.507936507936508"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 58 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 13 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 141 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 126 cups and 115 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 72 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((126 * (141 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 58) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 115) * 126) + ((((100 + 13) / 100) * 115) * 126))) * ((100 + 13) / 100)) = 0.6594452396857208"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 53 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 280 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 45 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 217 cups and 17 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 16 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((217 * (45 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 53) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 17) * 217) + ((((100 + 280) / 100) * 17) * 217))) * ((100 + 280) / 100)) = 0.312988031233999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 48 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 112 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 120 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 259 cups and 14 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 288 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((259 * (120 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 48) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 14) * 259) + ((((100 + 112) / 100) * 14) * 259))) * ((100 + 112) / 100)) = 1.0059538844585574"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 102 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 280 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 215 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 113 cups and 230 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 143 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((113 * (215 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 102) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 230) * 113) + ((((100 + 280) / 100) * 230) * 113))) * ((100 + 280) / 100)) = 0.13016833103298964"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 4 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 82 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 217 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 175 cups and 143 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 80 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((175 * (217 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 4) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 143) * 175) + ((((100 + 82) / 100) * 143) * 175))) * ((100 + 82) / 100)) = 0.31066792393525067"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 111 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 173 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 53 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 48 cups and 195 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 50 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((48 * (53 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 111) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 195) * 48) + ((((100 + 173) / 100) * 195) * 48))) * ((100 + 173) / 100)) = 0.05983050237512594"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 184 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 177 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 136 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 23 cups and 236 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 275 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((23 * (136 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 184) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 236) * 23) + ((((100 + 177) / 100) * 236) * 23))) * ((100 + 177) / 100)) = 0.13988590666791356"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 64 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 194 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 41 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 283 cups and 151 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 186 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((283 * (41 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 64) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 151) * 283) + ((((100 + 194) / 100) * 151) * 283))) * ((100 + 194) / 100)) = 0.04198480334418808"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 296 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 99 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 36 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 24 cups and 117 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 149 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((24 * (36 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 296) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 117) * 24) + ((((100 + 99) / 100) * 117) * 24))) * ((100 + 99) / 100)) = 0.25198548305915386"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sarah operated her lemonade stand monday through friday over a two week period and made a total profit of 41 dollars . on hot days she sold cups of lemonade for a price that was 120 percent higher than the regular days . each cup she sold had a total cost of 52 cents and sarah did not incur any other costs . if every day she sold exactly 195 cups and 143 of the days were hot , then what was the price of 233 cup on a hot day ?",
        "Solution": "(((((195 * (52 / 100)) * ((4 + 1) * 2)) + 41) / (((((4 + 1) * 2) - 143) * 195) + ((((100 + 120) / 100) * 143) * 195))) * ((100 + 120) / 100)) = 0.06554275386874506"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 58 cups of bird seed are used every 13 days to feed 141 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 126 parakeets for 115 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 * 58) * 115) / (13 * 141)) = 458.494271685761"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 72 cups of bird seed are used every 53 days to feed 280 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 45 parakeets for 217 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 72) * 217) / (53 * 280)) = 47.37735849056604"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 17 cups of bird seed are used every 16 days to feed 48 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 112 parakeets for 120 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((112 * 17) * 120) / (16 * 48)) = 297.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 259 cups of bird seed are used every 14 days to feed 288 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 102 parakeets for 280 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 * 259) * 280) / (14 * 288)) = 1834.5833333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 215 cups of bird seed are used every 113 days to feed 230 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 143 parakeets for 4 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 215) * 4) / (113 * 230)) = 4.731819930742593"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 82 cups of bird seed are used every 217 days to feed 175 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 143 parakeets for 80 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 82) * 80) / (217 * 175)) = 24.702567478604344"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 111 cups of bird seed are used every 173 days to feed 53 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 48 parakeets for 195 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 111) * 195) / (173 * 53)) = 113.31224779147126"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 50 cups of bird seed are used every 184 days to feed 177 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 136 parakeets for 23 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((136 * 50) * 23) / (184 * 177)) = 4.80225988700565"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 236 cups of bird seed are used every 275 days to feed 64 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 194 parakeets for 41 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((194 * 236) * 41) / (275 * 64)) = 106.65590909090909"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "at sandi \u2019 s pet shop , 283 cups of bird seed are used every 151 days to feed 186 parakeets . how many cups of bird seed would be required to feed 296 parakeets for 99 days ?",
        "Solution": "(((296 * 283) * 99) / (151 * 186)) = 295.27280495620596"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 58 available positions and 13 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((13 / 2) - 1) / (13 - 1)) * ((13 / 2) / 13)) * 58) = 13.291666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 141 available positions and 126 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((126 / 2) - 1) / (126 - 1)) * ((126 / 2) / 126)) * 141) = 34.967999999999996"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 115 available positions and 72 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((72 / 2) - 1) / (72 - 1)) * ((72 / 2) / 72)) * 115) = 28.345070422535212"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 53 available positions and 280 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((280 / 2) - 1) / (280 - 1)) * ((280 / 2) / 280)) * 53) = 13.202508960573477"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 45 available positions and 217 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((217 / 2) - 1) / (217 - 1)) * ((217 / 2) / 217)) * 45) = 11.197916666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 17 available positions and 16 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((16 / 2) - 1) / (16 - 1)) * ((16 / 2) / 16)) * 17) = 3.966666666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 48 available positions and 112 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((112 / 2) - 1) / (112 - 1)) * ((112 / 2) / 112)) * 48) = 11.891891891891891"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 120 available positions and 259 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((259 / 2) - 1) / (259 - 1)) * ((259 / 2) / 259)) * 120) = 29.883720930232556"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 14 available positions and 288 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((288 / 2) - 1) / (288 - 1)) * ((288 / 2) / 288)) * 14) = 3.4878048780487805"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 102 available positions and 280 candidates , one half of whom are democrats and another half are republicans . if it was decided that the positions would be filled at random , then what is the probability e that the both positions will be taken by members of just one party ?",
        "Solution": "(((((280 / 2) - 1) / (280 - 1)) * ((280 / 2) / 280)) * 102) = 25.408602150537632"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 58 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 13 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * ((13 * 58) / ((13 - 58) * 58))) / (58 / 10)) = -2.8888888888888884"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 141 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 126 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * ((126 * 141) / ((126 - 141) * 141))) / (141 / 10)) = -84.00000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 115 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 72 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * ((72 * 115) / ((72 - 115) * 115))) / (115 / 10)) = -16.74418604651163"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 53 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 280 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * ((280 * 53) / ((280 - 53) * 53))) / (53 / 10)) = 12.334801762114537"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 45 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 217 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * ((217 * 45) / ((217 - 45) * 45))) / (45 / 10)) = 12.616279069767442"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 17 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 16 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * ((16 * 17) / ((16 - 17) * 17))) / (17 / 10)) = -160.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 48 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 112 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * ((112 * 48) / ((112 - 48) * 48))) / (48 / 10)) = 17.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 120 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 259 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * ((259 * 120) / ((259 - 120) * 120))) / (120 / 10)) = 18.633093525179856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 14 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 288 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * ((288 * 14) / ((288 - 14) * 14))) / (14 / 10)) = 10.51094890510949"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car travels from point a to point b . the average speed of the car is 102 km / hr and it travels the first half of the trip at a speed of 280 km / hr . what is the speed of the car in the second half of the trip ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * ((280 * 102) / ((280 - 102) * 102))) / (102 / 10)) = 15.730337078651687"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 58 which amounted to rs . 13 after 141 years at simple interest . had the interest been 126 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((126 / 100) + (((13 - 58) / 141) / 58)) * 58) * 141) + 58) = 10317.28"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 115 which amounted to rs . 72 after 53 years at simple interest . had the interest been 280 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((280 / 100) + (((72 - 115) / 53) / 115)) * 115) * 53) + 115) = 17138.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 45 which amounted to rs . 217 after 17 years at simple interest . had the interest been 16 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((16 / 100) + (((217 - 45) / 17) / 45)) * 45) * 17) + 45) = 339.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 48 which amounted to rs . 112 after 120 years at simple interest . had the interest been 259 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((259 / 100) + (((112 - 48) / 120) / 48)) * 48) * 120) + 48) = 15030.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 14 which amounted to rs . 288 after 102 years at simple interest . had the interest been 280 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((280 / 100) + (((288 - 14) / 102) / 14)) * 14) * 102) + 14) = 4286.400000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 215 which amounted to rs . 113 after 230 years at simple interest . had the interest been 143 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((143 / 100) + (((113 - 215) / 230) / 215)) * 215) * 230) + 215) = 70826.49999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 4 which amounted to rs . 82 after 217 years at simple interest . had the interest been 175 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((175 / 100) + (((82 - 4) / 217) / 4)) * 4) * 217) + 4) = 1601.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 143 which amounted to rs . 80 after 111 years at simple interest . had the interest been 173 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((173 / 100) + (((80 - 143) / 111) / 143)) * 143) * 111) + 143) = 27540.29"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 53 which amounted to rs . 48 after 195 years at simple interest . had the interest been 50 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((50 / 100) + (((48 - 53) / 195) / 53)) * 53) * 195) + 53) = 5215.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "sonika deposited rs . 184 which amounted to rs . 177 after 136 years at simple interest . had the interest been 23 % more . she would get how much ?",
        "Solution": "(((((23 / 100) + (((177 - 184) / 136) / 184)) * 184) * 136) + 184) = 5932.5199999999995"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 58 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 13 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 141 , there by earning a profit of 126 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (13 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 126) / 100)) / ((13 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 58) / 100)) = 4.855013774459704"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 115 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 72 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 53 , there by earning a profit of 280 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (72 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 280) / 100)) / ((72 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 115) / 100)) = 7.69192451111554"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 45 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 217 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 17 , there by earning a profit of 16 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (217 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 16) / 100)) / ((217 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 45) / 100)) = 61.06407799037498"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 48 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 112 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 120 , there by earning a profit of 259 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (112 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 259) / 100)) / ((112 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 48) / 100)) = 14.922783981227248"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 14 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 288 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 102 , there by earning a profit of 280 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (288 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 280) / 100)) / ((288 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 14) / 100)) = 25.707156523974074"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 215 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 113 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 230 , there by earning a profit of 143 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (113 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 143) / 100)) / ((113 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 215) / 100)) = 10.401687675205325"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 4 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 82 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 217 , there by earning a profit of 175 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (82 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 175) / 100)) / ((82 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 4) / 100)) = 23.64750633981403"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 143 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 80 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 111 , there by earning a profit of 173 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (80 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 173) / 100)) / ((80 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 143) / 100)) = 10.05692981001623"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 53 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 48 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 195 , there by earning a profit of 50 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (48 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 50) / 100)) / ((48 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 53) / 100)) = 21.2241653418124"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a manufacturer sells a pair of glasses to a wholesale dealer at a profit of 184 % . the wholesaler sells the same to retailer at a profit of 177 % . the retailer in turn sells them to a customer for rs . 136 , there by earning a profit of 23 % . the cost price for the manufacturer is :",
        "Solution": "((((((1 + 2) * (177 / 2)) + ((3 * 3) / 100)) / ((100 + 23) / 100)) / ((177 + 100) / 100)) / ((100 + 184) / 100)) = 27.447860536468788"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 58 meters , if he runs at the rate of 13 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 4) / (13 * (1000 / 3600))) = 64.24615384615385"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 141 meters , if he runs at the rate of 126 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * 4) / (126 * (1000 / 3600))) = 16.114285714285714"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 115 meters , if he runs at the rate of 72 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * 4) / (72 * (1000 / 3600))) = 23.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 53 meters , if he runs at the rate of 280 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 4) / (280 * (1000 / 3600))) = 2.7257142857142855"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 45 meters , if he runs at the rate of 217 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * 4) / (217 * (1000 / 3600))) = 2.986175115207373"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 17 meters , if he runs at the rate of 16 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 4) / (16 * (1000 / 3600))) = 15.299999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 48 meters , if he runs at the rate of 112 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 4) / (112 * (1000 / 3600))) = 6.171428571428571"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 120 meters , if he runs at the rate of 259 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * 4) / (259 * (1000 / 3600))) = 6.671814671814672"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 14 meters , if he runs at the rate of 288 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * 4) / (288 * (1000 / 3600))) = 0.7"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 102 meters , if he runs at the rate of 280 km / hr ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 4) / (280 * (1000 / 3600))) = 5.2457142857142856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 58 positive even integers is 13 . what is the sum of the even integers from 141 to 126 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 + 141) / 2) * (((126 - 141) / 2) + 1)) = -867.75"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 115 positive even integers is 72 . what is the sum of the even integers from 53 to 280 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 + 53) / 2) * (((280 - 53) / 2) + 1)) = 19064.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 45 positive even integers is 217 . what is the sum of the even integers from 17 to 16 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((16 + 17) / 2) * (((16 - 17) / 2) + 1)) = 8.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 48 positive even integers is 112 . what is the sum of the even integers from 120 to 259 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((259 + 120) / 2) * (((259 - 120) / 2) + 1)) = 13359.75"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 14 positive even integers is 288 . what is the sum of the even integers from 102 to 280 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 + 102) / 2) * (((280 - 102) / 2) + 1)) = 17190.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 215 positive even integers is 113 . what is the sum of the even integers from 230 to 143 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 + 230) / 2) * (((143 - 230) / 2) + 1)) = -7926.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 4 positive even integers is 82 . what is the sum of the even integers from 217 to 175 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((175 + 217) / 2) * (((175 - 217) / 2) + 1)) = -3920.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 143 positive even integers is 80 . what is the sum of the even integers from 111 to 173 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((173 + 111) / 2) * (((173 - 111) / 2) + 1)) = 4544.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 53 positive even integers is 48 . what is the sum of the even integers from 195 to 50 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((50 + 195) / 2) * (((50 - 195) / 2) + 1)) = -8758.75"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the sum of the first 184 positive even integers is 177 . what is the sum of the even integers from 136 to 23 inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(((23 + 136) / 2) * (((23 - 136) / 2) + 1)) = -4412.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 58 matches is 13 . in the next 58 matches the batsman scored an average of 141 runs . find his average in all the 126 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((13 * 58) + (141 * 58)) / (58 + 58)) = 77.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 115 matches is 72 . in the next 115 matches the batsman scored an average of 53 runs . find his average in all the 280 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((72 * 115) + (53 * 115)) / (115 + 115)) = 62.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 45 matches is 217 . in the next 45 matches the batsman scored an average of 17 runs . find his average in all the 16 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 45) + (17 * 45)) / (45 + 45)) = 117.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 48 matches is 112 . in the next 48 matches the batsman scored an average of 120 runs . find his average in all the 259 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((112 * 48) + (120 * 48)) / (48 + 48)) = 116.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 14 matches is 288 . in the next 14 matches the batsman scored an average of 102 runs . find his average in all the 280 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((288 * 14) + (102 * 14)) / (14 + 14)) = 195.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 215 matches is 113 . in the next 215 matches the batsman scored an average of 230 runs . find his average in all the 143 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((113 * 215) + (230 * 215)) / (215 + 215)) = 171.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 4 matches is 82 . in the next 4 matches the batsman scored an average of 217 runs . find his average in all the 175 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((82 * 4) + (217 * 4)) / (4 + 4)) = 149.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 143 matches is 80 . in the next 143 matches the batsman scored an average of 111 runs . find his average in all the 173 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((80 * 143) + (111 * 143)) / (143 + 143)) = 95.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 53 matches is 48 . in the next 53 matches the batsman scored an average of 195 runs . find his average in all the 50 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 53) + (195 * 53)) / (53 + 53)) = 121.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the average runs scored by a batsman in 184 matches is 177 . in the next 184 matches the batsman scored an average of 136 runs . find his average in all the 23 matches ?",
        "Solution": "(((177 * 184) + (136 * 184)) / (184 + 184)) = 156.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 58 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 13 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(58 - ((58 / 13) / 10)) = 57.55384615384615"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 141 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 126 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(141 - ((141 / 126) / 10)) = 140.88809523809525"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 115 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 72 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(115 - ((115 / 72) / 10)) = 114.84027777777777"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 53 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 280 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(53 - ((53 / 280) / 10)) = 52.981071428571425"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 45 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 217 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(45 - ((45 / 217) / 10)) = 44.97926267281106"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 17 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 16 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(17 - ((17 / 16) / 10)) = 16.89375"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 48 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 112 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(48 - ((48 / 112) / 10)) = 47.957142857142856"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 120 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 259 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(120 - ((120 / 259) / 10)) = 119.95366795366796"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 14 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 288 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(14 - ((14 / 288) / 10)) = 13.995138888888889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "there are 102 giraffes at a large zoo . the number of giraffes is 280 times the number of all the other animals combined . how many more giraffes are there than non giraffes animals at the zoo ?",
        "Solution": "(102 - ((102 / 280) / 10)) = 101.96357142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 58 / 13 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 141 / 126 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((13 + 141) / (126 * 2)) = 0.6111111111111112"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 115 / 72 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 53 / 280 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((72 + 53) / (280 * 2)) = 0.22321428571428573"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 45 / 217 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 17 / 16 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((217 + 17) / (16 * 2)) = 7.3125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 48 / 112 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 120 / 259 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((112 + 120) / (259 * 2)) = 0.44787644787644787"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 14 / 288 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 102 / 280 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((288 + 102) / (280 * 2)) = 0.6964285714285714"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 215 / 113 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 230 / 143 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((113 + 230) / (143 * 2)) = 1.1993006993006994"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 4 / 82 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 217 / 175 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((82 + 217) / (175 * 2)) = 0.8542857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 143 / 80 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 111 / 173 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((80 + 111) / (173 * 2)) = 0.5520231213872833"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 53 / 48 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 195 / 50 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((48 + 195) / (50 * 2)) = 2.43"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "bucket a is 184 / 177 full of sand , and bucket b , which has one - half the capacity of bucket a , is 136 / 23 full of sand . jana pours the contents of bucket b into bucket a . bucket a is now filled to what fraction of its capacity ?",
        "Solution": "((177 + 136) / (23 * 2)) = 6.804347826086956"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 58 ) - n and f ( 13 ) = 141 . what is the value of f ( 126 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((141 - (58 + 13)) - 126) = -56"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 115 ) - n and f ( 72 ) = 53 . what is the value of f ( 280 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((53 - (115 + 72)) - 280) = -414"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 45 ) - n and f ( 217 ) = 17 . what is the value of f ( 16 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((17 - (45 + 217)) - 16) = -261"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 48 ) - n and f ( 112 ) = 120 . what is the value of f ( 259 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((120 - (48 + 112)) - 259) = -299"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 14 ) - n and f ( 288 ) = 102 . what is the value of f ( 280 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((102 - (14 + 288)) - 280) = -480"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 215 ) - n and f ( 113 ) = 230 . what is the value of f ( 143 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((230 - (215 + 113)) - 143) = -241"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 4 ) - n and f ( 82 ) = 217 . what is the value of f ( 175 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((217 - (4 + 82)) - 175) = -44"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 143 ) - n and f ( 80 ) = 111 . what is the value of f ( 173 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((111 - (143 + 80)) - 173) = -285"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 53 ) - n and f ( 48 ) = 195 . what is the value of f ( 50 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((195 - (53 + 48)) - 50) = 44"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if n is an integer , f ( n ) = f ( n - 184 ) - n and f ( 177 ) = 136 . what is the value of f ( 23 ) ?",
        "Solution": "((136 - (184 + 177)) - 23) = -248"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 58 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 13 plus 2.58 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 141,126 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 115 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(115 / (58 / 100)) = 198.27586206896552"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 72 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 53 plus 2.72 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 280,45 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 217 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / (72 / 100)) = 301.3888888888889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 17 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 16 plus 2.17 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 48,112 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 120 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / (17 / 100)) = 705.8823529411765"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 259 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 14 plus 2.259 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 288,102 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 280 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / (259 / 100)) = 108.10810810810811"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 215 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 113 plus 2.215 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 230,143 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 4 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(4 / (215 / 100)) = 1.8604651162790697"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 82 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 217 plus 2.82 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 175,143 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 80 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(80 / (82 / 100)) = 97.5609756097561"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 111 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 173 plus 2.111 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 53,48 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 195 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(195 / (111 / 100)) = 175.67567567567565"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 50 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 184 plus 2.50 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 177,136 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 23 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(23 / (50 / 100)) = 46.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 236 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 275 plus 2.236 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 64,194 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 41 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(41 / (236 / 100)) = 17.372881355932204"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a salesman \u2019 s terms were changed from a flat commission of 283 % on all his sales to a fixed salary of rs . 151 plus 2.283 % commission on all sales exceeding rs . 186,296 . if his remuneration as per new scheme was rs . 99 more than that by the previous schema , his sales were worth ?",
        "Solution": "(99 / (283 / 100)) = 34.98233215547703"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 58 to 13 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((13 - 58) + 1) = -44"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 141 to 126 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((126 - 141) + 1) = -14"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 115 to 72 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((72 - 115) + 1) = -42"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 53 to 280 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((280 - 53) + 1) = 228"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 45 to 217 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((217 - 45) + 1) = 173"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 17 to 16 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((16 - 17) + 1) = 0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 48 to 112 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((112 - 48) + 1) = 65"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 120 to 259 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((259 - 120) + 1) = 140"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 14 to 288 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((288 - 14) + 1) = 275"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "andy solves problems 102 to 280 inclusive in a math exercise . how many problems does he solve ?",
        "Solution": "((280 - 102) + 1) = 179"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 58 and their hcf is 13 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((58 + 58) - (13 + 13)) = 90"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 141 and their hcf is 126 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((141 + 141) - (126 + 126)) = 30"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 115 and their hcf is 72 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((115 + 115) - (72 + 72)) = 86"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 53 and their hcf is 280 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((53 + 53) - (280 + 280)) = -454"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 45 and their hcf is 217 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((45 + 45) - (217 + 217)) = -344"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 17 and their hcf is 16 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((17 + 17) - (16 + 16)) = 2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 48 and their hcf is 112 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((48 + 48) - (112 + 112)) = -128"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 120 and their hcf is 259 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((120 + 120) - (259 + 259)) = -278"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 14 and their hcf is 288 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((14 + 14) - (288 + 288)) = -548"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a ' and ' b ' are positive integers such that their lcm is 102 and their hcf is 280 . what is the addition of the maximum and minimum possible values of ' a + b ' ?",
        "Solution": "((102 + 102) - (280 + 280)) = -356"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 / 13 of all married couples have more than one child . 141 / 13 of all married couples have more than 58 children . what fraction of all married couples have 141 or 58 children ?",
        "Solution": "((58 / 13) - (141 / 13)) = -6.384615384615385"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "126 / 115 of all married couples have more than one child . 72 / 115 of all married couples have more than 126 children . what fraction of all married couples have 72 or 126 children ?",
        "Solution": "((126 / 115) - (72 / 115)) = 0.4695652173913042"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 / 280 of all married couples have more than one child . 45 / 280 of all married couples have more than 53 children . what fraction of all married couples have 45 or 53 children ?",
        "Solution": "((53 / 280) - (45 / 280)) = 0.028571428571428553"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "217 / 17 of all married couples have more than one child . 16 / 17 of all married couples have more than 217 children . what fraction of all married couples have 16 or 217 children ?",
        "Solution": "((217 / 17) - (16 / 17)) = 11.823529411764707"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 / 112 of all married couples have more than one child . 120 / 112 of all married couples have more than 48 children . what fraction of all married couples have 120 or 48 children ?",
        "Solution": "((48 / 112) - (120 / 112)) = -0.6428571428571428"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "259 / 14 of all married couples have more than one child . 288 / 14 of all married couples have more than 259 children . what fraction of all married couples have 288 or 259 children ?",
        "Solution": "((259 / 14) - (288 / 14)) = -2.071428571428573"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "102 / 280 of all married couples have more than one child . 215 / 280 of all married couples have more than 102 children . what fraction of all married couples have 215 or 102 children ?",
        "Solution": "((102 / 280) - (215 / 280)) = -0.40357142857142864"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "113 / 230 of all married couples have more than one child . 143 / 230 of all married couples have more than 113 children . what fraction of all married couples have 143 or 113 children ?",
        "Solution": "((113 / 230) - (143 / 230)) = -0.13043478260869562"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "4 / 82 of all married couples have more than one child . 217 / 82 of all married couples have more than 4 children . what fraction of all married couples have 217 or 4 children ?",
        "Solution": "((4 / 82) - (217 / 82)) = -2.597560975609756"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "175 / 143 of all married couples have more than one child . 80 / 143 of all married couples have more than 175 children . what fraction of all married couples have 80 or 175 children ?",
        "Solution": "((175 / 143) - (80 / 143)) = 0.6643356643356643"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 58 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (58 * 2)))) = 1.008695652173913"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 13 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (13 * 2)))) = 1.04"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 141 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (141 * 2)))) = 1.0035587188612098"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 126 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (126 * 2)))) = 1.00398406374502"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 115 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (115 * 2)))) = 1.0043668122270741"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 72 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (72 * 2)))) = 1.0069930069930069"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 53 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (53 * 2)))) = 1.0095238095238095"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 280 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (280 * 2)))) = 1.0017889087656529"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 45 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (45 * 2)))) = 1.0112359550561798"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "one pump drains one - half of a pond in 217 hours , and then a second pump starts draining the pond . the two pumps working together finish emptying the pond in one - half hour . how long would it take the second pump to drain the pond if it had to do the job alone ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (1 - (1 / (217 * 2)))) = 1.002309468822171"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 58 ^ 58 n + 58 ^ 58 n + 58 ^ 58 n + 58 ^ 58 n = 13 ^ 141 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((141 * 58) - 58) / 58) = 140.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 126 ^ 126 n + 126 ^ 126 n + 126 ^ 126 n + 126 ^ 126 n = 115 ^ 72 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((72 * 126) - 126) / 126) = 71.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 53 ^ 53 n + 53 ^ 53 n + 53 ^ 53 n + 53 ^ 53 n = 280 ^ 45 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 53) - 53) / 53) = 44.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 217 ^ 217 n + 217 ^ 217 n + 217 ^ 217 n + 217 ^ 217 n = 17 ^ 16 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((16 * 217) - 217) / 217) = 15.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 48 ^ 48 n + 48 ^ 48 n + 48 ^ 48 n + 48 ^ 48 n = 112 ^ 120 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((120 * 48) - 48) / 48) = 119.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 259 ^ 259 n + 259 ^ 259 n + 259 ^ 259 n + 259 ^ 259 n = 14 ^ 288 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((288 * 259) - 259) / 259) = 287.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 102 ^ 102 n + 102 ^ 102 n + 102 ^ 102 n + 102 ^ 102 n = 280 ^ 215 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((215 * 102) - 102) / 102) = 214.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 113 ^ 113 n + 113 ^ 113 n + 113 ^ 113 n + 113 ^ 113 n = 230 ^ 143 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 113) - 113) / 113) = 142.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 4 ^ 4 n + 4 ^ 4 n + 4 ^ 4 n + 4 ^ 4 n = 82 ^ 217 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 4) - 4) / 4) = 216.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 175 ^ 175 n + 175 ^ 175 n + 175 ^ 175 n + 175 ^ 175 n = 143 ^ 80 , then n =",
        "Solution": "(((80 * 175) - 175) / 175) = 79.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 58 % profit on his goods . he lost 13 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 58) - (((100 + 58) * 13) / 100))) = -37.46000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 141 % profit on his goods . he lost 126 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 141) - (((100 + 141) * 126) / 100))) = 162.66000000000003"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 115 % profit on his goods . he lost 72 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 115) - (((100 + 115) * 72) / 100))) = 39.80000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 53 % profit on his goods . he lost 280 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 53) - (((100 + 53) * 280) / 100))) = 375.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 45 % profit on his goods . he lost 217 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 45) - (((100 + 45) * 217) / 100))) = 269.65"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 17 % profit on his goods . he lost 16 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 17) - (((100 + 17) * 16) / 100))) = 1.7199999999999989"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 48 % profit on his goods . he lost 112 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 48) - (((100 + 48) * 112) / 100))) = 117.75999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 120 % profit on his goods . he lost 259 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 120) - (((100 + 120) * 259) / 100))) = 449.79999999999995"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 14 % profit on his goods . he lost 288 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 14) - (((100 + 14) * 288) / 100))) = 314.32"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a fair price shopkeeper takes 102 % profit on his goods . he lost 280 % goods during theft . his loss percent is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((100 + 102) - (((100 + 102) * 280) / 100))) = 463.6"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 58 / 13 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 141 / 126 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 115 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((58 * 13) * 115) / 58) * 13) / 58) = 335.08620689655174"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 72 / 53 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 280 / 45 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 217 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((72 * 53) * 217) / 72) * 53) / 72) = 8466.013888888889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 17 / 16 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 48 / 112 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 120 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((17 * 16) * 120) / 17) * 16) / 17) = 1807.0588235294117"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 259 / 14 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 288 / 102 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 280 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((259 * 14) * 280) / 259) * 14) / 259) = 211.8918918918919"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 215 / 113 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 230 / 143 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 4 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((215 * 113) * 4) / 215) * 113) / 215) = 237.56279069767442"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 82 / 217 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 175 / 143 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 80 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((82 * 217) * 80) / 82) * 217) / 82) = 45940.48780487805"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 111 / 173 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 53 / 48 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 195 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((111 * 173) * 195) / 111) * 173) / 111) = 52577.97297297297"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 50 / 184 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 177 / 136 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 23 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((50 * 184) * 23) / 50) * 184) / 50) = 15573.76"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 236 / 275 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 64 / 194 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 41 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((236 * 275) * 41) / 236) * 275) / 236) = 13138.24152542373"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in cliff \u2019 s impressive rock collection , there are half as many igneous rocks as sedimentary rocks . of the igneous rocks , 283 / 151 are shiny and the rest are matte , while 186 / 296 of the sedimentary rocks are shiny . if there are 99 shiny igneous rocks , how many total rocks does cliff have ?",
        "Solution": "(((((283 * 151) * 99) / 283) * 151) / 283) = 7976.3215547703185"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 58 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(58 - (((58 / (10 / 2)) + (58 / 3)) - (58 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 30.933333333333337"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 13 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(13 - (((13 / (10 / 2)) + (13 / 3)) - (13 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 6.933333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 141 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(141 - (((141 / (10 / 2)) + (141 / 3)) - (141 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 75.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 126 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(126 - (((126 / (10 / 2)) + (126 / 3)) - (126 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 67.19999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 115 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(115 - (((115 / (10 / 2)) + (115 / 3)) - (115 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 61.33333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 72 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(72 - (((72 / (10 / 2)) + (72 / 3)) - (72 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 38.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 53 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(53 - (((53 / (10 / 2)) + (53 / 3)) - (53 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 28.266666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 280 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(280 - (((280 / (10 / 2)) + (280 / 3)) - (280 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 149.33333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 45 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(45 - (((45 / (10 / 2)) + (45 / 3)) - (45 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 24.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two assembly line inspectors , smithy and glen , inspect widgets as they come off the assembly line . if smithy inspects every fifth widget , starting with the fifth , and glen inspects every third , starting with the third , how many of the 217 widgets produced in the first hour of operation are not inspected by either inspector ?",
        "Solution": "(217 - (((217 / (10 / 2)) + (217 / 3)) - (217 / ((10 / 2) * 3)))) = 115.73333333333335"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 58 and 13 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 13) / 4) = 188.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 141 and 126 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * 126) / 4) = 4441.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 115 and 72 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * 72) / 4) = 2070.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 53 and 280 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 280) / 4) = 3710.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 45 and 217 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * 217) / 4) = 2441.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 17 and 16 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 16) / 4) = 68.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 48 and 112 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 112) / 4) = 1344.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 120 and 259 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * 259) / 4) = 7770.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 14 and 288 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * 288) / 4) = 1008.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the sum of the numbers between 102 and 280 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 280) / 4) = 7140.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 58 km in the first hour and 13 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((58 + 13) / 2) = 35.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 141 km in the first hour and 126 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((141 + 126) / 2) = 133.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 115 km in the first hour and 72 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((115 + 72) / 2) = 93.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 53 km in the first hour and 280 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((53 + 280) / 2) = 166.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 45 km in the first hour and 217 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((45 + 217) / 2) = 131.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 17 km in the first hour and 16 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((17 + 16) / 2) = 16.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 48 km in the first hour and 112 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((48 + 112) / 2) = 80.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 120 km in the first hour and 259 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((120 + 259) / 2) = 189.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 14 km in the first hour and 288 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((14 + 288) / 2) = 151.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the speed of a car is 102 km in the first hour and 280 km in the second hour . what is the average speed of the car ?",
        "Solution": "((102 + 280) / 2) = 191.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 58 children , 13 % children can speak only english , 141 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((58 - 13) + ((141 * 58) / 100)) = 126.78"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 126 children , 115 % children can speak only english , 72 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((126 - 115) + ((72 * 126) / 100)) = 101.72"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 53 children , 280 % children can speak only english , 45 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((53 - 280) + ((45 * 53) / 100)) = -203.15"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 217 children , 17 % children can speak only english , 16 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((217 - 17) + ((16 * 217) / 100)) = 234.72"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 48 children , 112 % children can speak only english , 120 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((48 - 112) + ((120 * 48) / 100)) = -6.399999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 259 children , 14 % children can speak only english , 288 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((259 - 14) + ((288 * 259) / 100)) = 990.92"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 102 children , 280 % children can speak only english , 215 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((102 - 280) + ((215 * 102) / 100)) = 41.30000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 113 children , 230 % children can speak only english , 143 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((113 - 230) + ((143 * 113) / 100)) = 44.59"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 4 children , 82 % children can speak only english , 217 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((4 - 82) + ((217 * 4) / 100)) = -69.32"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a class of 175 children , 143 % children can speak only english , 80 % hindi and english both and the rest of the children can speak only hindi . how many children can speak hindi ?",
        "Solution": "((175 - 143) + ((80 * 175) / 100)) = 172.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 % of a number is more than 13 % of 141 by 126 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((141 * 13) / 100) + 126) * 100) / 58) = 248.84482758620686"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 % of a number is more than 72 % of 53 by 280 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((53 * 72) / 100) + 280) * 100) / 115) = 276.66086956521735"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 % of a number is more than 217 % of 17 by 16 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((17 * 217) / 100) + 16) * 100) / 45) = 117.53333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 % of a number is more than 112 % of 120 by 259 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((120 * 112) / 100) + 259) * 100) / 48) = 819.5833333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "14 % of a number is more than 288 % of 102 by 280 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((102 * 288) / 100) + 280) * 100) / 14) = 4098.285714285715"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "215 % of a number is more than 113 % of 230 by 143 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((230 * 113) / 100) + 143) * 100) / 215) = 187.3953488372093"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "4 % of a number is more than 82 % of 217 by 175 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((217 * 82) / 100) + 175) * 100) / 4) = 8823.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "143 % of a number is more than 80 % of 111 by 173 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((111 * 80) / 100) + 173) * 100) / 143) = 183.07692307692307"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 % of a number is more than 48 % of 195 by 50 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((195 * 48) / 100) + 50) * 100) / 53) = 270.9433962264151"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "184 % of a number is more than 177 % of 136 by 23 . find the number ?",
        "Solution": "(((((136 * 177) / 100) + 23) * 100) / 184) = 143.32608695652175"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 58 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 13 cylinders . if 141 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 13) - 141) = 613"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 126 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 115 cylinders . if 72 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * 115) - 72) = 14418"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 53 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 280 cylinders . if 45 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 280) - 45) = 14795"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 217 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 17 cylinders . if 16 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 17) - 16) = 3673"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 48 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 112 cylinders . if 120 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 112) - 120) = 5256"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 259 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 14 cylinders . if 288 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * 14) - 288) = 3338"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 102 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 280 cylinders . if 215 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 280) - 215) = 28345"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 113 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 230 cylinders . if 143 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((113 * 230) - 143) = 25847"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 4 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 82 cylinders . if 217 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((4 * 82) - 217) = 111"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "george ' s car calls for 175 ounces of oil for each cylinder used . his car ' s engine has 143 cylinders . if 80 ounces of oil has already been put into the engine used , then how many additional ounces of oil are needed ?",
        "Solution": "((175 * 143) - 80) = 24945"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 58 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 58 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 13 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 58) / (58 / 58)) = 42.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 141 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 141 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 126 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 141) / (141 / 141)) = -41.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 115 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 115 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 72 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 115) / (115 / 115)) = -15.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 53 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 53 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 280 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 53) / (53 / 53)) = 47.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 45 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 45 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 217 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 45) / (45 / 45)) = 55.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 17 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 17 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 16 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 17) / (17 / 17)) = 83.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 48 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 48 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 112 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 48) / (48 / 48)) = 52.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 120 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 120 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 259 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 120) / (120 / 120)) = -20.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 14 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 14 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 288 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 14) / (14 / 14)) = 86.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a car traveled 102 % of the way from town x to town y at an average speed of 102 mph . the car traveled at an average speed of v mph for the remaining part of the trip . the average speed for the entire trip was 280 mph . what is v in mph ?",
        "Solution": "((100 - 102) / (102 / 102)) = -2.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 58 years at 13 % per annum be rs . 141 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 13) * 13) * 58) / 100) = 29406.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 126 years at 115 % per annum be rs . 72 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 115) * 115) * 126) / 100) = 4999050.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 53 years at 280 % per annum be rs . 45 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 280) * 280) * 53) / 100) = 12465600.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 217 years at 17 % per annum be rs . 16 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 17) * 17) * 217) / 100) = 188139.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 48 years at 112 % per annum be rs . 120 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 112) * 112) * 48) / 100) = 1806336.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 259 years at 14 % per annum be rs . 288 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 14) * 14) * 259) / 100) = 152292.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 102 years at 280 % per annum be rs . 215 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 280) * 280) * 102) / 100) = 23990400.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 113 years at 230 % per annum be rs . 143 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 230) * 230) * 113) / 100) = 17933100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 4 years at 82 % per annum be rs . 217 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 82) * 82) * 4) / 100) = 80688.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the compound interest on a certain sum of money for 175 years at 143 % per annum be rs . 80 , what would be the simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "(((((3.0 * 100) * 143) * 143) * 175) / 100) = 10735725.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 58 hammers and 13 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((58 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 13)) = -7.428571428571429"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 141 hammers and 126 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((141 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 126)) = -1.125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 115 hammers and 72 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((115 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 72)) = -1.6515151515151516"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 53 hammers and 280 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((53 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 280)) = -0.17153284671532848"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 45 hammers and 217 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((45 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 217)) = -0.1848341232227488"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 17 hammers and 16 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((17 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 16)) = -1.1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 48 hammers and 112 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((48 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 112)) = -0.39622641509433965"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 120 hammers and 259 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((120 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 259)) = -0.4505928853754941"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 14 hammers and 288 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((14 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 288)) = -0.028368794326241134"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "hammers and wrenches are manufactured at a uniform weight per hammer and a uniform weight per wrench . if the total weight of two hammers and two wrenches is one - third that of 102 hammers and 280 wrenches , then the total weight of one wrench is how many times that of one hammer ?",
        "Solution": "((102 - (3 * 2)) / ((3 * 2) - 280)) = -0.35036496350364965"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 58 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 13 : 13 : 141 . if the mixture is worth rs . 126 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((126 * ((13 + 13) + 141)) - (58 + 58)) / 141) = 148.4113475177305"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 115 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 72 : 72 : 53 . if the mixture is worth rs . 280 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((280 * ((72 + 72) + 53)) - (115 + 115)) / 53) = 1036.4150943396226"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 45 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 217 : 217 : 17 . if the mixture is worth rs . 16 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((16 * ((217 + 217) + 17)) - (45 + 45)) / 17) = 419.1764705882353"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 48 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 112 : 112 : 120 . if the mixture is worth rs . 259 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((259 * ((112 + 112) + 120)) - (48 + 48)) / 120) = 741.6666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 14 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 288 : 288 : 102 . if the mixture is worth rs . 280 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((280 * ((288 + 288) + 102)) - (14 + 14)) / 102) = 1860.9019607843138"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 215 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 113 : 113 : 230 . if the mixture is worth rs . 143 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((143 * ((113 + 113) + 230)) - (215 + 215)) / 230) = 281.6434782608696"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 4 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 82 : 82 : 217 . if the mixture is worth rs . 175 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((175 * ((82 + 82) + 217)) - (4 + 4)) / 217) = 307.221198156682"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 143 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 80 : 80 : 111 . if the mixture is worth rs . 173 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((173 * ((80 + 80) + 111)) - (143 + 143)) / 111) = 419.7927927927928"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 53 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 48 : 48 : 195 . if the mixture is worth rs . 50 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((50 * ((48 + 48) + 195)) - (53 + 53)) / 195) = 74.07179487179488"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tea worth rs . 184 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 177 : 177 : 136 . if the mixture is worth rs . 23 per kg , the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "Solution": "(((23 * ((177 + 177) + 136)) - (184 + 184)) / 136) = 80.16176470588235"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 58 % of total students failed in hindi , 13 % failed in english and 141 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((58 + 13) - 141)) = 170"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 126 % of total students failed in hindi , 115 % failed in english and 72 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((126 + 115) - 72)) = -69"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 53 % of total students failed in hindi , 280 % failed in english and 45 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((53 + 280) - 45)) = -188"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 217 % of total students failed in hindi , 17 % failed in english and 16 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((217 + 17) - 16)) = -118"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 48 % of total students failed in hindi , 112 % failed in english and 120 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((48 + 112) - 120)) = 60"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 259 % of total students failed in hindi , 14 % failed in english and 288 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((259 + 14) - 288)) = 115"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 102 % of total students failed in hindi , 280 % failed in english and 215 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((102 + 280) - 215)) = -67"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 113 % of total students failed in hindi , 230 % failed in english and 143 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((113 + 230) - 143)) = -100"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 4 % of total students failed in hindi , 82 % failed in english and 217 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((4 + 82) - 217)) = 231"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in an examination , 175 % of total students failed in hindi , 143 % failed in english and 80 % in both . the percentage of these who passed in both the subjects is :",
        "Solution": "(100 - ((175 + 143) - 80)) = -138"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 58 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 / 3) / 3) + (((58 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 9.666666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 13 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((13 / 3) / 3) + (((13 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 2.1666666666666665"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 141 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((141 / 3) / 3) + (((141 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 23.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 126 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((126 / 3) / 3) + (((126 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 21.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 115 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((115 / 3) / 3) + (((115 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 19.166666666666668"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 72 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((72 / 3) / 3) + (((72 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 12.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 53 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 / 3) / 3) + (((53 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 8.833333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 280 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((280 / 3) / 3) + (((280 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 46.666666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 45 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((45 / 3) / 3) + (((45 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 7.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the total circumference of two circles is 217 . if the first circle has a circumference that is exactly twice the circumference of the second circle , then what is the approximate sum of their two radii ?",
        "Solution": "((((217 / 3) / 3) + (((217 / 3) * 2) / 3)) / 2) = 36.166666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 58 and will last for 13 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 141 and will last for 126 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((141 - (58 * 126)) / (58 * 126))) = -98.07060755336617"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 115 and will last for 72 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 53 and will last for 280 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((53 - (115 * 280)) / (115 * 280))) = -99.83540372670807"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 45 and will last for 217 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 17 and will last for 16 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((17 - (45 * 16)) / (45 * 16))) = -97.63888888888889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 48 and will last for 112 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 120 and will last for 259 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((120 - (48 * 259)) / (48 * 259))) = -99.03474903474904"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 14 and will last for 288 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 102 and will last for 280 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((102 - (14 * 280)) / (14 * 280))) = -97.39795918367346"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 215 and will last for 113 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 230 and will last for 143 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((230 - (215 * 143)) / (215 * 143))) = -99.25191087981786"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 4 and will last for 82 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 217 and will last for 175 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((217 - (4 * 175)) / (4 * 175))) = -69.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 143 and will last for 80 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 111 and will last for 173 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((111 - (143 * 173)) / (143 * 173))) = -99.55131573628684"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 53 and will last for 48 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 195 and will last for 50 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((195 - (53 * 50)) / (53 * 50))) = -92.64150943396227"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain pair of used shoes can be repaired for $ 184 and will last for 177 year . a pair of the same kind of shoes can be purchased new for $ 136 and will last for 23 years . the average cost per year of the new shoes is what percent greater than the cost of repairing the used shoes ?",
        "Solution": "(100 * ((136 - (184 * 23)) / (184 * 23))) = -96.78638941398866"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 58 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 13 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 58) - (1 / 13))) = -16.755555555555553"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 141 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 126 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 141) - (1 / 126))) = -1184.4000000000003"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 115 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 72 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 115) - (1 / 72))) = -192.55813953488376"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 53 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 280 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 53) - (1 / 280))) = 65.37444933920705"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 45 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 217 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 45) - (1 / 217))) = 56.77325581395349"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 17 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 16 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 17) - (1 / 16))) = -271.99999999999994"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 48 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 112 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 48) - (1 / 112))) = 84.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 120 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 259 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 120) - (1 / 259))) = 223.59712230215828"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 14 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 288 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 14) - (1 / 288))) = 14.715328467153286"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a cistern can be filled by a tap in 102 hours while it can be emptied by another tap in 280 hours . if both the taps are opened simultaneously , then after how much time will the cistern get filled ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / ((1 / 102) - (1 / 280))) = 160.4494382022472"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 58 and rs . 13 in a business . after 141 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 126 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 141) + ((13 / 3) * (126 * 141))) / ((13 * (126 * 3)) + ((13 - (13 / 3)) * (126 * 3)))) = 10.398534798534799"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 115 and rs . 72 in a business . after 53 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 280 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 * 53) + ((72 / 3) * (280 * 53))) / ((72 * (280 * 3)) + ((72 - (72 / 3)) * (280 * 3)))) = 3.5937996031746033"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 45 and rs . 217 in a business . after 17 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 16 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 17) + ((217 / 3) * (16 * 17))) / ((217 * (16 * 3)) + ((217 - (217 / 3)) * (16 * 3)))) = 1.1774001536098309"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 48 and rs . 112 in a business . after 120 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 259 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 120) + ((112 / 3) * (259 * 120))) / ((112 * (259 * 3)) + ((112 - (112 / 3)) * (259 * 3)))) = 8.039713182570326"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 14 and rs . 288 in a business . after 102 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 280 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 * 102) + ((288 / 3) * (280 * 102))) / ((288 * (280 * 3)) + ((288 - (288 / 3)) * (280 * 3)))) = 6.803541666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 215 and rs . 113 in a business . after 230 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 143 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((215 * 230) + ((113 / 3) * (143 * 230))) / ((113 * (143 * 3)) + ((113 - (113 / 3)) * (143 * 3)))) = 15.945376157765537"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 4 and rs . 82 in a business . after 217 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 175 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 217) + ((82 / 3) * (175 * 217))) / ((82 * (175 * 3)) + ((82 - (82 / 3)) * (175 * 3)))) = 14.478764227642275"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 143 and rs . 80 in a business . after 111 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 173 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 111) + ((80 / 3) * (173 * 111))) / ((80 * (173 * 3)) + ((80 - (80 / 3)) * (173 * 3)))) = 7.629378612716763"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 53 and rs . 48 in a business . after 195 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 50 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 195) + ((48 / 3) * (50 * 195))) / ((48 * (50 * 3)) + ((48 - (48 / 3)) * (50 * 3)))) = 13.86125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a and b invests rs . 184 and rs . 177 in a business . after 136 months , a withdraws half of his capital and 23 months later , b withdraws one - third of his capital . in what ratio should they share the profits at the end of the year ?",
        "Solution": "(((184 * 136) + ((177 / 3) * (23 * 136))) / ((177 * (23 * 3)) + ((177 - (177 / 3)) * (23 * 3)))) = 10.296045197740114"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 58 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(58 * 2) = 116"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 13 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(13 * 2) = 26"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 141 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(141 * 2) = 282"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 126 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(126 * 2) = 252"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 115 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(115 * 2) = 230"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 72 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(72 * 2) = 144"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 53 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(53 * 2) = 106"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 280 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(280 * 2) = 560"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 45 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(45 * 2) = 90"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a runs twice as fast as b and gives b a start of 217 m . how long should the racecourse be so that a and b might reach in the same time ?",
        "Solution": "(217 * 2) = 434"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 58 : 13 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 141 : 126 . if there are 115 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((115 / (((58 * 13) + 141) + 126)) * 141) = 15.88148873653281"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 72 : 53 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 280 : 45 . if there are 217 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((217 / (((72 * 53) + 280) + 45)) * 280) = 14.672784351605891"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 17 : 16 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 48 : 112 . if there are 120 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((120 / (((17 * 16) + 48) + 112)) * 48) = 13.333333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 259 : 14 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 288 : 102 . if there are 280 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((280 / (((259 * 14) + 288) + 102)) * 288) = 20.079681274900395"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 215 : 113 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 230 : 143 . if there are 4 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((4 / (((215 * 113) + 230) + 143)) * 230) = 0.037295281336143994"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 82 : 217 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 175 : 143 . if there are 80 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((80 / (((82 * 217) + 175) + 143)) * 175) = 0.7729681978798587"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 111 : 173 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 53 : 48 . if there are 195 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((195 / (((111 * 173) + 53) + 48)) * 53) = 0.5353812681309573"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 50 : 184 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 177 : 136 . if there are 23 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((23 / (((50 * 184) + 177) + 136)) * 177) = 0.42794071270892464"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 236 : 275 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 64 : 194 . if there are 41 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((41 / (((236 * 275) + 64) + 194)) * 64) = 0.04027134043402192"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain town , the ratio of ny yankees fans to ny mets fans is 283 : 151 , and the ratio of ny mets fans to boston red sox fans is 186 : 296 . if there are 99 baseball fans in the town , each of whom is a fan of exactly one of those three teams , how many ny mets fans are there in this town ?",
        "Solution": "((99 / (((283 * 151) + 186) + 296)) * 186) = 0.4261020479000347"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 58 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 13 / 141 ?",
        "Solution": "(13 / 141) = 0.09219858156028368"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 126 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 115 / 72 ?",
        "Solution": "(115 / 72) = 1.5972222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 53 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 280 / 45 ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / 45) = 6.222222222222222"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 217 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 17 / 16 ?",
        "Solution": "(17 / 16) = 1.0625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 48 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 112 / 120 ?",
        "Solution": "(112 / 120) = 0.9333333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 259 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 14 / 288 ?",
        "Solution": "(14 / 288) = 0.04861111111111111"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 102 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 280 / 215 ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / 215) = 1.302325581395349"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 113 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 230 / 143 ?",
        "Solution": "(230 / 143) = 1.6083916083916083"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 4 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 82 / 217 ?",
        "Solution": "(82 / 217) = 0.3778801843317972"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "what is the 175 th digit to the right of the decimal point in the decimal form of 143 / 80 ?",
        "Solution": "(143 / 80) = 1.7875"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 58 days . b is 13 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * 60.0) / 100) = 34.8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 141 days . b is 126 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * 60.0) / 100) = 84.6"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 115 days . b is 72 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * 60.0) / 100) = 69.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 53 days . b is 280 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * 60.0) / 100) = 31.8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 45 days . b is 217 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((45 * 60.0) / 100) = 27.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 17 days . b is 16 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 60.0) / 100) = 10.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 48 days . b is 112 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 60.0) / 100) = 28.8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 120 days . b is 259 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * 60.0) / 100) = 72.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 14 days . b is 288 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * 60.0) / 100) = 8.4"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a can complete a certain job in 102 days . b is 280 % more efficient than a . in how many days can b complete the same job ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * 60.0) / 100) = 61.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 58 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (58 * 100)) = 1.7241379310344827"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 13 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (13 * 100)) = 7.6923076923076925"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 141 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (141 * 100)) = 0.7092198581560284"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 126 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (126 * 100)) = 0.7936507936507936"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 115 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (115 * 100)) = 0.8695652173913043"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 72 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (72 * 100)) = 1.3888888888888888"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 53 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (53 * 100)) = 1.8867924528301887"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 280 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (280 * 100)) = 0.35714285714285715"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 45 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (45 * 100)) = 2.2222222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in what time a sum of money double itself at 217 % per annum simple interest ?",
        "Solution": "((100 * 100) / (217 * 100)) = 0.4608294930875576"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 58 , 13,141 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 58) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.741935483870968"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 126 , 115,72 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 126) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.8769230769230774"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 53 , 280,45 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 53) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.719298245614035"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 217 , 17,16 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 217) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.9276018099547514"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 48 , 112,120 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 48) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.6923076923076925"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 259 , 14,288 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 259) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.9391634980988592"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 102 , 280,215 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 102) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.8490566037735854"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 113 , 230,143 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 113) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.8632478632478637"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 4 , 82,217 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 4) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 2.0000000000000004"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a , b , c can complete a piece of work in 175 , 143,80 days . working together , they complete the same work in how many days ?",
        "Solution": "(1 / (((1 / 175) + (1 / (4 + 2))) + (1 / (2 * (4 + 2))))) = 3.9106145251396645"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 58 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 13 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((13 / 58) / (13 / 58)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 141 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 126 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((126 / 141) / (126 / 141)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 115 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 72 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((72 / 115) / (72 / 115)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 53 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 280 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((280 / 53) / (280 / 53)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 45 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 217 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((217 / 45) / (217 / 45)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 17 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 16 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((16 / 17) / (16 / 17)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 48 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 112 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((112 / 48) / (112 / 48)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 120 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 259 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((259 / 120) / (259 / 120)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 14 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 288 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((288 / 14) / (288 / 14)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the horse can run 102 miles / hour , how many days would it take for a horse to run from new york city to washington . d . c . ? ( 280 miles from nyc to d . c . )",
        "Solution": "((280 / 102) / (280 / 102)) = 1.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 58 + . 13 + . 141",
        "Solution": "((58 + (4 / 1000)) + (141 / 1000)) = 58.144999999999996"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 126 + . 115 + . 72",
        "Solution": "((126 + (4 / 1000)) + (72 / 1000)) = 126.07600000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 53 + . 280 + . 45",
        "Solution": "((53 + (4 / 1000)) + (45 / 1000)) = 53.049"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 217 + . 17 + . 16",
        "Solution": "((217 + (4 / 1000)) + (16 / 1000)) = 217.01999999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 48 + . 112 + . 120",
        "Solution": "((48 + (4 / 1000)) + (120 / 1000)) = 48.123999999999995"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 259 + . 14 + . 288",
        "Solution": "((259 + (4 / 1000)) + (288 / 1000)) = 259.29200000000003"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 102 + . 280 + . 215",
        "Solution": "((102 + (4 / 1000)) + (215 / 1000)) = 102.21900000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 113 + . 230 + . 143",
        "Solution": "((113 + (4 / 1000)) + (143 / 1000)) = 113.147"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 4 + . 82 + . 217",
        "Solution": "((4 + (4 / 1000)) + (217 / 1000)) = 4.220999999999999"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "solution for 175 + . 143 + . 80",
        "Solution": "((175 + (4 / 1000)) + (80 / 1000)) = 175.084"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 58",
        "Solution": "((6 - 58) / 6) = -8.666666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 13",
        "Solution": "((6 - 13) / 6) = -1.1666666666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 141",
        "Solution": "((6 - 141) / 6) = -22.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 126",
        "Solution": "((6 - 126) / 6) = -20.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 115",
        "Solution": "((6 - 115) / 6) = -18.166666666666668"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 72",
        "Solution": "((6 - 72) / 6) = -11.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 53",
        "Solution": "((6 - 53) / 6) = -7.833333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 280",
        "Solution": "((6 - 280) / 6) = -45.666666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 45",
        "Solution": "((6 - 45) / 6) = -6.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a throw of dice what is the probability of ge \u00e6 \u00ab ng number greater than 217",
        "Solution": "((6 - 217) / 6) = -35.166666666666664"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 58 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 13 kgs more for rs . 141 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((141 * 58) / 100) / 13) = 6.2907692307692304"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 126 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 115 kgs more for rs . 72 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((72 * 126) / 100) / 115) = 0.7888695652173913"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 53 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 280 kgs more for rs . 45 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 53) / 100) / 280) = 0.08517857142857144"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 217 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 17 kgs more for rs . 16 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((16 * 217) / 100) / 17) = 2.0423529411764707"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 48 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 112 kgs more for rs . 120 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((120 * 48) / 100) / 112) = 0.5142857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 259 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 14 kgs more for rs . 288 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((288 * 259) / 100) / 14) = 53.279999999999994"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 102 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 280 kgs more for rs . 215 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((215 * 102) / 100) / 280) = 0.7832142857142858"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 113 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 230 kgs more for rs . 143 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 113) / 100) / 230) = 0.7025652173913044"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 4 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 82 kgs more for rs . 217 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 4) / 100) / 82) = 0.10585365853658536"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a reduction of 175 % in the price of oil enables a house wife to obtain 143 kgs more for rs . 80 , what is the reduced price for kg ?",
        "Solution": "(((80 * 175) / 100) / 143) = 0.9790209790209791"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 58 13 / 58 m * 58 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 141 m long and 126 13 / 58 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((141 * (126 + (13 / 58))) / ((58 + (13 / 58)) * 58)) = 5.270240878968274"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 115 72 / 115 m * 115 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 53 m long and 280 72 / 115 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * (280 + (72 / 115))) / ((115 + (72 / 115)) * 115)) = 1.11853670818197"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 45 217 / 45 m * 45 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 17 m long and 16 217 / 45 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * (16 + (217 / 45))) / ((45 + (217 / 45)) * 45)) = 0.15788482505699275"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 48 112 / 48 m * 48 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 120 m long and 259 112 / 48 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((120 * (259 + (112 / 48))) / ((48 + (112 / 48)) * 48)) = 12.980132450331125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 14 288 / 14 m * 14 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 102 m long and 280 288 / 14 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * (280 + (288 / 14))) / ((14 + (288 / 14)) * 14)) = 63.3435655253837"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 215 113 / 215 m * 215 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 230 m long and 143 113 / 215 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((230 * (143 + (113 / 215))) / ((215 + (113 / 215)) * 215)) = 0.7123933644294149"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 4 82 / 4 m * 4 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 217 m long and 175 82 / 4 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * (175 + (82 / 4))) / ((4 + (82 / 4)) * 4)) = 432.89285714285717"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 143 80 / 143 m * 143 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 111 m long and 173 80 / 143 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((111 * (173 + (80 / 143))) / ((143 + (80 / 143)) * 143)) = 0.9384333334355255"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 53 48 / 53 m * 53 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 195 m long and 50 48 / 53 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((195 * (50 + (48 / 53))) / ((53 + (48 / 53)) * 53)) = 3.4744850450069675"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many paying stones , each measuring 184 177 / 184 m * 184 m are required to pave a rectangular court yard 136 m long and 23 177 / 184 m board ?",
        "Solution": "((136 * (23 + (177 / 184))) / ((184 + (177 / 184)) * 184)) = 0.09575488751965802"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 13 : 141 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 126 : 13 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((126 + 13) * ((58 * 13) / (13 + 141))) / 126) * 13) / (126 + 13)) - ((58 * 141) / (13 + 141))) = -52.59874252731396"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 72 : 53 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 280 : 72 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((280 + 72) * ((115 * 72) / (72 + 53))) / 280) * 72) / (280 + 72)) - ((115 * 53) / (72 + 53))) = -31.726857142857142"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 217 : 17 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 16 : 217 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((16 + 217) * ((45 * 217) / (217 + 17))) / 16) * 217) / (16 + 217)) - ((45 * 17) / (217 + 17))) = 562.7043269230771"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 112 : 120 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 259 : 112 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((259 + 112) * ((48 * 112) / (112 + 120))) / 259) * 112) / (259 + 112)) - ((48 * 120) / (112 + 120))) = -14.80708294501398"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "14 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 288 : 102 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 280 : 288 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((280 + 288) * ((14 * 288) / (288 + 102))) / 280) * 288) / (280 + 288)) - ((14 * 102) / (288 + 102))) = 6.972307692307691"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "215 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 113 : 230 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 143 : 113 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((143 + 113) * ((215 * 113) / (113 + 230))) / 143) * 113) / (143 + 113)) - ((215 * 230) / (113 + 230))) = -88.1978225855777"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "4 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 82 : 217 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 175 : 82 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((175 + 82) * ((4 * 82) / (82 + 217))) / 175) * 82) / (175 + 82)) - ((4 * 217) / (82 + 217))) = -2.3889918776875296"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "143 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 80 : 111 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 173 : 80 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((173 + 80) * ((143 * 80) / (80 + 111))) / 173) * 80) / (173 + 80)) - ((143 * 111) / (80 + 111))) = -55.40746905547317"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 48 : 195 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 50 : 48 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((50 + 48) * ((53 * 48) / (48 + 195))) / 50) * 48) / (50 + 48)) - ((53 * 195) / (48 + 195))) = -32.4804938271605"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "184 liters of a mixture is created by mixing liquid p and liquid q in the ratio 177 : 136 . how many liters of liquid q must be added to make the ratio 23 : 177 ?",
        "Solution": "((((((23 + 177) * ((184 * 177) / (177 + 136))) / 23) * 177) / (23 + 177)) - ((184 * 136) / (177 + 136))) = 720.7923322683707"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 58 in 13 years at the rate of 141 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(58 / (((141 / 100) + 1) ** 13)) = 0.000626911793790963"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 126 in 115 years at the rate of 72 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(126 / (((72 / 100) + 1) ** 115)) = 1.0341871821074653e-25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 53 in 280 years at the rate of 45 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(53 / (((45 / 100) + 1) ** 280)) = 3.4772446196197296e-44"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 217 in 17 years at the rate of 16 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / (((16 / 100) + 1) ** 17)) = 17.404995566362476"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 48 in 112 years at the rate of 120 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(48 / (((120 / 100) + 1) ** 112)) = 2.137474711516487e-37"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 259 in 14 years at the rate of 288 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(259 / (((288 / 100) + 1) ** 14)) = 1.4779359245394502e-06"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 102 in 280 years at the rate of 215 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(102 / (((215 / 100) + 1) ** 280)) = 3.031413013632576e-138"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 113 in 230 years at the rate of 143 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(113 / (((143 / 100) + 1) ** 230)) = 2.31012519059786e-87"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 4 in 82 years at the rate of 217 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(4 / (((217 / 100) + 1) ** 82)) = 3.2749184465561613e-41"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sum amounts to rs . 175 in 143 years at the rate of 80 % p . a . if interest was compounded yearly then what was the principal ?",
        "Solution": "(175 / (((80 / 100) + 1) ** 143)) = 5.48365115198586e-35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 58 per car , every liter of fuel costs 13 $ . assuming that a company owns 141 cars and that every fuel tank contains 126 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((13 * 126) * 141) = 230958"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 115 per car , every liter of fuel costs 72 $ . assuming that a company owns 53 cars and that every fuel tank contains 280 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((72 * 280) * 53) = 1068480"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 45 per car , every liter of fuel costs 217 $ . assuming that a company owns 17 cars and that every fuel tank contains 16 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * 16) * 17) = 59024"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 48 per car , every liter of fuel costs 112 $ . assuming that a company owns 120 cars and that every fuel tank contains 259 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((112 * 259) * 120) = 3480960"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 14 per car , every liter of fuel costs 288 $ . assuming that a company owns 102 cars and that every fuel tank contains 280 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((288 * 280) * 102) = 8225280"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 215 per car , every liter of fuel costs 113 $ . assuming that a company owns 230 cars and that every fuel tank contains 143 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((113 * 143) * 230) = 3716570"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 4 per car , every liter of fuel costs 82 $ . assuming that a company owns 217 cars and that every fuel tank contains 175 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((82 * 175) * 217) = 3113950"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 143 per car , every liter of fuel costs 80 $ . assuming that a company owns 111 cars and that every fuel tank contains 173 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((80 * 173) * 111) = 1536240"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 53 per car , every liter of fuel costs 48 $ . assuming that a company owns 195 cars and that every fuel tank contains 50 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * 50) * 195) = 468000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a fuel station the service costs $ 184 per car , every liter of fuel costs 177 $ . assuming that a company owns 136 cars and that every fuel tank contains 23 liters and they are all empty , how much money total will it cost to fuel all cars ?",
        "Solution": "((177 * 23) * 136) = 553656"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 58 days , but 13 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 141 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((13 * 141) / (141 - 58)) = 22.08433734939759"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 126 days , but 115 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 72 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * 72) / (72 - 126)) = -153.33333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 53 days , but 280 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 45 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 45) / (45 - 53)) = -1575.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 217 days , but 17 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 16 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 16) / (16 - 217)) = -1.3532338308457712"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 48 days , but 112 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 120 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((112 * 120) / (120 - 48)) = 186.66666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 259 days , but 14 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 288 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * 288) / (288 - 259)) = 139.0344827586207"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 102 days , but 280 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 215 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 215) / (215 - 102)) = 532.7433628318585"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 113 days , but 230 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 143 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((230 * 143) / (143 - 113)) = 1096.3333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 4 days , but 82 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 217 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((82 * 217) / (217 - 4)) = 83.53990610328638"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a group of men decided to do a work in 175 days , but 143 of them became absent . if the rest of the group did the work in 80 days , find the original number of men ?",
        "Solution": "((143 * 80) / (80 - 175)) = -120.42105263157895"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 58 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 13 % . if c pays $ 141 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(141 / ((1 + (58 / 100)) * (1 + (13 / 100)))) = 78.97389940629552"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 126 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 115 % . if c pays $ 72 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(72 / ((1 + (126 / 100)) * (1 + (115 / 100)))) = 14.817863757974894"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 53 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 280 % . if c pays $ 45 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(45 / ((1 + (53 / 100)) * (1 + (280 / 100)))) = 7.739938080495356"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 217 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 17 % . if c pays $ 16 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(16 / ((1 + (217 / 100)) * (1 + (17 / 100)))) = 4.313947531613147"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 48 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 112 % . if c pays $ 120 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(120 / ((1 + (48 / 100)) * (1 + (112 / 100)))) = 38.2457929627741"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 259 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 14 % . if c pays $ 288 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(288 / ((1 + (259 / 100)) * (1 + (14 / 100)))) = 70.37091335581293"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 102 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 280 % . if c pays $ 215 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(215 / ((1 + (102 / 100)) * (1 + (280 / 100)))) = 28.00937988535696"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 113 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 230 % . if c pays $ 143 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(143 / ((1 + (113 / 100)) * (1 + (230 / 100)))) = 20.344287949921757"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 4 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 82 % . if c pays $ 217 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(217 / ((1 + (4 / 100)) * (1 + (82 / 100)))) = 114.6449704142012"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a sells a cricket bat to b at a profit of 175 % . b sells it to c at a profit of 143 % . if c pays $ 80 for it , the cost price of the cricket bat for a is :",
        "Solution": "(80 / ((1 + (175 / 100)) * (1 + (143 / 100)))) = 11.971567527123083"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 58 percent of the population are employed , and 13 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 - 13) / 58) * 100) = 77.58620689655173"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 141 percent of the population are employed , and 126 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((141 - 126) / 141) * 100) = 10.638297872340425"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 115 percent of the population are employed , and 72 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 - 72) / 115) * 100) = 37.391304347826086"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 53 percent of the population are employed , and 280 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 - 280) / 53) * 100) = -428.3018867924528"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 45 percent of the population are employed , and 217 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 - 217) / 45) * 100) = -382.22222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 17 percent of the population are employed , and 16 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((17 - 16) / 17) * 100) = 5.88235294117647"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 48 percent of the population are employed , and 112 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 - 112) / 48) * 100) = -133.33333333333331"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 120 percent of the population are employed , and 259 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((120 - 259) / 120) * 100) = -115.83333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 14 percent of the population are employed , and 288 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 - 288) / 14) * 100) = -1957.1428571428573"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in town x , 102 percent of the population are employed , and 280 percent of the population are employed males . what percent of the employed people in town x are females ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 - 280) / 102) * 100) = -174.50980392156862"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 58 boggies , each boggy 13 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 141 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 13) - 13) / ((58 * 13) / 141)) = 138.56896551724137"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 126 boggies , each boggy 115 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 72 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((126 * 115) - 115) / ((126 * 115) / 72)) = 71.42857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 53 boggies , each boggy 280 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 45 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 280) - 280) / ((53 * 280) / 45)) = 44.15094339622642"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 217 boggies , each boggy 17 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 16 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 17) - 17) / ((217 * 17) / 16)) = 15.926267281105991"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 48 boggies , each boggy 112 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 120 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 112) - 112) / ((48 * 112) / 120)) = 117.50000000000001"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 259 boggies , each boggy 14 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 288 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((259 * 14) - 14) / ((259 * 14) / 288)) = 286.88803088803087"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 102 boggies , each boggy 280 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 215 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((102 * 280) - 280) / ((102 * 280) / 215)) = 212.89215686274508"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 113 boggies , each boggy 230 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 143 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((113 * 230) - 230) / ((113 * 230) / 143)) = 141.73451327433628"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 4 boggies , each boggy 82 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 217 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 82) - 82) / ((4 * 82) / 217)) = 162.75"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train consists of 175 boggies , each boggy 143 metres long . the train crosses a telegraph post in 80 seconds . due to some problem , one boggies were detached . the train now crosses a telegraph post in",
        "Solution": "(((175 * 143) - 143) / ((175 * 143) / 80)) = 79.54285714285714"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 58 to b for 13 years and rs . 141 to c for 126 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 115 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((115 / ((58 * 13) + (141 * 126))) * 100) = 0.6209503239740821"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 72 to b for 53 years and rs . 280 to c for 45 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 217 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((217 / ((72 * 53) + (280 * 45))) * 100) = 1.3218810916179335"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 17 to b for 16 years and rs . 48 to c for 112 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 120 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((120 / ((17 * 16) + (48 * 112))) * 100) = 2.1246458923512748"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 259 to b for 14 years and rs . 288 to c for 102 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 280 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((280 / ((259 * 14) + (288 * 102))) * 100) = 0.848433428277074"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 215 to b for 113 years and rs . 230 to c for 143 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 4 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((4 / ((215 * 113) + (230 * 143))) * 100) = 0.006994841304537903"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 82 to b for 217 years and rs . 175 to c for 143 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 80 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((80 / ((82 * 217) + (175 * 143))) * 100) = 0.18683294799037808"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 111 to b for 173 years and rs . 53 to c for 48 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 195 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((195 / ((111 * 173) + (53 * 48))) * 100) = 0.8966754035039316"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 50 to b for 184 years and rs . 177 to c for 136 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 23 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((23 / ((50 * 184) + (177 * 136))) * 100) = 0.06912719403702813"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 236 to b for 275 years and rs . 64 to c for 194 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 41 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((41 / ((236 * 275) + (64 * 194))) * 100) = 0.05302912721816959"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a lent rs . 283 to b for 151 years and rs . 186 to c for 296 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received rs . 99 in all from both of them as interest . the rate of interest per annum is ?",
        "Solution": "((99 / ((283 * 151) + (186 * 296))) * 100) = 0.10123838059495445"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 58 to 13 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 141 ?",
        "Solution": "((13 / 141) / 13) = 0.0070921985815602835"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 126 to 115 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 72 ?",
        "Solution": "((115 / 72) / 115) = 0.01388888888888889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 53 to 280 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 45 ?",
        "Solution": "((280 / 45) / 280) = 0.022222222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 217 to 17 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 16 ?",
        "Solution": "((17 / 16) / 17) = 0.0625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 48 to 112 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 120 ?",
        "Solution": "((112 / 120) / 112) = 0.008333333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 259 to 14 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 288 ?",
        "Solution": "((14 / 288) / 14) = 0.0034722222222222225"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 102 to 280 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 215 ?",
        "Solution": "((280 / 215) / 280) = 0.004651162790697674"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 113 to 230 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 143 ?",
        "Solution": "((230 / 143) / 230) = 0.006993006993006993"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 4 to 82 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 217 ?",
        "Solution": "((82 / 217) / 82) = 0.004608294930875576"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "tickets numbered from 175 to 143 are mixed and then a ticket is selected randomly . what is the probability that the selected ticket bears a number which is a multiple of 80 ?",
        "Solution": "((143 / 80) / 143) = 0.0125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 58 % of the total boys are from school a and 13 % of those study science . if there are 141 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(141 / (((100 - 13) / 100) * (58 / 100))) = 279.4292508917955"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 126 % of the total boys are from school a and 115 % of those study science . if there are 72 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(72 / (((100 - 115) / 100) * (126 / 100))) = -380.95238095238096"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 53 % of the total boys are from school a and 280 % of those study science . if there are 45 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(45 / (((100 - 280) / 100) * (53 / 100))) = -47.16981132075471"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 217 % of the total boys are from school a and 17 % of those study science . if there are 16 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(16 / (((100 - 17) / 100) * (217 / 100))) = 8.883460107711954"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 48 % of the total boys are from school a and 112 % of those study science . if there are 120 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / (((100 - 112) / 100) * (48 / 100))) = -2083.3333333333335"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 259 % of the total boys are from school a and 14 % of those study science . if there are 288 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(288 / (((100 - 14) / 100) * (259 / 100))) = 129.29873394989676"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 102 % of the total boys are from school a and 280 % of those study science . if there are 215 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(215 / (((100 - 280) / 100) * (102 / 100))) = -117.10239651416121"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 113 % of the total boys are from school a and 230 % of those study science . if there are 143 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(143 / (((100 - 230) / 100) * (113 / 100))) = -97.34513274336284"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 4 % of the total boys are from school a and 82 % of those study science . if there are 217 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / (((100 - 82) / 100) * (4 / 100))) = 30138.88888888889"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a certain boys camp , 175 % of the total boys are from school a and 143 % of those study science . if there are 80 boys in the camp that are from school a but do not study science then what is the total number of boys in the camp ?",
        "Solution": "(80 / (((100 - 143) / 100) * (175 / 100))) = -106.312292358804"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 58 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 13 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 141 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 58 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((141 / 13) + 58) / 13) * 2) - 13) - 3)) = -0.18490153172866516"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 126 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 115 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 72 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 126 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((72 / 115) + 126) / 115) * 2) - 115) - 3)) = -0.008635742112253547"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 53 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 280 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 45 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 53 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((45 / 280) + 53) / 280) * 2) - 280) - 3)) = -0.003538316492481303"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 217 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 17 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 16 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 217 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((16 / 17) + 217) / 17) * 2) - 17) - 3)) = 0.17730061349693252"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 48 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 112 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 120 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 48 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((120 / 112) + 48) / 112) * 2) - 112) - 3)) = -0.008762419947917249"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 259 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 14 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 288 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 259 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((288 / 14) + 259) / 14) * 2) - 14) - 3)) = 0.04359430604982206"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 102 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 280 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 215 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 102 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((215 / 280) + 102) / 280) * 2) - 280) - 3)) = -0.0035427582451597744"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 113 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 230 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 143 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 113 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((143 / 230) + 113) / 230) * 2) - 230) - 3)) = -0.004310122171186972"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 4 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 82 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 217 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 4 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((217 / 82) + 4) / 82) * 2) - 82) - 3)) = -0.01178718555526339"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a certain list consists of 175 different numbers . if n is in the list and n is 143 times the average ( arithmetic mean ) of the other 80 numbers in the list , then n is what fraction of the sum of the 175 numbers in the list ?",
        "Solution": "((1 * 1) / ((((((80 / 143) + 175) / 143) * 2) - 143) - 3)) = -0.00696647479818379"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 58 men whose average weight is increased by 13 kg when 13 man of 141 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(141 + 58) = 199"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 126 men whose average weight is increased by 115 kg when 115 man of 72 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(72 + 126) = 198"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 53 men whose average weight is increased by 280 kg when 280 man of 45 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(45 + 53) = 98"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 217 men whose average weight is increased by 17 kg when 17 man of 16 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(16 + 217) = 233"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 48 men whose average weight is increased by 112 kg when 112 man of 120 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(120 + 48) = 168"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 259 men whose average weight is increased by 14 kg when 14 man of 288 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(288 + 259) = 547"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 102 men whose average weight is increased by 280 kg when 280 man of 215 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(215 + 102) = 317"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 113 men whose average weight is increased by 230 kg when 230 man of 143 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(143 + 113) = 256"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 4 men whose average weight is increased by 82 kg when 82 man of 217 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(217 + 4) = 221"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "in a boat there are 175 men whose average weight is increased by 143 kg when 143 man of 80 kg is replaced by a new man . what is weight of new comer ?",
        "Solution": "(80 + 175) = 255"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 58 : 13 . after 141 years their ratio is 13 : 141 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 * 141) * 13) / 141) - (13 * 13)) = 585.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 126 : 115 . after 72 years their ratio is 115 : 72 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((126 * 72) * 115) / 72) - (115 * 115)) = 1265.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 53 : 280 . after 45 years their ratio is 280 : 45 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 * 45) * 280) / 45) - (280 * 280)) = -63560.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 217 : 17 . after 16 years their ratio is 17 : 16 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((217 * 16) * 17) / 16) - (17 * 17)) = 3400.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 48 : 112 . after 120 years their ratio is 112 : 120 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((48 * 120) * 112) / 120) - (112 * 112)) = -7168.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 259 : 14 . after 288 years their ratio is 14 : 288 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((259 * 288) * 14) / 288) - (14 * 14)) = 3430.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 102 : 280 . after 215 years their ratio is 280 : 215 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((102 * 215) * 280) / 215) - (280 * 280)) = -49840.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 113 : 230 . after 143 years their ratio is 230 : 143 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((113 * 143) * 230) / 143) - (230 * 230)) = -26910.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 4 : 82 . after 217 years their ratio is 82 : 217 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((4 * 217) * 82) / 217) - (82 * 82)) = -6396.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the ratio of a and b is 175 : 143 . after 80 years their ratio is 143 : 80 . what is the age of b ?",
        "Solution": "((((175 * 80) * 143) / 80) - (143 * 143)) = 4576.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 58 a . m . at a speed of 13 kmph . another train leaves at 141 p . m . at a speed of 126 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((13 * (3 + 141)) / (126 - 13)) * 126) = 2087.3628318584074"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 115 a . m . at a speed of 72 kmph . another train leaves at 53 p . m . at a speed of 280 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((72 * (3 + 53)) / (280 - 72)) * 280) = 5427.692307692308"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 45 a . m . at a speed of 217 kmph . another train leaves at 17 p . m . at a speed of 16 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * (3 + 17)) / (16 - 217)) * 16) = -345.4726368159204"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 48 a . m . at a speed of 112 kmph . another train leaves at 120 p . m . at a speed of 259 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((112 * (3 + 120)) / (259 - 112)) * 259) = 24272.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 14 a . m . at a speed of 288 kmph . another train leaves at 102 p . m . at a speed of 280 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((288 * (3 + 102)) / (280 - 288)) * 280) = -1058400.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 215 a . m . at a speed of 113 kmph . another train leaves at 230 p . m . at a speed of 143 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((113 * (3 + 230)) / (143 - 113)) * 143) = 125501.56666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 4 a . m . at a speed of 82 kmph . another train leaves at 217 p . m . at a speed of 175 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((82 * (3 + 217)) / (175 - 82)) * 175) = 33946.23655913978"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 143 a . m . at a speed of 80 kmph . another train leaves at 111 p . m . at a speed of 173 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((80 * (3 + 111)) / (173 - 80)) * 173) = 16965.16129032258"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 53 a . m . at a speed of 48 kmph . another train leaves at 195 p . m . at a speed of 50 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * (3 + 195)) / (50 - 48)) * 50) = 237600.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a train leaves delhi at 184 a . m . at a speed of 177 kmph . another train leaves at 136 p . m . at a speed of 23 kmph on the same day and in the same direction . how far from delhi , will the two trains meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((177 * (3 + 136)) / (23 - 177)) * 23) = -3674.474025974026"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 58 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 13 rainy days from july 141 through july 126 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(141 * ((1 / 2) ** 141)) = 5.05812693682686e-41"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 115 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 72 rainy days from july 53 through july 280 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(53 * ((1 / 2) ** 53)) = 5.88418203051333e-15"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 45 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 217 rainy days from july 17 through july 16 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(17 * ((1 / 2) ** 17)) = 0.00012969970703125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 48 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 112 rainy days from july 120 through july 259 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(120 * ((1 / 2) ** 120)) = 9.027796614315168e-35"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 14 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 288 rainy days from july 102 through july 280 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(102 * ((1 / 2) ** 102)) = 2.01159530831358e-29"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 215 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 113 rainy days from july 230 through july 143 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(230 * ((1 / 2) ** 230)) = 1.332995960403292e-67"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 4 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 82 rainy days from july 217 through july 175 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(217 * ((1 / 2) ** 217)) = 1.0302691004149382e-63"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 143 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 80 rainy days from july 111 through july 173 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(111 * ((1 / 2) ** 111)) = 4.2755644765396636e-32"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 53 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 48 rainy days from july 195 through july 50 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(195 * ((1 / 2) ** 195)) = 3.8831615333853524e-57"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the probability of rain on any given day in chicago during the summer is 184 % , independent of what happens on any other day , what is the probability of having exactly 177 rainy days from july 136 through july 23 , inclusive ?",
        "Solution": "(136 * ((1 / 2) ** 136)) = 1.5612034346858506e-39"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 58 cm & breadth is increased by 58 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 13 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((13 + (58 * 58)) / ((2 * 58) - 58))) = 116.44827586206897"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 141 cm & breadth is increased by 141 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 126 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((126 + (141 * 141)) / ((2 * 141) - 141))) = 283.78723404255317"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 115 cm & breadth is increased by 115 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 72 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((72 + (115 * 115)) / ((2 * 115) - 115))) = 231.2521739130435"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 53 cm & breadth is increased by 53 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 280 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((280 + (53 * 53)) / ((2 * 53) - 53))) = 116.56603773584905"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 45 cm & breadth is increased by 45 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 217 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((217 + (45 * 45)) / ((2 * 45) - 45))) = 99.64444444444445"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 17 cm & breadth is increased by 17 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 16 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((16 + (17 * 17)) / ((2 * 17) - 17))) = 35.88235294117647"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 48 cm & breadth is increased by 48 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 112 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((112 + (48 * 48)) / ((2 * 48) - 48))) = 100.66666666666667"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 120 cm & breadth is increased by 120 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 259 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((259 + (120 * 120)) / ((2 * 120) - 120))) = 244.31666666666666"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 14 cm & breadth is increased by 14 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 288 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((288 + (14 * 14)) / ((2 * 14) - 14))) = 69.14285714285714"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the length of a rectangle is twice its breadth . if its lengthis decreased by 102 cm & breadth is increased by 102 cm , the area of the rectangle is increased by 280 sq . cm . what is the length of the rectangle ?",
        "Solution": "(2 * ((280 + (102 * 102)) / ((2 * 102) - 102))) = 209.49019607843138"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 58 / 13 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 141 ?",
        "Solution": "((141 + ((58 / 13) * 141)) + ((58 / 13) * (141 + ((58 / 13) * 141)))) = 4205.804733727811"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 126 / 115 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 72 ?",
        "Solution": "((72 + ((126 / 115) * 72)) + ((126 / 115) * (72 + ((126 / 115) * 72)))) = 316.20657844990546"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 53 / 280 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 45 ?",
        "Solution": "((45 + ((53 / 280) * 45)) + ((53 / 280) * (45 + ((53 / 280) * 45)))) = 63.64802295918367"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 217 / 17 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 16 ?",
        "Solution": "((16 + ((217 / 17) * 16)) + ((217 / 17) * (16 + ((217 / 17) * 16)))) = 3031.4740484429067"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 48 / 112 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 120 ?",
        "Solution": "((120 + ((48 / 112) * 120)) + ((48 / 112) * (120 + ((48 / 112) * 120)))) = 244.89795918367344"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 259 / 14 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 288 ?",
        "Solution": "((288 + ((259 / 14) * 288)) + ((259 / 14) * (288 + ((259 / 14) * 288)))) = 109512.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 102 / 280 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 215 ?",
        "Solution": "((215 + ((102 / 280) * 215)) + ((102 / 280) * (215 + ((102 / 280) * 215)))) = 400.1742346938775"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 113 / 230 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 143 ?",
        "Solution": "((143 + ((113 / 230) * 143)) + ((113 / 230) * (143 + ((113 / 230) * 143)))) = 318.03037807183364"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 4 / 82 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 217 ?",
        "Solution": "((217 + ((4 / 82) * 217)) + ((4 / 82) * (217 + ((4 / 82) * 217)))) = 238.68709101725165"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "every year an amount increases by 175 / 143 th of itself . how much will it be after two years if its present value is rs . 80 ?",
        "Solution": "((80 + ((175 / 143) * 80)) + ((175 / 143) * (80 + ((175 / 143) * 80)))) = 395.6144554745953"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 58 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 13 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 141 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 13) + 141) / 58) = 15.431034482758621"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 126 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 115 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 72 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 * 115) + 72) / 126) = 115.57142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 53 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 280 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 45 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 280) + 45) / 53) = 280.8490566037736"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 217 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 17 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 16 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 17) + 16) / 217) = 17.07373271889401"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 48 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 112 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 120 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 112) + 120) / 48) = 114.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 259 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 14 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 288 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((259 * 14) + 288) / 259) = 15.111969111969112"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 102 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 280 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 215 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 * 280) + 215) / 102) = 282.1078431372549"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 113 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 230 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 143 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((113 * 230) + 143) / 113) = 231.26548672566372"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 4 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 82 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 217 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 82) + 217) / 4) = 136.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "set s contains exactly 175 numbers and has an average ( arithmetic mean ) of 143 . if one of the numbers in set s is increased by 80 , while all other numbers remain the same , what is the new average of set s ?",
        "Solution": "(((175 * 143) + 80) / 175) = 143.45714285714286"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 58 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 58 candies for the discounted price of 13 candies . the store still makes a profit of 141 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((141 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (58 / 100)) * ((58 - 13) / 58))) - 1) * 100) = 639.5767195767196"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 126 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 126 candies for the discounted price of 115 candies . the store still makes a profit of 72 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((72 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (126 / 100)) * ((126 - 115) / 126))) - 1) * 100) = -7677.622377622377"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 53 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 53 candies for the discounted price of 280 candies . the store still makes a profit of 45 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((45 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (53 / 100)) * ((53 - 280) / 53))) - 1) * 100) = -172.03111819289532"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 217 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 217 candies for the discounted price of 17 candies . the store still makes a profit of 16 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((16 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (217 / 100)) * ((217 - 17) / 217))) - 1) * 100) = -207.5726495726496"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 48 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 48 candies for the discounted price of 112 candies . the store still makes a profit of 120 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((120 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (48 / 100)) * ((48 - 112) / 48))) - 1) * 100) = -417.3076923076923"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 259 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 259 candies for the discounted price of 14 candies . the store still makes a profit of 288 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((288 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (259 / 100)) * ((259 - 14) / 259))) - 1) * 100) = -357.9694519317161"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 102 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 102 candies for the discounted price of 280 candies . the store still makes a profit of 215 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((215 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (102 / 100)) * ((102 - 280) / 102))) - 1) * 100) = 8925.280898876395"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 113 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 113 candies for the discounted price of 230 candies . the store still makes a profit of 143 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((143 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (113 / 100)) * ((113 - 230) / 113))) - 1) * 100) = 1705.3254437869832"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 4 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 4 candies for the discounted price of 82 candies . the store still makes a profit of 217 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((217 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (4 / 100)) * ((4 - 82) / 4))) - 1) * 100) = -116.9337606837607"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "during a sale of 175 % on everything in a store , a kid is successful in convincing the store manager to give him 175 candies for the discounted price of 143 candies . the store still makes a profit of 80 % on this sale . what is the mark up percentage on each candy ?",
        "Solution": "(((((80 / 100) + 1) / ((1 - (175 / 100)) * ((175 - 143) / 175))) - 1) * 100) = -1412.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 58 between 13 and 141 .",
        "Solution": "(141 / (58 * 13)) = 0.1870026525198939"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 126 between 115 and 72 .",
        "Solution": "(72 / (126 * 115)) = 0.004968944099378882"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 53 between 280 and 45 .",
        "Solution": "(45 / (53 * 280)) = 0.003032345013477089"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 217 between 17 and 16 .",
        "Solution": "(16 / (217 * 17)) = 0.00433721875847113"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 48 between 112 and 120 .",
        "Solution": "(120 / (48 * 112)) = 0.022321428571428572"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 259 between 14 and 288 .",
        "Solution": "(288 / (259 * 14)) = 0.07942636514065085"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 102 between 280 and 215 .",
        "Solution": "(215 / (102 * 280)) = 0.007528011204481793"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 113 between 230 and 143 .",
        "Solution": "(143 / (113 * 230)) = 0.005502116198537899"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 4 between 82 and 217 .",
        "Solution": "(217 / (4 * 82)) = 0.6615853658536586"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many numbers are divisible by 175 between 143 and 80 .",
        "Solution": "(80 / (175 * 143)) = 0.003196803196803197"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 58 km / hr instead of 13 km / hr , he would have walked 141 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(13 * (141 / (58 - 13))) = 40.733333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 126 km / hr instead of 115 km / hr , he would have walked 72 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(115 * (72 / (126 - 115))) = 752.7272727272727"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 53 km / hr instead of 280 km / hr , he would have walked 45 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(280 * (45 / (53 - 280))) = -55.50660792951541"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 217 km / hr instead of 17 km / hr , he would have walked 16 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(17 * (16 / (217 - 17))) = 1.36"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 48 km / hr instead of 112 km / hr , he would have walked 120 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(112 * (120 / (48 - 112))) = -210.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 259 km / hr instead of 14 km / hr , he would have walked 288 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(14 * (288 / (259 - 14))) = 16.45714285714286"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 102 km / hr instead of 280 km / hr , he would have walked 215 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(280 * (215 / (102 - 280))) = -338.2022471910112"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 113 km / hr instead of 230 km / hr , he would have walked 143 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(230 * (143 / (113 - 230))) = -281.11111111111114"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 4 km / hr instead of 82 km / hr , he would have walked 217 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(82 * (217 / (4 - 82))) = -228.1282051282051"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if a person walks at 175 km / hr instead of 143 km / hr , he would have walked 80 km more . what is the actual distance travelled by him ?",
        "Solution": "(143 * (80 / (175 - 143))) = 357.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 58,13 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 141 , 13 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((141 * 100) * 10)) = 1.702127659574468"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 126,115 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 72 , 115 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((72 * 100) * 10)) = 3.3333333333333335"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 53,280 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 45 , 280 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((45 * 100) * 10)) = 5.333333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 217,17 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 16 , 17 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((16 * 100) * 10)) = 15.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 48,112 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 120 , 112 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((120 * 100) * 10)) = 2.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 259,14 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 288 , 14 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((288 * 100) * 10)) = 0.8333333333333334"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 102,280 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 215 , 280 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((215 * 100) * 10)) = 1.1162790697674418"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 113,230 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 143 , 230 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((143 * 100) * 10)) = 1.6783216783216783"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 4,82 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 217 , 82 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((217 * 100) * 10)) = 1.1059907834101383"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "arjun started a business with rs . 175,143 and is joined afterwards by anoop with rs . 80 , 143 . after how many months did anoop join if the profits at the end of the year are divided equally ?",
        "Solution": "(((((4 * 100) * 100) * 12) - (((2 * 100) * 100) * 12)) / ((80 * 100) * 10)) = 3.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 \u00d7 13 = ?",
        "Solution": "((58 / 13) * 100) = 446.1538461538462"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "141 \u00d7 126 = ?",
        "Solution": "((141 / 126) * 100) = 111.90476190476191"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 \u00d7 72 = ?",
        "Solution": "((115 / 72) * 100) = 159.72222222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 \u00d7 280 = ?",
        "Solution": "((53 / 280) * 100) = 18.928571428571427"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 \u00d7 217 = ?",
        "Solution": "((45 / 217) * 100) = 20.737327188940093"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "17 \u00d7 16 = ?",
        "Solution": "((17 / 16) * 100) = 106.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 \u00d7 112 = ?",
        "Solution": "((48 / 112) * 100) = 42.857142857142854"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "120 \u00d7 259 = ?",
        "Solution": "((120 / 259) * 100) = 46.33204633204633"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "14 \u00d7 288 = ?",
        "Solution": "((14 / 288) * 100) = 4.861111111111112"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "102 \u00d7 280 = ?",
        "Solution": "((102 / 280) * 100) = 36.42857142857142"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 x 58 = ?",
        "Solution": "((58 / 58) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "13 x 13 = ?",
        "Solution": "((13 / 13) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "141 x 141 = ?",
        "Solution": "((141 / 141) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "126 x 126 = ?",
        "Solution": "((126 / 126) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 x 115 = ?",
        "Solution": "((115 / 115) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "72 x 72 = ?",
        "Solution": "((72 / 72) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 x 53 = ?",
        "Solution": "((53 / 53) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "280 x 280 = ?",
        "Solution": "((280 / 280) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 x 45 = ?",
        "Solution": "((45 / 45) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "217 x 217 = ?",
        "Solution": "((217 / 217) * 100) = 100.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 58 < x < 13 and y = x + 141 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((141 + 10) + 10) = 161"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 126 < x < 115 and y = x + 72 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((72 + 10) + 10) = 92"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 53 < x < 280 and y = x + 45 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((45 + 10) + 10) = 65"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 217 < x < 17 and y = x + 16 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((16 + 10) + 10) = 36"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 48 < x < 112 and y = x + 120 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((120 + 10) + 10) = 140"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 259 < x < 14 and y = x + 288 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((288 + 10) + 10) = 308"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 102 < x < 280 and y = x + 215 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((215 + 10) + 10) = 235"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 113 < x < 230 and y = x + 143 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((143 + 10) + 10) = 163"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 4 < x < 82 and y = x + 217 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((217 + 10) + 10) = 237"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if 175 < x < 143 and y = x + 80 , what is the greatest possible integer value of x + y ?",
        "Solution": "((80 + 10) + 10) = 100"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 58 kg of tea at 13 per kg with 141 kg of tea at cost price of 141 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 126 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((58 * 13) + (141 * 141)) / (58 + 141)) * 126) / 100) + (((58 * 13) + (141 * 141)) / (58 + 141))) = 234.34723618090453"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 115 kg of tea at 72 per kg with 53 kg of tea at cost price of 53 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 280 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((115 * 72) + (53 * 53)) / (115 + 53)) * 280) / 100) + (((115 * 72) + (53 * 53)) / (115 + 53))) = 250.82261904761907"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 45 kg of tea at 217 per kg with 17 kg of tea at cost price of 17 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 16 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((45 * 217) + (17 * 17)) / (45 + 17)) * 16) / 100) + (((45 * 217) + (17 * 17)) / (45 + 17))) = 188.10709677419354"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 48 kg of tea at 112 per kg with 120 kg of tea at cost price of 120 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 259 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((48 * 112) + (120 * 120)) / (48 + 120)) * 259) / 100) + (((48 * 112) + (120 * 120)) / (48 + 120))) = 422.5942857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 14 kg of tea at 288 per kg with 102 kg of tea at cost price of 102 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 280 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((14 * 288) + (102 * 102)) / (14 + 102)) * 280) / 100) + (((14 * 288) + (102 * 102)) / (14 + 102))) = 472.90344827586205"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 215 kg of tea at 113 per kg with 230 kg of tea at cost price of 230 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 143 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((215 * 113) + (230 * 230)) / (215 + 230)) * 143) / 100) + (((215 * 113) + (230 * 230)) / (215 + 230))) = 421.53674157303374"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 4 kg of tea at 82 per kg with 217 kg of tea at cost price of 217 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 175 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((4 * 82) + (217 * 217)) / (4 + 217)) * 175) / 100) + (((4 * 82) + (217 * 217)) / (4 + 217))) = 590.0305429864253"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 143 kg of tea at 80 per kg with 111 kg of tea at cost price of 111 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 173 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((143 * 80) + (111 * 111)) / (143 + 111)) * 173) / 100) + (((143 * 80) + (111 * 111)) / (143 + 111))) = 255.38397637795276"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 53 kg of tea at 48 per kg with 195 kg of tea at cost price of 195 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 50 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((53 * 48) + (195 * 195)) / (53 + 195)) * 50) / 100) + (((53 * 48) + (195 * 195)) / (53 + 195))) = 245.37701612903226"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a trader mixes 184 kg of tea at 177 per kg with 136 kg of tea at cost price of 136 per kg . in order to earn a profit of 23 % , what should be the sale price of the mixed tea ?",
        "Solution": "((((((184 * 177) + (136 * 136)) / (184 + 136)) * 23) / 100) + (((184 * 177) + (136 * 136)) / (184 + 136))) = 196.27724999999998"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 58 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 13 and 141 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((13 + 141) / (13 * 141)) = 0.08401527550463721"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 126 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 115 and 72 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((115 + 72) / (115 * 72)) = 0.022584541062801933"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 53 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 280 and 45 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((280 + 45) / (280 * 45)) = 0.025793650793650792"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 217 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 17 and 16 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((17 + 16) / (17 * 16)) = 0.1213235294117647"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 48 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 112 and 120 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((112 + 120) / (112 * 120)) = 0.017261904761904763"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 259 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 14 and 288 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((14 + 288) / (14 * 288)) = 0.07490079365079365"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 102 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 280 and 215 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((280 + 215) / (280 * 215)) = 0.008222591362126245"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 113 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 230 and 143 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((230 + 143) / (230 * 143)) = 0.011340833079963515"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 4 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 82 and 217 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((82 + 217) / (82 * 217)) = 0.01680341688209509"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the sum of two numbers is 175 and the h . c . f and l . c . m of these numbers are 143 and 80 respectively , then the sum of the reciprocal of the numbers is equal to :",
        "Solution": "((143 + 80) / (143 * 80)) = 0.019493006993006993"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 58 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 13 per bowl . he sold 141 of them at rs . 126 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((141 * 126) - (58 * 13)) / (58 * 13)) * 100) = 2256.233421750663"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 115 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 72 per bowl . he sold 53 of them at rs . 280 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 * 280) - (115 * 72)) / (115 * 72)) * 100) = 79.22705314009661"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 45 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 217 per bowl . he sold 17 of them at rs . 16 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((17 * 16) - (45 * 217)) / (45 * 217)) * 100) = -97.21454173067076"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 48 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 112 per bowl . he sold 120 of them at rs . 259 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((120 * 259) - (48 * 112)) / (48 * 112)) * 100) = 478.125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 14 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 288 per bowl . he sold 102 of them at rs . 280 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((102 * 280) - (14 * 288)) / (14 * 288)) * 100) = 608.3333333333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 215 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 113 per bowl . he sold 230 of them at rs . 143 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((230 * 143) - (215 * 113)) / (215 * 113)) * 100) = 35.37764972216505"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 4 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 82 per bowl . he sold 217 of them at rs . 175 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((217 * 175) - (4 * 82)) / (4 * 82)) * 100) = 11477.743902439024"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 143 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 80 per bowl . he sold 111 of them at rs . 173 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((111 * 173) - (143 * 80)) / (143 * 80)) * 100) = 67.85839160839161"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 53 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 48 per bowl . he sold 195 of them at rs . 50 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((195 * 50) - (53 * 48)) / (53 * 48)) * 100) = 283.2547169811321"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a person bought 184 glass bowls at a rate of rs . 177 per bowl . he sold 136 of them at rs . 23 and the remaining broke . what is the percentage gain for a ?",
        "Solution": "((((136 * 23) - (184 * 177)) / (184 * 177)) * 100) = -90.3954802259887"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 58 km / h , which is 13 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 141 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 4) + (((4 * 58) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (58 + ((4 * 58) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 126 km / h , which is 115 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 72 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 * 4) + (((4 * 126) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (126 + ((4 * 126) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 53 km / h , which is 280 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 45 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 4) + (((4 * 53) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (53 + ((4 * 53) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 217 km / h , which is 17 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 16 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 4) + (((4 * 217) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (217 + ((4 * 217) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 48 km / h , which is 112 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 120 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((48 * 4) + (((4 * 48) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (48 + ((4 * 48) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 259 km / h , which is 14 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 288 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((259 * 4) + (((4 * 259) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (259 + ((4 * 259) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 102 km / h , which is 280 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 215 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((102 * 4) + (((4 * 102) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (102 + ((4 * 102) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 113 km / h , which is 230 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 143 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((113 * 4) + (((4 * 113) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (113 + ((4 * 113) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 4 km / h , which is 82 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 217 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((4 * 4) + (((4 * 4) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (4 + ((4 * 4) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "two cars are driving toward each other . the first car is traveling at a speed of 175 km / h , which is 143 % slower than the second car ' s speed . if the distance between the cars is 80 km , how many hours will it take until the two cars meet ?",
        "Solution": "(((175 * 4) + (((4 * 175) / (1 + 4)) * 4)) / (175 + ((4 * 175) / (1 + 4)))) = 4.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 58 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((58 * 3) - (((58 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 29.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 13 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((13 * 3) - (((13 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 6.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 141 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((141 * 3) - (((141 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 70.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 126 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((126 * 3) - (((126 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 63.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 115 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 * 3) - (((115 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 57.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 72 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((72 * 3) - (((72 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 36.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 53 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((53 * 3) - (((53 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 26.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 280 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 * 3) - (((280 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 140.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 45 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((45 * 3) - (((45 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 22.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "by travelling at 217 kmph , a person reaches his destination on time . he covered two - third the total distance in one - third of the total time . what speed should he maintain for the remaining distance to reach his destination on time ?",
        "Solution": "(((217 * 3) - (((217 * 3) * 2) / 3)) / (3 - 1)) = 108.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 58 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 13 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 58 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 141,126 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 115 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 72 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 115 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 53,280 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 45 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 217 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 45 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 17,16 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 48 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 112 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 48 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 120,259 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 14 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 288 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 14 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 102,280 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 215 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 113 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 215 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 230,143 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 4 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 82 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 4 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 217,175 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 143 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 80 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 143 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 111,173 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 53 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 48 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 53 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 195,50 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the cost of registration at a professional association meeting was $ 184 per person ; a lunch for registrants only was available for an additional $ 177 per person . if the number of registrants who paid for lunch was 184 more than the number who did not , and if receipts for registration and lunch totaled $ 136,23 , how many people paid just for registration at the meeting ?",
        "Solution": "(1 * 1) = 1"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 58 * 13 * 141 * 126 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((58 * 13) * 141) * 126) - ((((58 * 13) * 141) * 126) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 115 * 72 * 53 * 280 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((115 * 72) * 53) * 280) - ((((115 * 72) * 53) * 280) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 45 * 217 * 17 * 16 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((45 * 217) * 17) * 16) - ((((45 * 217) * 17) * 16) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 48 * 112 * 120 * 259 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((48 * 112) * 120) * 259) - ((((48 * 112) * 120) * 259) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 14 * 288 * 102 * 280 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((14 * 288) * 102) * 280) - ((((14 * 288) * 102) * 280) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 215 * 113 * 230 * 143 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((215 * 113) * 230) * 143) - ((((215 * 113) * 230) * 143) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 4 * 82 * 217 * 175 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((4 * 82) * 217) * 175) - ((((4 * 82) * 217) * 175) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 143 * 80 * 111 * 173 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((143 * 80) * 111) * 173) - ((((143 * 80) * 111) * 173) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 53 * 48 * 195 * 50 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((53 * 48) * 195) * 50) - ((((53 * 48) * 195) * 50) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the unit digit in the product ( 184 * 177 * 136 * 23 ) is :",
        "Solution": "((((184 * 177) * 136) * 23) - ((((184 * 177) * 136) * 23) - (4 + 4))) = 8"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 58 be written when listing the integers from 13 to 141 ?",
        "Solution": "(((13 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 3900"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 126 be written when listing the integers from 115 to 72 ?",
        "Solution": "(((115 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 34500"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 53 be written when listing the integers from 280 to 45 ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 84000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 217 be written when listing the integers from 17 to 16 ?",
        "Solution": "(((17 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 5100"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 48 be written when listing the integers from 112 to 120 ?",
        "Solution": "(((112 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 33600"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 259 be written when listing the integers from 14 to 288 ?",
        "Solution": "(((14 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 4200"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 102 be written when listing the integers from 280 to 215 ?",
        "Solution": "(((280 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 84000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 113 be written when listing the integers from 230 to 143 ?",
        "Solution": "(((230 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 69000"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 4 be written when listing the integers from 82 to 217 ?",
        "Solution": "(((82 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 24600"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "how many times will the digit 175 be written when listing the integers from 143 to 80 ?",
        "Solution": "(((143 * 10) * 10) * 3) = 42900"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 58 sprockets . it takes machine a 13 hours longer to produce 58 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 13 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(58 / (((13 * 58) * ((100 + 13) / 100)) / ((58 * ((100 + 13) / 100)) - 58))) = 0.5132743362831854"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 141 sprockets . it takes machine a 126 hours longer to produce 141 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 126 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(141 / (((126 * 141) * ((100 + 126) / 100)) / ((141 * ((100 + 126) / 100)) - 141))) = 0.6238938053097345"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 115 sprockets . it takes machine a 72 hours longer to produce 115 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 72 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(115 / (((72 * 115) * ((100 + 72) / 100)) / ((115 * ((100 + 72) / 100)) - 115))) = 0.6686046511627906"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 53 sprockets . it takes machine a 280 hours longer to produce 53 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 280 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(53 / (((280 * 53) * ((100 + 280) / 100)) / ((53 * ((100 + 280) / 100)) - 53))) = 0.1394736842105263"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 45 sprockets . it takes machine a 217 hours longer to produce 45 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 217 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(45 / (((217 * 45) * ((100 + 217) / 100)) / ((45 * ((100 + 217) / 100)) - 45))) = 0.14195583596214512"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 17 sprockets . it takes machine a 16 hours longer to produce 17 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 16 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(17 / (((16 * 17) * ((100 + 16) / 100)) / ((17 * ((100 + 16) / 100)) - 17))) = 0.146551724137931"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 48 sprockets . it takes machine a 112 hours longer to produce 48 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 112 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(48 / (((112 * 48) * ((100 + 112) / 100)) / ((48 * ((100 + 112) / 100)) - 48))) = 0.22641509433962265"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 120 sprockets . it takes machine a 259 hours longer to produce 120 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 259 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / (((259 * 120) * ((100 + 259) / 100)) / ((120 * ((100 + 259) / 100)) - 120))) = 0.33426183844011137"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 14 sprockets . it takes machine a 288 hours longer to produce 14 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 288 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(14 / (((288 * 14) * ((100 + 288) / 100)) / ((14 * ((100 + 288) / 100)) - 14))) = 0.03608247422680412"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "machine a and machine b are each used to manufacture 102 sprockets . it takes machine a 280 hours longer to produce 102 sprockets than machine b . machine b produces 280 percent more sprockets per hour than machine a . how many sprockets per hour does machine a produces ?",
        "Solution": "(102 / (((280 * 102) * ((100 + 280) / 100)) / ((102 * ((100 + 280) / 100)) - 102))) = 0.2684210526315789"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 58 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 13 terms of the g . p . is 141 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((141 - 1) ** (1 / 13)) = 1.4624693464336296"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 126 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 115 terms of the g . p . is 72 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((72 - 1) ** (1 / 115)) = 1.0377623218895962"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 53 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 280 terms of the g . p . is 45 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((45 - 1) ** (1 / 280)) = 1.0136067029118176"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 217 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 17 terms of the g . p . is 16 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((16 - 1) ** (1 / 17)) = 1.1726862656152632"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 48 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 112 terms of the g . p . is 120 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((120 - 1) ** (1 / 112)) = 1.0435942301537724"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 259 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 14 terms of the g . p . is 288 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((288 - 1) ** (1 / 14)) = 1.4981765416159618"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 102 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 280 terms of the g . p . is 215 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((215 - 1) ** (1 / 280)) = 1.019349012038955"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 113 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 230 terms of the g . p . is 143 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((143 - 1) ** (1 / 230)) = 1.021780888685877"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 4 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 82 terms of the g . p . is 217 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((217 - 1) ** (1 / 82)) = 1.0677484463864697"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the ratio of the sum of the first 175 terms of a g . p . to the sum of the first 143 terms of the g . p . is 80 , what is the common ratio of the g . p ?",
        "Solution": "((80 - 1) ** (1 / 143)) = 1.0310271923165915"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 58 gallon solution of salt and water is 13 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 141 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((58 * (13 - 141)) / 141) = -52.652482269503544"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 126 gallon solution of salt and water is 115 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 72 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((126 * (115 - 72)) / 72) = 75.25"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 53 gallon solution of salt and water is 280 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 45 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((53 * (280 - 45)) / 45) = 276.77777777777777"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 217 gallon solution of salt and water is 17 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 16 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((217 * (17 - 16)) / 16) = 13.5625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 48 gallon solution of salt and water is 112 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 120 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((48 * (112 - 120)) / 120) = -3.2"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 259 gallon solution of salt and water is 14 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 288 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((259 * (14 - 288)) / 288) = -246.40972222222223"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 102 gallon solution of salt and water is 280 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 215 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((102 * (280 - 215)) / 215) = 30.837209302325583"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 113 gallon solution of salt and water is 230 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 143 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((113 * (230 - 143)) / 143) = 68.74825174825175"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 4 gallon solution of salt and water is 82 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 217 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((4 * (82 - 217)) / 217) = -2.488479262672811"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a 175 gallon solution of salt and water is 143 % salt . how many gallons of water must be added to the solution in order to decrease the salt to 80 % of the volume ?",
        "Solution": "((175 * (143 - 80)) / 80) = 137.8125"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 58 after 13 years . if the principal is trebled after 141 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 / 13) * 141) * 3) + ((58 / 13) * 141)) = 2516.3076923076924"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 126 after 115 years . if the principal is trebled after 72 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((126 / 115) * 72) * 3) + ((126 / 115) * 72)) = 315.5478260869565"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 53 after 280 years . if the principal is trebled after 45 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 / 280) * 45) * 3) + ((53 / 280) * 45)) = 34.07142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 217 after 17 years . if the principal is trebled after 16 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((217 / 17) * 16) * 3) + ((217 / 17) * 16)) = 816.9411764705883"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 48 after 112 years . if the principal is trebled after 120 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((48 / 112) * 120) * 3) + ((48 / 112) * 120)) = 205.7142857142857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 259 after 14 years . if the principal is trebled after 288 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((259 / 14) * 288) * 3) + ((259 / 14) * 288)) = 21312.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 102 after 280 years . if the principal is trebled after 215 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((102 / 280) * 215) * 3) + ((102 / 280) * 215)) = 313.2857142857143"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 113 after 230 years . if the principal is trebled after 143 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((113 / 230) * 143) * 3) + ((113 / 230) * 143)) = 281.02608695652174"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 4 after 82 years . if the principal is trebled after 217 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((4 / 82) * 217) * 3) + ((4 / 82) * 217)) = 42.34146341463415"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the simple interest on a sum of money will be rs . 175 after 143 years . if the principal is trebled after 80 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "Solution": "((((175 / 143) * 80) * 3) + ((175 / 143) * 80)) = 391.60839160839157"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 58 meters by 13 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 141 meters by 141 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 58 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(58 * 58) = 3364"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 126 meters by 115 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 72 meters by 72 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 126 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(126 * 126) = 15876"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 53 meters by 280 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 45 meters by 45 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 53 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(53 * 53) = 2809"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 217 meters by 17 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 16 meters by 16 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 217 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(217 * 217) = 47089"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 48 meters by 112 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 120 meters by 120 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 48 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(48 * 48) = 2304"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 259 meters by 14 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 288 meters by 288 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 259 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(259 * 259) = 67081"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 102 meters by 280 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 215 meters by 215 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 102 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(102 * 102) = 10404"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 113 meters by 230 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 143 meters by 143 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 113 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(113 * 113) = 12769"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 4 meters by 82 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 217 meters by 217 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 4 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(4 * 4) = 16"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a rectangular floor that measures 175 meters by 143 meters is to be covered with carpet squares that each measure 80 meters by 80 meters . if the carpet squares cost $ 175 apiece , what is the total cost for the number of carpet squares needed to cover the floor ?",
        "Solution": "(175 * 175) = 30625"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 58 which was a 13 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(58 / ((13 / 100) + 1)) = 51.32743362831859"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 141 which was a 126 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(141 / ((126 / 100) + 1)) = 62.389380530973455"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 115 which was a 72 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(115 / ((72 / 100) + 1)) = 66.86046511627907"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 53 which was a 280 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(53 / ((280 / 100) + 1)) = 13.947368421052632"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 45 which was a 217 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(45 / ((217 / 100) + 1)) = 14.195583596214512"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 17 which was a 16 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(17 / ((16 / 100) + 1)) = 14.655172413793105"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 48 which was a 112 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(48 / ((112 / 100) + 1)) = 22.641509433962263"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 120 which was a 259 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(120 / ((259 / 100) + 1)) = 33.42618384401114"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 14 which was a 288 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(14 / ((288 / 100) + 1)) = 3.6082474226804124"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "jim is able to sell a hand - carved statue for $ 102 which was a 280 % profit over his cost . how much did the statue originally cost him ?",
        "Solution": "(102 / ((280 / 100) + 1)) = 26.842105263157897"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 58 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 13 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 58) * 60) = 447.2727272727272"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 141 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 126 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 141) * 60) = -4532.727272727273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 115 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 72 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 115) * 60) = -2972.727272727273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 53 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 280 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 53) * 60) = 747.2727272727273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 45 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 217 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 45) * 60) = 1227.2727272727273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 17 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 16 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 17) * 60) = 2907.272727272727"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 48 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 112 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 48) * 60) = 1047.2727272727273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 120 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 259 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 120) * 60) = -3272.727272727273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 14 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 288 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 14) * 60) = 3087.272727272727"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "the minute hand of a clock overtakes the hour hand at intervals of 102 minutes of correct time . how much does the clock gain or lose in 280 hours ?",
        "Solution": "(((((2 * 3) * 60) / ((((2 * 3) * 60) - (((2 * 3) * 60) / (3 * 4))) / 60)) - 102) * 60) = -2192.727272727273"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 58 cm tall . the average female height was 13 cm , and the average male height was 141 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((58 - 13) / (141 - 58)) = 0.5421686746987951"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 126 cm tall . the average female height was 115 cm , and the average male height was 72 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((126 - 115) / (72 - 126)) = -0.2037037037037037"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 53 cm tall . the average female height was 280 cm , and the average male height was 45 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((53 - 280) / (45 - 53)) = 28.375"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 217 cm tall . the average female height was 17 cm , and the average male height was 16 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((217 - 17) / (16 - 217)) = -0.9950248756218906"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 48 cm tall . the average female height was 112 cm , and the average male height was 120 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((48 - 112) / (120 - 48)) = -0.8888888888888888"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 259 cm tall . the average female height was 14 cm , and the average male height was 288 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((259 - 14) / (288 - 259)) = 8.448275862068966"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 102 cm tall . the average female height was 280 cm , and the average male height was 215 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((102 - 280) / (215 - 102)) = -1.575221238938053"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 113 cm tall . the average female height was 230 cm , and the average male height was 143 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((113 - 230) / (143 - 113)) = -3.9"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 4 cm tall . the average female height was 82 cm , and the average male height was 217 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((4 - 82) / (217 - 4)) = -0.36619718309859156"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "students at a school were on average 175 cm tall . the average female height was 143 cm , and the average male height was 80 cms . what was the ratio f of men to women ?",
        "Solution": "((175 - 143) / (80 - 175)) = -0.3368421052631579"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 58 earning members was rs . 13 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 141 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((13 * 58) - (141 * (58 - 1))) = -7283"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 126 earning members was rs . 115 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 72 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((115 * 126) - (72 * (126 - 1))) = 5490"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 53 earning members was rs . 280 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 45 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 53) - (45 * (53 - 1))) = 12500"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 217 earning members was rs . 17 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 16 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((17 * 217) - (16 * (217 - 1))) = 233"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 48 earning members was rs . 112 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 120 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((112 * 48) - (120 * (48 - 1))) = -264"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 259 earning members was rs . 14 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 288 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((14 * 259) - (288 * (259 - 1))) = -70678"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 102 earning members was rs . 280 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 215 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((280 * 102) - (215 * (102 - 1))) = 6845"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 113 earning members was rs . 230 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 143 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((230 * 113) - (143 * (113 - 1))) = 9974"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 4 earning members was rs . 82 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 217 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((82 * 4) - (217 * (4 - 1))) = -323"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "average monthly income of a family of 175 earning members was rs . 143 . one of the earning members died and therefore , the average income came down to rs 80 . the income of the deceased was ?",
        "Solution": "((143 * 175) - (80 * (175 - 1))) = 11105"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 58 and after 13 months b joined him investing rs . 141 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 126 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(126 - (60 * 100)) = -5874"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 115 and after 72 months b joined him investing rs . 53 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 280 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(280 - (60 * 100)) = -5720"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 45 and after 217 months b joined him investing rs . 17 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 16 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(16 - (60 * 100)) = -5984"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 48 and after 112 months b joined him investing rs . 120 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 259 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(259 - (60 * 100)) = -5741"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 14 and after 288 months b joined him investing rs . 102 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 280 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(280 - (60 * 100)) = -5720"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 215 and after 113 months b joined him investing rs . 230 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 143 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(143 - (60 * 100)) = -5857"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 4 and after 82 months b joined him investing rs . 217 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 175 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(175 - (60 * 100)) = -5825"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 143 and after 80 months b joined him investing rs . 111 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 173 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(173 - (60 * 100)) = -5827"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 53 and after 48 months b joined him investing rs . 195 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 50 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(50 - (60 * 100)) = -5950"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a started a business with an investment of rs . 184 and after 177 months b joined him investing rs . 136 . if the profit at the end of a year is rs . 23 , then the share of b is ?",
        "Solution": "(23 - (60 * 100)) = -5977"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 58 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 13 liters per day , the supply lasts for 141 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 58 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((13 * 141) / (58 - 141)) * 58) / (58 + ((13 * 141) / (58 - 141)))) = -35.66387118416638"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 126 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 115 liters per day , the supply lasts for 72 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 126 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((115 * 72) / (126 - 72)) * 126) / (126 + ((115 * 72) / (126 - 72)))) = 69.16467780429593"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 53 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 280 liters per day , the supply lasts for 45 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 53 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((280 * 45) / (53 - 45)) * 53) / (53 + ((280 * 45) / (53 - 45)))) = 51.274570024570025"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 217 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 17 liters per day , the supply lasts for 16 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 217 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((17 * 16) / (217 - 16)) * 217) / (217 + ((17 * 16) / (217 - 16)))) = 1.3448472282348651"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 48 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 112 liters per day , the supply lasts for 120 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 48 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((112 * 120) / (48 - 120)) * 48) / (48 + ((112 * 120) / (48 - 120)))) = 64.61538461538461"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 259 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 14 liters per day , the supply lasts for 288 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 259 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((14 * 288) / (259 - 288)) * 259) / (259 + ((14 * 288) / (259 - 288)))) = -300.16901408450707"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 102 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 280 liters per day , the supply lasts for 215 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 102 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((280 * 215) / (102 - 215)) * 102) / (102 + ((280 * 215) / (102 - 215)))) = 126.15359329416115"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 113 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 230 liters per day , the supply lasts for 143 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 113 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((230 * 143) / (113 - 143)) * 113) / (113 + ((230 * 143) / (113 - 143)))) = 125.98542372881356"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 4 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 82 liters per day , the supply lasts for 217 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 4 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((82 * 217) / (4 - 217)) * 4) / (4 + ((82 * 217) / (4 - 217)))) = 4.201156888206823"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a tank can supply water to a village for 175 days . if a leak at the bottom of the tank drains out 143 liters per day , the supply lasts for 80 days only . for how many days will the supply last if the leak drains out 175 liters per day ?",
        "Solution": "((((143 * 80) / (175 - 80)) * 175) / (175 + ((143 * 80) / (175 - 80)))) = 71.33440228042045"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "58 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 13 of these 58 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 141 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 126 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((141 + (((126 - 58) - 141) / 2)) + 13) = 117.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "115 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 72 of these 115 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 53 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 280 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((53 + (((280 - 115) - 53) / 2)) + 72) = 181.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "45 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 217 of these 45 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 17 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 16 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((17 + (((16 - 45) - 17) / 2)) + 217) = 211.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "48 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 112 of these 48 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 120 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 259 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((120 + (((259 - 48) - 120) / 2)) + 112) = 277.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "14 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 288 of these 14 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 102 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 280 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((102 + (((280 - 14) - 102) / 2)) + 288) = 472.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "215 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 113 of these 215 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 230 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 143 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((230 + (((143 - 215) - 230) / 2)) + 113) = 192.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "4 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 82 of these 4 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 217 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 175 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((217 + (((175 - 4) - 217) / 2)) + 82) = 276.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "143 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 80 of these 143 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 111 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 173 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((111 + (((173 - 143) - 111) / 2)) + 80) = 150.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "53 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 48 of these 53 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 195 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 50 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((195 + (((50 - 53) - 195) / 2)) + 48) = 144.0"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "184 of the scientists that attended a certain workshop were wolf prize laureates , and 177 of these 184 were also nobel prize laureates . of the scientists that attended that workshop and had not received the wolf prize , the number of scientists that had received the nobel prize was 136 greater than the number of scientists that had not received the nobel prize . if 23 of the scientists attended that workshop , how many of them were nobel prize laureates ?",
        "Solution": "((136 + (((23 - 184) - 136) / 2)) + 177) = 164.5"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 58 x black - and - white films and 13 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(13 / ((58 / 100) + 13)) = 0.9572901325478645"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 141 x black - and - white films and 126 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(126 / ((141 / 100) + 126)) = 0.9889333647280434"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 115 x black - and - white films and 72 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(72 / ((115 / 100) + 72)) = 0.9842788790157211"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 53 x black - and - white films and 280 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / ((53 / 100) + 280)) = 0.9981107189961859"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 45 x black - and - white films and 217 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(217 / ((45 / 100) + 217)) = 0.9979305587491378"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 17 x black - and - white films and 16 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(16 / ((17 / 100) + 16)) = 0.989486703772418"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 48 x black - and - white films and 112 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(112 / ((48 / 100) + 112)) = 0.995732574679943"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 120 x black - and - white films and 259 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(259 / ((120 / 100) + 259)) = 0.9953881629515757"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 14 x black - and - white films and 288 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(288 / ((14 / 100) + 288)) = 0.9995141250780871"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "a committee is reviewing a total of 102 x black - and - white films and 280 y color films for a festival . if the committee selects y / x % of the black - and - white films and all of the color films , what fraction x of the selected films are in color ?",
        "Solution": "(280 / ((102 / 100) + 280)) = 0.9963703650985696"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 58 , x + 13 , and x + 141 is 126 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((13 * 2) - (58 * 2)) = -90"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 115 , x + 72 , and x + 53 is 280 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((72 * 2) - (115 * 2)) = -86"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 45 , x + 217 , and x + 17 is 16 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((217 * 2) - (45 * 2)) = 344"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 48 , x + 112 , and x + 120 is 259 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((112 * 2) - (48 * 2)) = 128"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 14 , x + 288 , and x + 102 is 280 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((288 * 2) - (14 * 2)) = 548"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 215 , x + 113 , and x + 230 is 143 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((113 * 2) - (215 * 2)) = -204"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 4 , x + 82 , and x + 217 is 175 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((82 * 2) - (4 * 2)) = 156"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 143 , x + 80 , and x + 111 is 173 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((80 * 2) - (143 * 2)) = -126"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 53 , x + 48 , and x + 195 is 50 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((48 * 2) - (53 * 2)) = -10"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "if the average ( arithmetic mean ) of x + 184 , x + 177 , and x + 136 is 23 , then x =",
        "Solution": "((177 * 2) - (184 * 2)) = -14"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 58 / x ) + ( ( 58 / y ) = 58 / 13",
        "Solution": "(((13 + 58) + 58) + 58) = 187"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 141 / x ) + ( ( 141 / y ) = 141 / 126",
        "Solution": "(((126 + 141) + 141) + 141) = 549"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 115 / x ) + ( ( 115 / y ) = 115 / 72",
        "Solution": "(((72 + 115) + 115) + 115) = 417"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 53 / x ) + ( ( 53 / y ) = 53 / 280",
        "Solution": "(((280 + 53) + 53) + 53) = 439"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 45 / x ) + ( ( 45 / y ) = 45 / 217",
        "Solution": "(((217 + 45) + 45) + 45) = 352"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 17 / x ) + ( ( 17 / y ) = 17 / 16",
        "Solution": "(((16 + 17) + 17) + 17) = 67"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 48 / x ) + ( ( 48 / y ) = 48 / 112",
        "Solution": "(((112 + 48) + 48) + 48) = 256"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 120 / x ) + ( ( 120 / y ) = 120 / 259",
        "Solution": "(((259 + 120) + 120) + 120) = 619"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 14 / x ) + ( ( 14 / y ) = 14 / 288",
        "Solution": "(((288 + 14) + 14) + 14) = 330"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "for how many integers pair ( x , y ) satisfies the result ( 102 / x ) + ( ( 102 / y ) = 102 / 280",
        "Solution": "(((280 + 102) + 102) + 102) = 586"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 58 / 13 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 141 / 13 are on the honor roll . if 13 / 126 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((58 * 141) * 141) + 141) / (141 * (13 * 58))) = 10.847480106100797"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 115 / 72 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 53 / 72 are on the honor roll . if 72 / 280 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((115 * 53) * 53) + 53) / (53 * (72 * 115))) = 0.736231884057971"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 45 / 217 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 17 / 217 are on the honor roll . if 217 / 16 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((45 * 17) * 17) + 17) / (17 * (217 * 45))) = 0.07844342037890426"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 48 / 112 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 120 / 112 are on the honor roll . if 112 / 259 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((48 * 120) * 120) + 120) / (120 * (112 * 48))) = 1.0716145833333333"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 14 / 288 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 102 / 288 are on the honor roll . if 288 / 280 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((14 * 102) * 102) + 102) / (102 * (288 * 14))) = 0.35441468253968256"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 215 / 113 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 230 / 113 are on the honor roll . if 113 / 143 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((215 * 230) * 230) + 230) / (230 * (113 * 215))) = 2.0354393908211565"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 4 / 82 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 217 / 82 are on the honor roll . if 82 / 175 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((4 * 217) * 217) + 217) / (217 * (82 * 4))) = 2.649390243902439"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 143 / 80 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 111 / 80 are on the honor roll . if 80 / 173 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((143 * 111) * 111) + 111) / (111 * (80 * 143))) = 1.3875874125874126"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 53 / 48 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 195 / 48 are on the honor roll . if 48 / 50 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((53 * 195) * 195) + 195) / (195 * (48 * 53))) = 4.062893081761007"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "of the female students at barkely university , 184 / 177 are on the honor roll . of the male students , 136 / 177 are on the honor roll . if 177 / 23 of the students are female , what fraction of all the students are on the honor roll ?",
        "Solution": "((((184 * 136) * 136) + 136) / (136 * (177 * 184))) = 0.7683922869073938"
    }
]